<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 07:27:56 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 07:27:56 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Late to the party :-) -&gt; All pieces of ATProto can and are running on non Bluesky servers e.g. Blacksky servers ; May 2, 2025:: Bryan Newbold:: A Full-Network Relay for $34 a Month</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Aug 24, 2025 14:34 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://whtwnd.com/bnewbold.net/3lo7a2a4qxg2l&quot;&gt;ME:: Late to the party :-) -&amp;gt; All pieces of ATProto can and are running on non Bluesky servers e.g. Blacksky servers ; May 2, 2025:: Bryan Newbold:: A Full-Network Relay for $34 a Month&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;This is an update to a Summer 2024 blog post. At the time, atproto relays required a cache of the full network on local disk to validate data structures. With the Sync v1.1 updates, relays don't need all that disk I/O. What impact does that have on hosting setup and operating costs ... Turns out the dev community beat me to the punch and folks like @futur.blue and @bad-example have been doing this for months on Rapsberry Pis and $19/month VPS servers in European jurisdiction. ... But i'm still really psyched at how much simpler things have become, so I set up my own $34/month VPS demo instance, and this is the write-up. ...The relay describe here is running at: https://relay-vps.demo.bsky.dev&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– See also Rudy Fraser’s YouTube interview: &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Uvj1h7OQPkk?si=OflEMDblOYTZOu1w&quot;&gt;Blacksky Algorithms: Building Decentralized Social Media with Rudy Fraser&lt;/a&gt; and of course &lt;a href=&quot;https://blacksky.community/&quot;&gt;Blacksky.community&lt;/a&gt; which is up and running and doing great AFAICT&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/24/p0734-blacksky-and-others-running-all-atproto-pieces-without-bluesky-involvement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/24/p0734-blacksky-and-others-running-all-atproto-pieces-without-bluesky-involvement/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME::tl;dr-ing:: We don't have the mathematics to be able to build real artificial general intelligence ; Django Beatty:: Alchemy 2: Electric Boogaloo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Aug 18, 2025 18:43 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/alchemy-2-electric-boogaloo-django-beatty-luqbc/&quot;&gt;ME::tl;dr-ing:: We don’t have the mathematics to be able to build real artificial general intelligence ; Django Beatty:: Alchemy 2: Electric Boogaloo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mathematics-of-impossible-things&quot;&gt;Mathematics of Impossible Things&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/alchemy-2-electric-boogaloo-django-beatty-luqbc/&quot;&gt;Django Beatty:: Alchemy 2: Electric Boogaloo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scientists recently mapped one cubic millimeter of human brain tissue - a piece the size of a grain of sand. It took 1.4 petabytes of data. Not to simulate it. Not to model it. Just to store a static 3D photograph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One grain of sand worth of brain tissue. Frozen. Dead. Not even trying to capture how it works - just what it looks like. And it takes more data than Netflix uses to stream to a small country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Inside that grain? 57,000 cells. 150 million synapses. Each synapse is a chemical factory with over 1,000 different proteins. Each protein changes shape and function based on what’s happening around it. And that’s just the photograph. The frozen moment. To model how it actually works? We don’t even know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is where the dream of artificial general intelligence hits a wall that nobody talks about. Years ago, I was discussing AGI with my friend Dr. Roman Belavkin - a researcher in cognitive science at Middlesex University. Over coffee, he explained the problems with modeling biological neurons that should be headline news but instead stay buried in academic conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I needed to understand: were these problems speed bumps or brick walls?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The more Roman explained, the clearer it became to me. These aren’t speed bumps. They’re mathematical voids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The problem starts with backpropagation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let me explain what that means, because it’s the heart of why AGI is impossible with current mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most deep learning systems today - ChatGPT, Claude, Gemini - rely on an algorithm called backpropagation. Think of it like teaching a child: you show them a picture of a cat, they guess “dog,” you tell them how wrong they were, and they adjust their mental model. Do this millions of times and they learn to recognize cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-1943-problem&quot;&gt;The 1943 Problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why don’t we just model real neurons? While we can model neurons at many fidelities - the best are still cartoon sketches. The original McCulloch-Pitts model from 1943 used simple on/off switches with step functions - not differentiable, couldn’t work with backpropagation (which hadn’t been invented yet). In the 1980s, to make backpropagation work, we replaced the step functions with smooth curves. But we’re still using the same basic framework: weighted sums, linear algebra, one-dimensional signals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If we tried to model biological detail - the neurotransmitters, the dendritic processing, the living cellular machinery - we don’t even have the mathematics to describe it, let alone compute it. A single biological neuron isn’t a switch - it’s a living cell, a chemical factory floating in a soup of neurotransmitters, hormones, and proteins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When a signal arrives at a neuron, it doesn’t just flow through like electricity through a wire. The signal arrives at branches called dendrites, and here’s where everything breaks: each branch does its own processing. Not simple addition or multiplication - complex, unpredictable transformations that we struggle to describe mathematically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Imagine you’re trying to predict the flow of a river. But this river has thousands of tributaries, and each tributary follows its own rules - some flow uphill, some disappear underground and reappear elsewhere, some spontaneously change direction based on the phase of the moon. Now try to write an equation for where a drop of water will end up. That’s what we’re trying to do with neurons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/18/p1143-alchemy-2-electric-boogaloo-django-beatty-luqbc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/18/p1143-alchemy-2-electric-boogaloo-django-beatty-luqbc/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: this looks great! ; Alternative Social Media Network Bibliography</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Aug 17, 2025 14:46 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://socialmediaalternatives.org/bib.html&quot;&gt;ME:: this looks great! ; Alternative Social Media Network Bibliography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obviously read the whole thing :-) :  &lt;a href=&quot;https://socialmediaalternatives.org/bib.html&quot;&gt;Alternative Social Media Network Bibliography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is an alternative social media (ASM) bibliography, a collection of scholarly articles exploring the world of social media beyond corporate sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This page will be updated monthly. For more up-to-date access to the bibliography, request to join the Social Media Alternatives Project Zotero group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note that inclusion in this bibliography does not mean these studies are endorsed by the network of ASM researchers. However, highlighted entries are authored by ASM network members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/17/p0746-bib/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/17/p0746-bib/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To the #WhitePersonSplainers :-) who tell me extending my right arm is not a valid right turn signal (nobody who's not white has ever mansplained this to me in 17 years of bicycling in Vancouver: It is a valid signal ; See:: BC Motor Vehicle Act:: Bicyclists signal a right turn by doing either of the following ... (ii) extending the person's right hand and arm horizontally from the cycle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Aug 16, 2025 05:16 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bclaws.gov.bc.ca/civix/document/id/complete/statreg/96318_05&quot;&gt;To the #WhitePersonSplainers :-) who tell me extending my right arm is not a valid right turn signal (nobody who’s not white has ever mansplained this to me in 17 years of bicycling in Vancouver: It is a valid signal ; See:: BC Motor Vehicle Act:: Bicyclists signal a right turn by doing either of the following … (ii) extending the person’s right hand and arm horizontally from the cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Happens about once a month. Get a life #WhitePersonSplainers :-) and more importantly read the BC law!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote-from-the-british-columbia-motor-vehicle-act-revised-august-5-2025&quot;&gt;QUOTE From the British Columbia Motor Vehicle Act revised August 5, 2025&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bclaws.gov.bc.ca/civix/document/id/complete/statreg/96318_05&quot;&gt;BC Motor Vehicle Act:: Bicyclists signal a right turn by doing either of the following … (ii) extending the person’s right hand and arm horizontally from the cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(17) A person operating a cycle on a highway must signify&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(a) a left turn by extending the person’s left hand and arm horizontally from the cycle,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(b) a right turn by doing either of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(i) extending the person’s left hand and arm out and upward from the cycle so that the upper and lower parts of the arm are at right angles;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;gt;(ii) extending the person’s right hand and arm horizontally from the cycle&lt;/strong&gt;, and&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/15/p2216-signalling-right-by-pointing-right-with-right-arm-is-legal-in-british-columbia/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/15/p2216-signalling-right-by-pointing-right-with-right-arm-is-legal-in-british-columbia/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I don't care what people who I otherwise respect like Om Malik and Dana Blankenhorn say about network effects blah blah blah :-) . It is wrong to be on a platform that openly allows hate speech. If the Nazi Party's newspaper paid you $USD1000 / month in 1939 to write an op-ed monthly would you do it? No. https://om.co/2025/08/03/the-why-of-substack/ is wrong. sorry not sorry Om et al!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Aug 8, 2025 03:26 &lt;a href=&quot;https://devdilettante.com/@roland/114990879704861981&quot;&gt;I don’t care what people who I otherwise respect like Om Malik and Dana Blankenhorn say about network effects blah blah blah :-) . It is wrong to be on a platform that openly allows hate speech. If the Nazi Party’s newspaper paid you $USD1000 / month in 1939 to write an op-ed monthly would you do it? No. https://om.co/2025/08/03/the-why-of-substack/ is wrong. sorry not sorry Om et al!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://om.co/2025/08/03/the-why-of-substack/&quot;&gt;Om’s blog post: 
The Why of Substack is WRONG!&lt;/a&gt; is wrong. sorry not sorry Om et al!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/07/om-malik-wrong-about-substack-in-1939-would-you-write-for-nazi-newspaper/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/07/om-malik-wrong-about-substack-in-1939-would-you-write-for-nazi-newspaper/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: RAGs are great if you use current (i.e. not months old) data you own since plagiarizing your own data is ok :-) and have permission for but they still make mistakes! ;  Marcus Hutchins:: Every Reason Why I Hate AI and You Should Too</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Aug 4, 2025 15:49 &lt;a href=&quot;https://malwaretech.com/2025/08/every-reason-why-i-hate-ai.html&quot;&gt;ME:: RAGs are great if you use current (i.e. not months old) data you own since plagiarizing your own data is ok :-) and have permission for but they still make mistakes! ;  Marcus Hutchins:: Every Reason Why I Hate AI and You Should Too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://malwaretech.com/2025/08/every-reason-why-i-hate-ai.html&quot;&gt;Marcus Hutchins:: Every Reason Why I Hate AI and You Should Too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;RAG basically allows the LLM to search the internet for fresh data relevant to the user’s query, enabling it to fetch the most up-to-date information. The LLM can then use its training data to summarize the information retrieved via RAG. Essentially, this combines LLMs and search engines into a single product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So, why do I hate this? Well, it’s basically glorified plagiarism. While I’d argue LLMs in general are just Plagiarism-as-a-Service, RAG is a lot closer to actual plagiarism that typical LLM behavior. As I’ve already argued, LLMs don’t think or reason. Thus, all RAG is really doing is using the LLMs’ natural language abilities to summarize or re-word some news article, blog post, or research paper. This deprives the original author of revenue &amp;amp; website traffic, while not transforming their work in any meaningful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So yes, while I may come off as a massive LLM hater, I feel like I have my reasons. With that said, I am still actively researching and experimenting with LLM regularly, and I’m always open to being proven wrong. But currently, I’m simply not seeing it. I’m not seeing heaps of successful LLM products, businesses, or use cases. What I’m seeing is a lot of shovel selling, and a huge black hole for VC money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Maybe some day I’ll write a post about the viability of LLMs for something I’m building. But it won’t be today, this year, or likely anytime soon. In fact, I’m currently still getting job offers for manual reverse engineering jobs. It’s extremely common for security companies that use machine learning to hire manual analysts. ML models need constant tweaking and updating, which means a huge market for experts who can be a part of that process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’d expect this is where LLMs will go should the tech take off. Not job replacement, but a shift towards professionals using their experience to fine tune LLMs, instead of doing the work directly. In fact, I’ve started getting the same offers to consult for LLM companies that I am for traditional ML ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Times change, but technology progresses slowly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/04/p0849-every-reason-why-i-hate-ai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/04/p0849-every-reason-why-i-hate-ai/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: The UN 'black helicopters' should offer free hosting for everybody as I said before :-) ; Drew Lyton:: The Future is NOT Self-Hosted but maybe libraries hosting stuff for us?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Aug 3, 2025 20:47 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drewlyton.com/story/the-future-is-not-self-hosted/&quot;&gt;ME:: The UN “black helicopters” should offer free hosting for everybody as I said before :-) ; Drew Lyton:: The Future is NOT Self-Hosted but maybe libraries hosting stuff for us?&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Imagine a world where your library card includes 100GB of encrypted file storage, photo-sharing and document collaboration tools, and media streaming services — all for free. Your data is encrypted end-to-end, but is shareable to anyone on any other service through standardized protocols.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;July 7, 2025:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/07/07/p2102-389-the-future-of-forums-is-lies-i-guess/&quot;&gt;ME:: I don’t have a solution other than ‘UN black helicopter hosting’ :-) (LOL!) with global trust and safety or miraculously :-) hosting becomes easy for everything and everybody runs their own individual server for everything: blogs, chat, forums, vlogs, music, etc etc etc ; Kyle Kingsbury:: The Future of Forums is Lies, I Guess&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/03/p1347-the-future-is-not-self-hosted/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/03/p1347-the-future-is-not-self-hosted/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: TIL about the macOS Dragging and Selection clipboards ; cricket:: The three different clipboards – Tech Reflect</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jul 31, 2025 16:31 &lt;a href=&quot;https://techreflect.org/2017/05/the-three-different-clipboards/&quot;&gt;ME:: TIL about the macOS Dragging and Selection clipboards ; cricket:: The three different clipboards – Tech Reflect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you use Copy (⌘C), the selected content is written to the system clipboard (aka clipboard), replacing what was already there. This is great until you find you really need to carry more bits of data around. Turns out that macOS actually has two additional clipboards:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Dragging clipboard&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Selection clipboard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/07/31/p0931-the-three-different-clipboards/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/07/31/p0931-the-three-different-clipboards/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: It's 2025: everybody is a bad developer using machine learning. Some of us will make the bad software production quality whatever ''quality' means for them, some of us will just blissfully use it even though it's bug ridden (like most 100% human written software sadly) ; Om Malik:: Software is going to be automated badly but good enough for many personal workflows The Satya of&amp;nbsp;Satya’s&amp;nbsp;Layoff Memo (laying off 9000 employees to hire AI experts and buy into the 'GPU compute bubble')</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jul 31, 2025 02:38 &lt;a href=&quot;https://om.co/2025/07/26/the-satya-of-satyas-layoff-memo/#comments&quot;&gt;ME:: It’s 2025: everybody is a bad developer using machine learning. Some of us will make the bad software production quality whatever “‘quality’ means for them, some of us will just blissfully use it even though it’s bug ridden (like most 100% human written software sadly) ; Om Malik:: Software is going to be automated badly but good enough for many personal workflows The Satya of Satya’s Layoff Memo (laying off 9000 employees to hire AI experts and buy into the ‘GPU compute bubble’)&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/30/p2151-how-a-91-year-old-vibe-coded-a-complex/&quot;&gt;QUOTING Om’s comment&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;AI (as we know it) is for real. It is good at automation. And frankly, the bespoke nature of software industry makes it ripe for automation. I have no idea what “singularity” or “sentience” looks like, but software is going to be automated, and fast. You can see how much it is working at a low-level. Claude Code is a good tool to experiment. ... That said, so many of the AI concepts are just non-sensical. Redressing the past ideas for AI (automation) age and this new way of “interacting” with software/computers will not work. I am excited for new ideas to emerge.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;June 20, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/30/p2151-how-a-91-year-old-vibe-coded-a-complex/&quot;&gt;ME:: oh really :-) ?!?! Why do I think all these miraculous folks have help from ‘real’ developers? Having said that I think everybody has been a programmer since Visicalc and even better Google Sheets and in the near future regardless what happens with Machine Learning, everybody will be a full fledged mobile and desktop app developer; Claire Vo:: How a 91-year-old vibe coded a complex event management system using Claude and Replit ¦ John Blackman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/07/30/p1938-the-satya-of-satyas-layoff-memo/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/07/30/p1938-the-satya-of-satyas-layoff-memo/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>July 1945:: Scanned copy of 'The mother of all demos':: The Atlantic:: Vannevar Bush: As we may think</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jul 29, 2025 14:11 &lt;a href=&quot;https://cdn.theatlantic.com/media/archives/1945/07/176-1/132407932.pdf&quot;&gt;July 1945:: Scanned copy of ‘The mother of all demos’:: The Atlantic:: Vannevar Bush: As we may think&lt;/a&gt; –&amp;gt; also &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.ph/vZK2b&quot;&gt;As we may think on archive.is from The Atlantic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/07/29/p0711-vannevar-bush-as-we-may-think-atlantic-magazine-1945/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/07/29/p0711-vannevar-bush-as-we-may-think-atlantic-magazine-1945/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
