<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:44:12 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:44:12 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Panasonic please add the LUT name to the EXIF in S9 JPEGs (and other cameras that support LUTs of course)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;So I can keep track of which LUT I used :-) . I doubt they will do this but can’t help to ask. I’ll see if I can file a support request or some such and if I can and do I will post a followup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oh and I hope and trust that somebody else has already asked for this feature :-) I don’t ever claim to be original in my 1000s :-) of ideas!!
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 8, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1010-lumix-s5ii-lut-package/&quot;&gt;ME:: so many free LUTs to try on the S9 and in Pearla and not boring iOS Camera Apps so little time :-) l KROLOP und GERST:: Lumix S5II LUT Package&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p0942-panasonic-lut-names-in-exif-jpegs-s9/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p0942-panasonic-lut-names-in-exif-jpegs-s9/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The more lenses you look at the world with the better. For example: food, languages, books, sports, hobbies, volunteering etc.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Find more lenses every year if you can :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p0038-lenses-food-languages-books-sports-hobbies-volunteering/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p0038-lenses-food-languages-books-sports-hobbies-volunteering/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>without-link-blogthis.rb: new ruby script for blog posts that don't reference a link I call this from linkless_blog_all_open.rb.</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;format is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;title followed by blank line followed by rest of the post in markdown format&lt;/code&gt; for example:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start of awesome post in a checkvist list item&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;awesome title

awesome rest of the post. &lt;span class=&quot;gs&quot;&gt;**awesome bold text**&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End of awesome post in a checkvist list item&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-checkvist/blob/main/without-link-blogthis.rb&quot;&gt;without-link-blogthis.rb&lt;/a&gt; autocreates the slug from the first line of a list item in a checkvist list (using the title with stop words removed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-checkvist/blob/main/linkless_blog_all_open.rb&quot;&gt;linkless_blog_all_open.rb&lt;/a&gt; calls without_blogthis.rb to create blog posts in jekyll format from my all open list items in my ‘blog this’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://checkvist.com/checklists/936619&quot;&gt;checkvist list 936619&lt;/a&gt; after you type ‘y’ to approve it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oh and along the way I improved my scripts so you don’t have to explicitly add the creation date. The created date is read from the checkvist api field &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;created_at&lt;/code&gt;. Ruby code:
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;parse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;created_at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;debug&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;created_at: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;ai&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time_discovered_slug&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;getlocal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;strftime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'%Y-%m-%d-p%H%M'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 28, 2024: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/28/p1718-blog_all_open/&quot;&gt;my ruby script that’s responsible for my flurry of recent blog posts is called blog_all_open.rb.. It calls blogthis.rb to create blog posts in jekyll format with a nice slug from my all open list items in my ‘blog this’ checkvist list 74286 after you type ‘y’ to approve it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/14/p0908-without-link-blogthis-linkless_blog_all_open/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/14/p0908-without-link-blogthis-linkless_blog_all_open/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Revenge of renewables. Despite the USA and Alberta governments (and our former environmentalist PM), renewable i.e. solar and wind is the right side of history</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The global south will lead this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is where Canada could and should (sorry about the should word :-) ) lead. The future. Renewable, green energy which provides jobs and super large infrastructure projects instead of the same old same old oil and gas projects (I am OK with being honest and saying we need some oil and gas projects for a very limited time and here is our clear and actionable roadmap and plan to get off of oil and gas. Two ideas I can hold in my head simultaneously).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And it goes with saying climate change is the number one issue for all humans! And it’s not a zero sum game in fact it’s win win. More jobs more better clean air, more more more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/13/p0841-revenge-renewables-usa-alberta-government-wrong-side-history/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/13/p0841-revenge-renewables-usa-alberta-government-wrong-side-history/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: free websites for folks who know how to use git for how long? Sounds great, except for having enough $. And grebedoc is codeberg spelled backwards LOL ; Catherine 'whitequark' and teammates:: Grebedoc — static site hosting for git forges</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 13, 2025 16:33 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://grebedoc.dev/&quot;&gt;ME:: free websites for folks who know how to use git for how long? Sounds great, except for having enough $. And grebedoc is codeberg spelled backwards LOL ; Catherine ‘whitequark’ and teammates:: Grebedoc — static site hosting for git forges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://grebedoc.dev/&quot;&gt;Grebedoc — static site hosting for git forges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In short: a service that publishes the pages branch in your Git repository as a website on your domain; think GitHub Pages if it was open source and community operated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;More specifically, it is a public deployment of git-pages and Caddy configured to work especially with Codeberg but also with other Git forges. It is operated by Catherine ‘whitequark’ and teammates, and currently deployed using Rage4 anycast infrastructure routing to VPSes in six regions (Europe, North America East, North America West, South America, East Asia, Australia), with site contents stored on Tigris and backed up to Wasabi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This service is provided as a public utility, especially for those migrating from GitHub to community operated forges, and we plan to operate it indefinitely. It is monitored and has a status page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The size of a website is currently limited to 768 MiB. We are aiming to eventually raise this to 10 GiB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/13/p0833-grebedoc-dev/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/13/p0833-grebedoc-dev/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Small 'p' political Songs from the 1980s. Shipbuilding is my favourite? What's yours?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;(I loved the big ‘P’ songs too like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sun_City_(song)&quot;&gt;Sun City&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_Nelson_Mandela&quot;&gt;Free Nelson Mandela&lt;/a&gt; don’t get me wrong :-) )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shipbuilding_(song)&quot;&gt;Shipbuilding&lt;/a&gt; by Elvis Costello and Robert Wyatt (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rolandmicroblog.com/2025/11/09/its-just-a-rumor-that.html&quot;&gt;I humourously (#Ymmv) tried to sing a couple of lines on my podcast&lt;/a&gt; :-) , my apologies LOL to Elvis and Robert), 1984.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;With everything to lose (from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Our_Favourite_Shop&quot;&gt;Our Favourite Shop&lt;/a&gt;) by The Style Council, 1985.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/There_Is_Power_in_a_Union_(Billy_Bragg_song)&quot;&gt;There Is Power in a Union&lt;/a&gt; by Billy Bragg, 1986.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/99_Luftballons&quot;&gt;99 Luftballons&lt;/a&gt; by Nena, 1983.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Skies&quot;&gt;Red Skies&lt;/a&gt; by The Fixx, 1982.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enola_Gay_(song)&quot;&gt;Enola Gay&lt;/a&gt; by OMD, 1980.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solidarity (from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anthem_(Black_Uhuru_album)&quot;&gt;Anthem&lt;/a&gt;) by Black Uhuru, 1984.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And so many more …. :-) What’s your favourite?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/12/p0748-small-political-songs-1980s-shipbuilding-favourite/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/12/p0748-small-political-songs-1980s-shipbuilding-favourite/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pluribus anti-zombie zombie 1st 2 episodes blew me away. COVID-19 awareness in a denialist world parallels per Julia Doubleday?</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See Dale and my impressions over on our Over 40 in Vancouver podcast:&lt;a href=&quot;https://over40invan.com/92-apple-tvs-pluribus-the-first-two-episodes/&quot;&gt;Episode #92 Apple TV’s Pluribus – The first two episodes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the COVID denialist parallel see Julia Doubleday’s post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegauntlet.news/p/pluribus-captures-the-isolation-of&quot;&gt;“Pluribus” captures the isolation of COVID-awareness in a COVID denialist world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote-from-julia-doubledays-post&quot;&gt;QUOTE from Julia Doubleday’s post&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing by Julia Doubleday: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegauntlet.news/p/pluribus-captures-the-isolation-of&quot;&gt;“Pluribus” captures the isolation of COVID-awareness in a COVID denialist world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s take a moment here. Whether or not Vince Gilligan meant to evoke the pandemic with this show, this is a show carrying a lot of psychic COVID baggage. The show begins with misused PPE, animal transmission/lab leak (pick your theory!), and the inversion of early pandemic measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rather than social distancing, these characters immediately begin kissing on the mouth. To me- and I’d guess, many other COVID cautious individuals, the invaded personal space and licked donuts evoke people’s continued insistence thddat they have the right not to isolate and mask while infected with COVID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What’s mine is yours, what’s yours is mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rather than swab to prevent the spread of disease, they swab to further it. And while to many this may feel like a far-fetched, sci-fi premise, for those of us living with Long COVID, it does in fact feel that most people today are actively promoting the spread of COVID rather than engaging with our ongoing efforts to halt and reduce the virus’ spread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For example, we’ve known for years that cleaning the indoor air by introducing higher ventilation standards and HEPA filtration standards would drastically reduce airborne illness. There’s a new technology called Far UVC that inactivates viral pathogens in the air. Combining these two could be a game changer- drastically reducing how much we all get sick. Yet no matter how much we bring up this idea- and no matter how often and how seriously their children get sick- people seem to prefer getting sick than breaking from The Borg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And The Borg, to be clear, is approximately where the show goes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/11/p1006-pluribus-anti-zombie-zombie-episodes-blew-covid-19-awareness-denialist-parallels-julia-doubleday/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/11/p1006-pluribus-anti-zombie-zombie-episodes-blew-covid-19-awareness-denialist-parallels-julia-doubleday/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Recipes that probably :-) work::  Gotta try this with cashews since Simon is allergic to peanuts :-) ; Genevieve Ko:: Dan Dan Noodles Recipe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 11, 2025 02:23 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/Ld85I#selection-1911.0-1911.810&quot;&gt;ME:: Recipes that probably :-) work::  Gotta try this with cashews since Simon is allergic to peanuts :-) ; Genevieve Ko:: Dan Dan Noodles Recipe&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A specialty from Sichuan, a province in the southwest of China, vendors once balanced baskets of noodles and sauce on their shoulder poles and cried out “dan dan mian!” to hawk their wares. Dan dan refers to those bamboo shoulder poles and mian means noodles, but there’s no one way to prepare them. Nowadays in the Western diaspora, the dish is associated with a few essentials, namely chile oil and sesame paste, but another is worth adding: preserved vegetables. Salty and a little sweet with the sour oomph of fermentation, pickled mustard greens give the soothing noodles an umami zing. These noodles are especially rich with sesame, but you can adjust all of the seasonings to your taste. Toasty and salty, tangy on the cliff of funk, chewy with pops of peanut, dan dan noodles are a bowl of contentment.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– see also: &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/RpRn9&quot;&gt;These Dan Dan Noodles Are the Weeknight Meal of Your Dreams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p1823-genevieve-ko-dan-dan-mian-noodles-recipe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p1823-genevieve-ko-dan-dan-mian-noodles-recipe/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I disagree with the analogue note taking folks. I don't read my old analogue notes. #Ymmv</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;And there’s no links. Digital text wins. If your notes are digital and text only (markdown, html, none of that other stuff :-)  or text + PNG and JPEG it’s simple (no crazy Obsidian or other note taking system needed) and will last forever. I want my Newton back. I guess I’ll eventually buy an iPad mini with something like the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://paperlike.com/&quot;&gt;paperlike&lt;/a&gt; screen protector that enhances the writing experience with an Apple Pencil and a Remarkable. Stylus plus printing recognition works for me., Again #Ymmv :-)  an example of the analogue note taking propaganda er marketing :-)  is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;reysu's video&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mq0XvGPSm9w\&quot;&gt;the hybrid note-taking system I wish I learned earlier&lt;/a&gt;  advocates both :-) digital and analogue no thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p1741-disagree-analogue-note-folks-read-notes-ymmv/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p1741-disagree-analogue-note-folks-read-notes-ymmv/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: LOL Ryan,respectfully I think you are wrong but what do I know :-) ; Ryan Dahl:: Humans Are Just Stochastic Parrots</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 10, 2025 17:13 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyclouds.org/humans/&quot;&gt;ME:: LOL Ryan,respectfully I think you are wrong but what do I know :-) ; Ryan Dahl:: Humans Are Just Stochastic Parrots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyclouds.org/humans/&quot;&gt;Ryan Dahl:: Humans Are Just Stochastic Parrots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This species will fabricate quotes, sources, and references – a lot of the time they just make things up that sound plausible. Their words are superficially impressive but largely lacking in substance — humans mostly produce what has been described as fluent bullshit. Humans mansplain, presenting reasoning free of evidence but with confidence in its own correctness on any topic, without regard for the audience. Like talking to a drunk person at a bar: wrong, but very confident about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yet humans really do accomplish a lot more than many thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Humans just spew words. It just so happens that we can decode them into something related, useful, and meaningful surprisingly often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p0913-humans-are-not-stochastic-parrots-sorry-ryan-dahl/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p0913-humans-are-not-stochastic-parrots-sorry-ryan-dahl/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
