<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 07:43:05 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 07:43:05 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>There is no safe crossing at 20th and Clark/Knight.  Transit app's Vancouver bicycle directions still steer you into dangerous situations.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 10, 2024. 07:33 &lt;a href=&quot;https://transitapp.com/en/region/vancouver&quot;&gt;There is no safe crossing at 20th and Clark/Knight.  Transit app’s Vancouver bicycle directions still steer you into dangerous situations.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– The safe crossing is at 19th and Clark/Knight. Perhaps this is due to the database not being updated? I need to enter my safe Vancouver street crossings info (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/10/14/p2-vancouver-safe-bicycle-crossings/&quot;&gt;Safe Vancouver Bicycle crossings&lt;/a&gt; into Open Street Maps. Hopefully Transit app reads from Open Street Maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 18, 2024: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/11/18/p2252-go-bike/&quot;&gt;Transit app is now a bike app, too&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/10/p0733-vancouver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/10/p0733-vancouver/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Guangchuang Yu:: How to use ggimage to plot PNGs instead of points in ggplot2</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 9, 2024 19:56 &lt;a href=&quot;https://yulab-smu.top/pkgdocs/ggimage.html&quot;&gt;Guangchuang Yu:: How to use ggimage to plot PNGs instead of points in ggplot2&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ggplot(d, aes(x, y)) + geom_image(aes(image=image), size=.05)&lt;/code&gt; via Stack Overflow: &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/2181902/how-to-use-an-image-as-a-point-in-ggplot&quot;&gt;How to use an image as a point in ggplot&lt;/a&gt;? To do it in python with matplotlib see https://www.tutorialspoint.com/how-to-use-a-custom-png-image-marker-in-a-plot-matplotlib&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/09/p1956-ggimage.html/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/09/p1956-ggimage.html/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rclone: command-line program to manage files on cloud storage.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 9, 2024 18:09 &lt;a href=&quot;https://rclone.org/&quot;&gt;Rclone: command-line program to manage files on cloud storage.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– via Danny Colin in Matrix chat, sounds great! –&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Rclone is a command-line program to manage files on cloud storage. It is a feature-rich alternative to cloud vendors' web storage interfaces. Over 70 cloud storage products support rclone including S3 object stores, business &amp;amp; consumer file storage services, as well as standard transfer protocols.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/04/29/p1-backup-wordpress-blog-httrack/&quot;&gt;How I used httrack to backup my Wordpress blog barbandroland.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/09/p1809-rclone-command-line-backup-to-cloud/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/09/p1809-rclone-command-line-backup-to-cloud/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Michael Nielsen:  How to be a wise optimist about science and technology? Do work on non-market safety. Do work on differential technology development, especially how to better align civilization with DTD. There's a hubris in pessimism, agreed!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 8, 2024 21:03 &lt;a href=&quot;https://michaelnotebook.com/optimism/&quot;&gt;Michael Nielsen:  How to be a wise optimist about science and technology? Do work on non-market safety. Do work on differential technology development, especially how to better align civilization with DTD. There’s a hubris in pessimism, agreed!&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Wow! Bravo read the whole thing! –&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;What, then, of the question of the title: how to be a wise optimist about science and technology? My condensed, provisional, personal answers: Do work on non-market safety. Do work on differential technology development, especially how to better align civilization with DTD. (I won't be individually prescriptive, since work on DTD will mean different things for different people, including: work on climate, on biosafety, on nuclear safety, on ways of improving the commons in general, on developing new amplifiers to modulate capitalism.) Despite the temptation and the honeyed words, don't work for AGI organizations unless they are making major sacrifices for non-market safety. Right now, it's not clear that includes any of the major companies. Finally: which world to choose: the precautionary world or the posthuman world? I'd say &quot;posthuman world&quot; if I felt confident that the organizations which aim to bring that world into existence were doing so in a way that prioritized non-market safety. But, as I said, right now I don't feel confident in that at all. I hope I'm wrong about that, and very much hope it's possible to help foster such a world. ... Is this enough for optimism? I think so. I don't see a guaranteed solution – but then, if the problem were easy, it would already have been solved! As I said earlier, there's often hubris in pessimism. The point is well made by Richard Feynman, recounting his mistaken pessimism about the future in response to the bombing of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, and his eventual belief that it's better to keep taking small optimistic steps, even in the face of daunting odds: ... [After returning from the Manhattan Project] I sat in a restaurant in New York… and I looked out at the buildings and I began to think, you know, about how much the radius of the Hiroshima bomb damage was and so forth… All those buildings, all smashed – and so on. And I would go along and I would see people building a bridge, or they'd be making a new road, and I thought, they're crazy, they just don't understand, they don't understand. Why are they making new things? It's so useless. But, fortunately, it's been useless for almost forty years now, hasn't it? So I've been wrong about it being useless making bridges and I'm glad those other people had the sense to go ahead. ... Let me conclude with some key takeaways from the essay:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October 25, 2018: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/10/25/p1-machine-learning-for-consumer-software-support-folks/&quot;&gt;Anybody have any case studies about machine learning for supporting consumer software and state of the art consumer software support in 2018?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/08/p2103-optimism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/08/p2103-optimism/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Om Malik and the other guy :-):: Will A.I. Eat The Browser?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 8, 2024 09:19 &lt;a href=&quot;https://crazystupidtech.com/archive/will-ai-eat-the-browser/&quot;&gt;Om Malik and the other guy :-):: Will A.I. Eat The Browser?&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;–&lt;strong&gt;Probably wrong opinion&lt;/strong&gt;: We’ll finally get the agent from the 1990s in something that vaguely resembles a web browser. We’ll use our voice as a command line and the LLM will work with us in a time consuming back and forth chat to get us what we want. For most people that will be better than using today’s web browser or today’s command line interface. For geeks they’ll use the traditional CLI and scripts and other programmatic stuff as well as the LLM agent. &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Miller’s optimism stems from the fact that the browser was able to metamorphose for mobile phones. Our mobile apps are essentially browsers with wrappers to perform specific tasks and make the internet more manageable and personalized. The next evolution might require a bit more contortion. ...As VR, AR, audio interfaces, and chat become ever more central to our daily lives — and not just for Vision Pro addicts like myself, but for everyone — the web browser’s limitations are becoming increasingly apparent.  There is no doubt in my mind that the implications of this seismic change in what a browser does, and how it works, will be felt far and wide.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/08/p0919-will-ai-eat-the-browser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/08/p0919-will-ai-eat-the-browser/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tablecruncher – Lightweight CSV editor for your Mac via a toot from  Alex Samuel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 7, 2024 22:27 &lt;a href=&quot;https://tablecruncher.com/&quot;&gt;Tablecruncher – Lightweight CSV editor for your Mac via a toot from  Alex Samuel&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;–whoah, macros in JS. Probably easier and faster to grok for non developers than miller aka mlr :-) –&amp;gt; QUOTE: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Use Javascript as a macro language to manipulate your CSV files. A simple API gives you access to all cells and you can change cell content as well as do abitrary calculations. &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/07/p2227-tablecruncher/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/07/p2227-tablecruncher/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Greg Wilson:: The Third Bit: Afraid of Change</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 4, 2024 07:19 &lt;a href=&quot;https://third-bit.com/2018/11/24/afraid-of-change/&quot;&gt;Greg Wilson:: The Third Bit: Afraid of Change&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;I think thought leaders in Silicon Valley started recommending it to each other for two reasons. First, it allows them to blame subordinates for not speaking out (again, ignoring the experience some of those subordinates may have had of bosses who say “I want to hear what you think” but really don’t). Second, it satisfies tech bros’ need to talk about something other than sexual harassment, racial discrimination, and pay inequity—in other words, their need to talk about things that sound important but won’t make them uncomfortable or undermine the system that they hope will make them rich.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/04/p0719-afraid-of-change/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/04/p0719-afraid-of-change/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nic Morales:: Cost of Convenience, a Wireless Shifting Review - BIKEPACKING.com</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 4, 2024 07:15 &lt;a href=&quot;https://bikepacking.com/plog/cost-of-convenience-wireless-shifting-review/&quot;&gt;Nic Morales:: Cost of Convenience, a Wireless Shifting Review - BIKEPACKING.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– can we invent electronic shifting that doesn’t require lithium batteries and complicated and bug prone proprietary software? I think so but there’s no will :-) –&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;I can’t answer all those questions. And living in a world that has normalized such energy usage is complex. I’m typing this on a computer powered by lithium batteries while sitting next to a phone powered by lithium batteries and being kept cool by a window unit A/C powered by electricity. But if we have to qualify and exonerate every potential criticism of new technologies through the sometimes unavoidable missteps of our current circumstance, we’ll never make anything better. I’m not proposing an unimpeachable solution to the moral and material ailments of our society—I’m 29 years old, I don’t know anything. I’m questioning the unnecessary complication of an activity that has meaningfully improved my life through the inherently revolutionary nature of its existence. &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/04/p0715-cost-of-convenience-wireless-shifting-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/04/p0715-cost-of-convenience-wireless-shifting-review/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dead Internet Souls | ★❤✰ Vicki Boykis ★❤✰</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 3, 2024 07:36 &lt;a href=&quot;https://vickiboykis.com/2024/09/19/dead-internet-souls/&quot;&gt;Dead Internet Souls | ★❤✰ Vicki Boykis ★❤✰&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– AMEN! Read the whole thing! –&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;If you are a human out there in the vast wilds of the new internet of dead souls, speak up. We are still out there, on the small web, being ingested into indie search engine indexes, on blogs, on websites. ... The machines are thinking, but so are people, and they’re still much better. I’m still out here. Come be out here with me, too.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/03/p0736-dead-internet-souls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/03/p0736-dead-internet-souls/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jason Velaquez:: Bluesky may have the juice, but we don't have to drink the Kool-Aid</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 3, 2024 07:31 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fromjason.xyz/p/notebook/bluesky-may-have-the-juice-but-we-don-t-have-to-drink-the-kool-aid/&quot;&gt;Jason Velaquez:: Bluesky may have the juice, but we don’t have to drink the Kool-Aid&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Communities cultivate. Markets extract. Cultivators make decisions based on what is best for the community. Extractors make the number go up. Communities can have markets, of course. But when markets run the community, we end up with the Internet we have today. Markets had their shot and they f🇺cked it up. It's time we brought back the virtual community.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– Amen! Read the whole thing :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/03/p0731-bluesky-may-have-the-juice-but-we-don-t-have-to-drink-the-kool-aid/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/03/p0731-bluesky-may-have-the-juice-but-we-don-t-have-to-drink-the-kool-aid/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
