<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 22:58:12 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 22:58:12 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: it's family background and luck more than 'meritocracy'. The authors' proposed 'moderated causal model' makes sense Ian R. Hadden, Céline Darnon, Lewis Doyle, Matthew J., Sébastien Goudeau, Andrei Cimpian :: Why the belief in meritocracy is so pervasive - ScienceDirect</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 14, 2025 19:14 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1364661324003292&quot;&gt;Me:: it’s family background and luck more than ‘meritocracy’. The authors’ proposed ‘moderated causal model’ makes sense Ian R. Hadden, Céline Darnon, Lewis Doyle, Matthew J., Sébastien Goudeau, Andrei Cimpian :: Why the belief in meritocracy is so pervasive - ScienceDirect&lt;/a&gt; via grimalkina’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@grimalkina/113827451914611149&quot;&gt;toot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1364661324003292&quot;&gt;Ian R. Hadden, Céline Darnon, Lewis Doyle, Matthew J., Sébastien Goudeau, Andrei Cimpian : Why the belief in meritocracy is so pervasive - ScienceDirect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘You can make it if you try.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is the rallying cry of meritocracy: that hard work – not luck or family background – determines success in life. The appeal of this idea runs deep [1]. Although people recognize, to varying degrees across countries [2], that factors other than hard work matter, they typically fail to grasp the true extent of their influence. For example, people underestimate the levels of inequalities in wealth [1] and overestimate the extent to which people move between economic strata through their own efforts [3].
This ‘myth of meritocracy’ is far from cost-free: it contributes to the acceptance and legitimation of historical inequalities between demographic groups. For example, when people believe they live in a meritocratic society, they are less likely to support policies that reduce income inequality [4] and more likely to allocate resources to individuals who already have the most [5].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Instead, a more promising avenue is to invoke a more nuanced and more accurate moderated causal model, wherein the dose–response relation between effort and success is calibrated by external factors (Figure 1C). This conveys the reality that the same amount of effort yields greater dividends for people in more favorable social circumstances (e.g., better-resourced schools, better-connected families). Just as a seed planted in fertile soil will fare quite differently from an identical one planted in a desert, the same ‘dose’ of effort does not take everyone equally far. This moderated causal model, with its balance of accuracy and intuitive appeal, is likely to be a valuable communication device in efforts to debunk the myth of meritocracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 30, 2024 &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/30/p0030-yes-americans-are-much-richer-than/&quot;&gt;Me:: file this under d⭕minant hegemony gotta d⭕minant hegemony :-) Yes, 🇦mericans are much richer when it comes to stuff than Japanese people (according to rich 🇦mericans like N⭕ah Sm🇮th LOL), easy for N⭕ah to say from his position of privilege, stuff and the ability to ‘innovate’ is priority 1. Doesn’t health, safety and quality of life and less inequality for all matter to entitled, wealthy 🇦mericans :-) ? Evidently not ?!?!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/14/p1914-s1364661324003292-why-belief-meritocracy-pervasive/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/14/p1914-s1364661324003292-why-belief-meritocracy-pervasive/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: The entshᜁttification rot is everywhere because software is everywhere! Ed Zitron:: Never Forgive Them</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 13, 2025 11:27  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wheresyoured.at/never-forgive-them/&quot;&gt;Me:: The entshᜁttification rot is everywhere because software is everywhere! Ed Zitron:: Never Forgive Them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wheresyoured.at/never-forgive-them/&quot;&gt;Ed Zitron:: Never Forgive Them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be clear, I don’t believe that this gradual enshᜁttification is part of some grand, Machiavellian long game by the tech companies, but rather the product of multiple consecutive decisions made in response to short-term financial needs. Even if it was, the result would be the same — people wouldn’t notice how bad things have gotten until it’s too late, or they might just assume that tech has always sucked, or they’re just personally incapable of using the tools that are increasingly fundamental to living in a modern world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are the victim of a con — one so pernicious that you’ve likely tuned it out despite the fact it’s part of almost every part of your life. It hurts everybody you know in different ways, and it hurts people more based on their socioeconomic status. It pokes and prods and twists millions of little parts of your life, and it’s everywhere, so you have to ignore it, because complaining about it feels futile, like complaining about the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It isn’t. You’re battered by the Rot Economy, and a tech industry that has become so obsessed with growth that you, the paying customer, are a nuisance to be mitigated far more than a participant in an exchange of value. A death cult has taken over the markets, using software as a mechanism to extract value at scale in the pursuit of growth at the cost of user happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These people want everything from you — to control every moment you spend working with them so that you may provide them with more ways to make money, even if doing so doesn’t involve you getting anything else in return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;July 12, 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/12/p1-the-whole-miasma-of-the-internet/&quot;&gt;The whole miasma of the internet has blocked me from blogging but not for long :-)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/13/p1127-never-forgive-them/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/13/p1127-never-forgive-them/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Graydon Hoare:: 50 Years in Formal World: Mainstream Computing's Mirror Universe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 13, 2025. 09:07 &lt;a href=&quot;http://d22yoqkt46k26p.cloudfront.net/graydon/talks/formal-world.pdf&quot;&gt;Graydon Hoare:: 50 Years in Formal World: Mainstream Computing’s Mirror Universe&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;lt;– I want to learn and use the formal world if it makes sense for “hobbyists” :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/13/p0907-formal-world/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/13/p0907-formal-world/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>'Cotton' she said to him 'I am Satoshi Nakaoto' &lt;-- LOL quote from Steve Berry's Novel The Atlas Maneuver, page 70</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 12, 2025 21:26  &lt;a href=&quot;https://steveberry.org/books/the-atlas-maneuver/&quot;&gt;‘Cotton’ she said to him ‘I am Satoshi Nakaoto’ &amp;lt;– LOL quote from Steve Berry’s Novel The Atlas Maneuver, page 70&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Pretty sure the real truth will be much stranger if/when we ever find out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/12/p2126-the-atlas-maneuver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/12/p2126-the-atlas-maneuver/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Trʊdeau Derangement Syndrome (because irrational?!?!) victims: D🄐nielle Smᜁth, St🄞ckwell D🄐y and all the usual C🄞nservative suspects Max Fawcett:: Trʊmp’s threats expose the tr🄐itors in our midst | Canada's National Observer: Climate News</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 12, 2025 19:30 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalobserver.com/2025/01/10/opinion/trump-threats-traitors&quot;&gt;Me:: Trʊdeau Derangement Syndrome (because irrational?!?!) victims: D🄐nielle Smᜁth, St🄞ckwell D🄐y and all the usual C🄞nservative suspects Max Fawcett:: Trʊmp’s threats expose the tr🄐itors in our midst ¦ Canada’s National Observer: Climate News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nationalobserver.com/2025/01/10/opinion/trump-threats-traitors&quot;&gt;Max Fawcett:: Trʊmp’s threats expose the tr🄐itors in our midst ¦ Canada’s National Observer: Climate News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So why are so many C🄐nadian C🄞nservatives welcoming, or at least entertaining, Trʊmp’s advances? Because Jʊstin Trʊdeau made them do it, apparently. His now infamous remark about how “there is no core identity, no mainstream in Canada” to fellow Canadian Guy Lawson in a 2015 New York Times magazine  profile, one that spoke to his father’s vision for our national culture and its unique ability to embrace difference and diversity, has somehow become an invitation to disloyalty and cowardice. Never mind that it was an attempt to articulate a more inclusive view of our national identity, one that clearly set us apart from America. For many C🄞nservatives in Canada, Trʊdeau’s belief in a “p🄞stn🄐tional” future was all the excuse they ever needed to betray their own country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is by far the most pitiful example yet of Trʊdeau-derangement syndrome, and that’s a category with plenty of strong contenders. I assure you that there is nothing any future government could say or do that would weaken my commitment to this country and its future. My loyalty and patriotism aren’t a function of who’s in power at the moment, and they certainly aren’t about to be overridden by petty partisanship, much less a misunderstood, decade-old quote in the New York Times. If only the folks who had spent so much time and energy over the last few years publicly professing their supposed love for this country felt the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/12/p1930-trmp-threats-traitors/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/12/p1930-trmp-threats-traitors/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I am really going to have to try another app for bicycle route finding. Not impressed by Google Maps and Transit app. Google Maps once more steers me wrong (recommended Nanaimo and Victoria instead of Lakewood - Strava:: Zum Pho Dundas :-) </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 11, 2025 17:46 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/13319298712&quot;&gt;I am really going to have to try another app for bicycle route finding. Not impressed by Google Maps and Transit app. Google Maps once more steers me wrong (recommended Nanaimo and Victoria instead of Lakewood - Strava:: Zum Pho Dundas :-) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/11/p1746-13319298712-google-maps-error-nanaimo-victoria-instead-lakewood/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/11/p1746-13319298712-google-maps-error-nanaimo-victoria-instead-lakewood/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Will H5N1 or mpox go pandemic? We don't know at the moment. Donald G. McNeil Jr. :: My book: The Wisdom of Plagues is out in paperback. It has a new chapter with a few things…</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 10, 2025 07:52 &lt;a href=&quot;https://donaldgmcneiljr1954.medium.com/my-book-is-out-in-paperback-9705ec01af2e&quot;&gt;Me:: Will H5N1 or mpox go pandemic? We don’t know at the moment. Donald G. McNeil Jr. :: My book: The Wisdom of Plagues is out in paperback. It has a new chapter with a few things…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the Whole Thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://donaldgmcneiljr1954.medium.com/my-book-is-out-in-paperback-9705ec01af2e&quot;&gt;Donald G. McNeil Jr.:: My book: The Wisdom of Plagues is out in paperback. It has a new chapter with a few things…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My book The Wisdom of Plagues is out in paperback as of today. Since I finished writing the hardback edition in the fall of 2023 and viruses keep mutating — as do perceptions of historical events — Simon &amp;amp; Schuster let me write a new addendum chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most of it is about our false memories of Covid and the threats of H5N1 and the new central African strain of mpox/monkeypox. I didn’t make any wild predictions because I had to file in September and I feared H5N1 would shift course in the publishing interim. It has: it’s now clearly two separate clades, one in birds and one in cows. And both can infect humans, and as of this week, one human has died of it. That is definitely bad news. The fact that variants infecting humans turned up late in the illness of the Louisiana patient is worrying, but not terribly surprising. When a virus is under a long but weak couterattack from a human immune system, it mutates to evade that attack. That doesn’t necessarily mean that strain will arise in nature. We still can’t say whether this virus will go pandemic or just pick humans off one by one as it has since 1997.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 5, 2025: Me:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/05/p2213-zgyj-d31/&quot;&gt;We can suppress any viral disease if we have the will via: multiple vaccinations, clean air, Five years of the COVID-19 pandemic: An interview with Dr. Arijit Chakravarty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/10/p0752-wisdom-of-plagues-h5n1-mpox/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/10/p0752-wisdom-of-plagues-h5n1-mpox/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Nvidia GPUs don't work currently on Raspbery PI and you need a Linux kernel patch for AMD GPUs 2024-11-19:: Jeff Geerling:: AMD Radeon PRO W7700 running on Raspberry Pi  </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 9, 2025 09:30 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2024/amd-radeon-pro-w7700-running-on-raspberry-pi&quot;&gt;Me:: Nvidia GPUs don’t work currently on Raspbery PI and you need a Linux kernel patch for AMD GPUs 2024-11-19:: Jeff Geerling:: AMD Radeon PRO W7700 running on Raspberry Pi  &lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– someday there will be a plug and play solution for raspberry Pis. Not there yet :-) &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;After years of work among a bunch of people in the Pi community (special callout to Coreforge!), we finally have multiple generations of AMD graphics cards working on the Raspberry Pi 5.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– see also the youtube video:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AyR7iCS7gNI&quot;&gt;A GPU-powered Pi for more efficient AI?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/09/p0930-amd-radeon-pro-w7700-running-on-raspberry-pi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/09/p0930-amd-radeon-pro-w7700-running-on-raspberry-pi/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Secular Monks is a scary but accurate phrase for many men Derek Thompson:: The Anti-Social Century - The Atlantic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 8, 2025 22:44 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2025/02/american-loneliness-personality-politics/681091/&quot;&gt;Me:: Secular Monks is a scary but accurate phrase for many men Derek Thompson:: The Anti-Social Century - The Atlantic&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Taggart called these men “secular monks” for their combination of old-fashioned austerity and modern solipsism. “Practitioners submit themselves to ever more rigorous, monitored forms of ascetic self-control,” he wrote, “among them, cold showers, intermittent fasting, data-driven health optimization, and meditation boot camps.”&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/08/p2244-american-loneliness-personality-politics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/08/p2244-american-loneliness-personality-politics/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: while it lasts :-) add cooked,wiki in front of an recipe url to get a no fluff reader mode style recipe Recipes that work:: Elise Bauer:: Pasta Carbonara</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 8, 2025 20:35 &lt;a href=&quot;https://cooked.wiki/new/recent/02d9102d-bfbd-419e-b0bc-c078b0c7545e&quot;&gt;Me:: while it lasts :-) add cooked,wiki in front of an recipe url to get a no fluff reader mode style recipe Recipes that work:: Elise Bauer:: Pasta Carbonara&lt;/a&gt; –&amp;gt; original recipe is here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simplyrecipes.com/recipes/spaghetti_alla_carbonara/&quot;&gt;Elise Bauer:: Pasta Carbonara ¦ simply recipes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/08/p2035-pasta-carbonara-cooked-wiki/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/08/p2035-pasta-carbonara-cooked-wiki/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
