<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 14:43:30 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 14:43:30 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to upgrade the Wavlink UTD01 Thunderbolt 3 dock Ubuntu driver: switch to insecure boot; download, compile and install firmware from Wavlink's site</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are you on Ubuntu and you see an  error message like the following when trying to install a driver? &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;modprobe: ERROR: could not insert 'r8152': Operation not permitted&lt;/code&gt;
Steps: 1. Switch to Insecure Boot as below 2. Download the &lt;a href=&quot;https://files2.wavlink.com/drivers/PC-peripherals/RTL8153/RTL8153_Driver_Unix%20(Linux).zip&quot;&gt;driver&lt;/a&gt;  from the Wavlink site and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo make all&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The real fix of course is to sign the modules yourself using your own cert or a cert that may already exist for your driver: See &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.ubuntu.com/UEFI/SecureBoot/DKMS&quot;&gt;DKMS modules need to be configured to work with UEFI Secure Boot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-switch-to-insecure-boot-on-ubuntu&quot;&gt;How to switch to Insecure Boot on Ubuntu&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Found on Ask Ubuntu:&lt;a href=&quot;https://askubuntu.com/questions/1114867/operation-not-permitted-when-trying-to-modprobe-xpad&quot;&gt;“Operation not permitted” when trying to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;modprobe xpad&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are facing this error modprobe: ERROR: could not insert ‘rtl8723de’: Operation not permitted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution is to disabled the Secure Boot. Firstly check if SecureBoot is enabled on Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install mokutil “sudo apt-get install mokutil”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and check the status of SecureBoot “mokutil –sb-state”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case it is enabled run command “sudo mokutil –disable-validation”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now enter a temporary password between 8 to 16 digits. We will use this password later. Enter the same password again to confirm. Once it’s done reboot the system and press any key when you see the blue screen (MOK management). Select Change Secure Boot state. Enter the password you had selected before and press Enter. Select Yes to disable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;error-messages-when-trying-to-install-the-driver-on-ubuntu-with-secure-boot&quot;&gt;Error messages when trying to install the driver on Ubuntu with Secure Boot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;roland@roland-XPS-13-9310:~/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0$ sudo make all
[sudo] password for roland: 
make -C /lib/modules/5.6.0-1042-oem/build M=/home/roland/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0 clean
make[1]: Entering directory '/usr/src/linux-headers-5.6.0-1042-oem'
  CLEAN   /home/roland/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0/Module.symvers
make[1]: Leaving directory '/usr/src/linux-headers-5.6.0-1042-oem'
make -C /lib/modules/5.6.0-1042-oem/build M=/home/roland/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0 modules
make[1]: Entering directory '/usr/src/linux-headers-5.6.0-1042-oem'
  CC [M]  /home/roland/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0/r8152.o
  MODPOST 1 modules
  CC [M]  /home/roland/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0/r8152.mod.o
  LD [M]  /home/roland/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0/r8152.ko
make[1]: Leaving directory '/usr/src/linux-headers-5.6.0-1042-oem'
make -C /lib/modules/5.6.0-1042-oem/build M=/home/roland/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0 INSTALL_MOD_DIR=kernel/drivers/net/usb modules_install
make[1]: Entering directory '/usr/src/linux-headers-5.6.0-1042-oem'
  INSTALL /home/roland/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0/r8152.ko
At main.c:160:
- SSL error:02001002:system library:fopen:No such file or directory: ../crypto/bio/bss_file.c:69
- SSL error:2006D080:BIO routines:BIO_new_file:no such file: ../crypto/bio/bss_file.c:76
sign-file: certs/signing_key.pem: No such file or directory
  DEPMOD  5.6.0-1042-oem
Warning: modules_install: missing 'System.map' file. Skipping depmod.
make[1]: Leaving directory '/usr/src/linux-headers-5.6.0-1042-oem'
modprobe r8152
modprobe: ERROR: could not insert 'r8152': Operation not permitted
make: *** [Makefile:42: install] Error 1
roland@roland-XPS-13-9310:~/Downloads/r8152-2.13.0$
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/02/04/p1-how-to-upgrade-driver-wavlink-utd01a-thunderbolt3-dock-ubuntu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/02/04/p1-how-to-upgrade-driver-wavlink-utd01a-thunderbolt3-dock-ubuntu/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Darius Kazemi: How do you compose for infinity? Via Matt Webb: Filtered for lo-fi strange new worlds</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt; Jan 31, 2021.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://tinysubversions.com/&quot;&gt;Darius Kazemi&lt;/a&gt; So how do you compose for infinity? via Matt Webb Interconnected: &lt;a href=&quot;http://interconnected.org/home/2021/01/29/filtered&quot;&gt;Filtered for lo-fi strange new worlds&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;lt;— “A simple for loop can, in a few seconds, generate more information than a human being can consume in a lifetime. When we make art with code, we have to confront this fact. So how do you compose for infinity?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/02/03/p1-darius-kazemi-how-do-you-compose-for-infinity-matt-webb-filtered-for-lo-fi-strange-new-worlds/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/02/03/p1-darius-kazemi-how-do-you-compose-for-infinity-matt-webb-filtered-for-lo-fi-strange-new-worlds/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Greg Wilson: Software Tools in JavaScript</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stjs.tech/vol1/&quot;&gt;Greg Wilson: Software Tools in JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If I were to finally learn JavaScript :-) I’d probably start with this not too wordy, just right intro to JS.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/02/02/p1-greg-wilson-software-tools-in-javascript/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/02/02/p1-greg-wilson-software-tools-in-javascript/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Monopolies Slowed the Vaccine Roll-Out, and Small Business Sped it Up -  CVS and Walgreens didn't deliver. Local pharmacists did</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mattstoller.substack.com/p/how-monopolies-slowed-the-vaccine&quot;&gt;How Monopolies Slowed the Vaccine Roll-Out, and Small Business Sped it Up CVS and Walgreens didn’t deliver. Local pharmacists did&lt;/a&gt;. (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/timbray/status/1354500383679205378&quot;&gt;Tim Bray&lt;/a&gt;): “Last February, I wrote a piece called “How CVS Became a Health Care Tyrant,” showing how CVS bought its way to dominance. CVS’s strategy isn’t oriented around offering better service, but to become a bottleneck for health care the way that Google is a bottleneck for the internet. “
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Sad but not surprising. Because c*pitalism s*cks :-) And so do all isms like s*cialism, c*mmunisim, and an*rchy&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/02/01/p1-monopolies-slowed-covid-19-virus-rollout-small-business-sped-it-up-cvs-walgreens/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/02/01/p1-monopolies-slowed-covid-19-virus-rollout-small-business-sped-it-up-cvs-walgreens/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jeremiah Owyang-The Future of Social Audio: Startups, Roadmap, Business Models, and a Forecast &lt;- will audio rival video by the end of 2020s? I don't think so but I'd love to be proven wrong since the human voice is amazing </title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeremiah Owyang: &lt;a href=&quot;https://web-strategist.com/blog/2021/01/30/the-future-of-social-audio-startups-roadmap-business-models-and-a-forecast/&quot;&gt;The Future of Social Audio: Startups, Roadmap, Business Models, and a Forecast&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– “I call this the “Goldilocks” medium for the 2020s: Text is not enough, and video is too much; social audio is just right. It represents the opportunity for social connection and empathy without the downsides of video”
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I am not 100% convinced but hey we have so many really  bad videos now including mine :-) so why not a world of bad but fun audio :-) after all &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2019/03/16/p1-voice-is-just-a-content-type-everybody-should-publish-what-they-want-video-audio-text-whatever-to-whoever-they-want/&quot;&gt;There’s nothing special about voice or podcasts, everybody should be able to publish what they: voice, audio, text, video whatever whenever they want to whomever they want&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Good audio quality used to be hard to capture but maybe not anymore with the rise of AirPods and other high quality bluetooth headsets!?!?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;And I don’t see the incentive; show me the money :-). What is the YouTube of audio? What is the TikTok of audio? Is it Clubhouse? Is it anchor.fm Not convinced but I am a gr*mpy old person who’s been podcasting since 2004 so what do I know.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gratuitous plug :-) : check out my “podcast” at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rolandmicroblog.com/&quot;&gt;rolandmicroblog.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/31/p1-jeremiah-owyang-future-social-audio-startups-roadmap-business-models-forecast/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/31/p1-jeremiah-owyang-future-social-audio-startups-roadmap-business-models-forecast/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BC Alliance for Arts and Culture: Digital Ladders: March 4, 2021 - Ask me anything...About Custom Merchandise</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ll be speaking and taking questions about custom merch like custom tshirts, shoes, mugs etc plus a few cool tools on March 4, 2021 but there are many more starting January 27. They are weekly and from noon-1p.m  Pacific and they are free. I highly recommend each and every session. Get in where you fit in! The sessions are recorded if you can’t make it live!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Check it out on the digital ladders website: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalladders.ca/ama&quot;&gt;Ask me anything&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Here are the details of the session copy and pasted form their website which has even more detail! Read the whole thing: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalladders.ca/ama&quot;&gt;digital ladders: ama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to find out about accessibility and other details.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;### #1 Ask Me Anything… About Discoverability&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, January 27 - 12:00 - 1:00 p.m.
  with Annelise Larson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;If you want your work to be found online, you’ll need search engines like Google on your side. Come ready to ask your questions about what it takes to be search engine friendly and get discovered more easily. &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/qHiMF7Eel3I&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch the recording&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;### #2 Ask Me Anything… About Working with Digital Specialists&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, February 2 - 12:00 - 1:00 p.m.
  with Jai Djwa and guest Anju Singh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Learn about working with website developers, agencies and freelancers. This conversation can cover tips and pitfalls around hiring and working with digital specialists including expectations, workflow, timing and delivery of projects. &lt;a href=&quot;https://us02web.zoom.us/meeting/register/tZcldumurDooEtHLm_rH1qYf2YQ2xIYI5aYj&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;### #3 Ask Me Anything… About a Simple Social Media Plan&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, February 10 - 12:00 - 1:00 p.m.
  with Shannon Emmerson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Learn how a small team or a one-person operation can create and deliver on a simple social media plan, using free tools to optimize your content. &lt;a href=&quot;https://us02web.zoom.us/meeting/register/tZIuf--uqTgsGt3Q-BWdsMmm-qeMROk-3CEt&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;### #4 Ask Me Anything… About Free A/V Production Software&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, February 17 - 12:00 - 1:00 p.m.
  with Johnny Kalangis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Learn about the free video and audio production software DaVinci Resolve, iMovie and Audacity. This will include into these tools, how to make cuts, what effects are possible and then how to get your content back out and sharable. Bring your own questions to ask, and let’s get into specifics. &lt;a href=&quot;https://us02web.zoom.us/meeting/register/tZAuc-6tqD8jHtbPKIGGjvpa0x9CqyBOwI_H&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;### #5 Ask Me Anything… About Setting Up a Website&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, February 24 - 12:00 - 1:00 p.m.
  with Adrian Jones&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;We’ll chat about registering a domain, deciding on the best host/server specs for your needs, handling emails and whether you should use a website builder, content management system or hire a designer and/or developer, and anything else you want! &lt;a href=&quot;https://us02web.zoom.us/meeting/register/tZcodOCrrjIuEtQ3YIl97Ngnbt07FDPTCz8N&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;### #6 Ask Me Anything…..About Custom Merchandise&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, March 3 - 12:00 - 1:00 p.m.
  with Roland Tanglao&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Learn about creating custom merch, and go over a few free tools that help you create and connect to your audience! &lt;a href=&quot;https://us02web.zoom.us/meeting/register/tZMvdOirqT8oH9wKf3LQve4aT7po_pOy7pTE&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;### sessions&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;### faculty&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Our &lt;strong&gt;Digital Ladders Faculty&lt;/strong&gt; includes some of BC’s foremost digital experts. Among them, they’ve worked for Microsoft, Google, Disney, Electronic Arts, Mozilla Firefox, PBS, Niantic Labs, CBC, the BBC, Just For Laughs Comedy Festival, the National Film Board of Canada, and the 2010 Olympic Games, to name only a few heavy-hitting organizations. They’ve earned Emmy® and Webby Awards, and have contributed to major motion pictures, AAA video games, international marketing campaigns, educational programs, Super Bowl commercials, web platforms, tech start-ups, mobile apps, music videos, television and radio programs, and everything else under the sun. &lt;strong&gt;They’re a digital dream team, and they’re here to bring *your* digital dreams to life.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitalladders.ca/who-we-are/&quot;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; to find out more about our Faculty.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;An AMA is more or less exactly what it sounds like — an opportunity to ask someone anything that’s on your mind on a given topic. In Digital Ladders terms, it’s an opportunity for you to bring your specific questions, concerns, wonders, dilemmas, hopes, etc., to a digital expert.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Each presenter will focus on a topic and will give a 5-10 minute overview including some basic information. After that, it’s up to those attending to ask questions to guide and drive the conversation. By engaging with individual questions, the presenter can really respond directly to what’s uniquely relevant to participants, in an informal and relaxed environment.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re facing a specific hurdle in the planning of a project, can’t get the hang of a certain elusive piece of software, or find yourself quickly needing new tools as you tackle a project solo or with a small team, you’ll get the answer you need to keep moving forward.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/30/p1-ask-me-anything-bc-alliance-custom-merchandise/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/30/p1-ask-me-anything-bc-alliance-custom-merchandise/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kevin Montrose: Overthinking CSV With Cesil: An Introduction. Also, github sponsors are few and far between</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 25, 2020.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevinmontrose.com/2020/05/28/overthinking-csv-with-cesil-an-introduction/&quot;&gt;Overthinking CSV With Cesil: An Introduction&lt;/a&gt; - I don’t know C# but I love this “little” project and its series of explanatory blog posts. Love what he is “committed to” namely (especially love to learn about comprehensive test coverage for a useful but small project, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/27/p1-test-driven-development-python-tutorial-anthony-shaw/&quot;&gt;Anthony Shaw: Getting Started With Testing in Python &amp;lt;– I’d like to do TDD in python, ruby and R someday :-)&lt;/a&gt; ) :
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Async as a first class citizen&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Maximum consumer flexibility&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Extensive documentation&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Comprehensive test coverage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Adopting C# 8 features&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Modern patterns and conventions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Efficiency, especially in terms of allocations&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See also:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://kevinmontrose.com/2020/09/24/overthinking-csv-with-cesil-open-source-update/&quot;&gt;Overthinking CSV With Cesil: Open Source Update&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;— “.First, the GitHub sponsors update – not a single one. I find this unsurprising, as I’m sure most readers do – honestly, it took some effort to not snark about the likely outcome in earlier posts … My big takeaway from this little sponsorship experiment is: things like GitHub Sponsors are tools you can use but creating a sustainable open source project is ultimately a job”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/28/p1-kevin-montrose-cesil-overthinking-csv-introduction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/28/p1-kevin-montrose-cesil-overthinking-csv-introduction/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anthony Shaw: Getting Started With Testing in Python &lt;-- I'd like to do TDD in python, ruby and R someday :-)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 17, 2020. &lt;a href=&quot;https://realpython.com/python-testing/#choosing-a-test-runner&quot;&gt;Getting Started With Testing in Python&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;—- i would like to do Test Driven Development for my tshirt visualizations and in the future for scripting at work (not merely learn :-) !) in Python, Ruby and R . Two year old Python tutorial seems like a fine place to start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/27/p1-test-driven-development-python-tutorial-anthony-shaw/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/27/p1-test-driven-development-python-tutorial-anthony-shaw/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>@maggiecodes_: How I applied to a Tech Job using a POST request using Insomnia an open source REST API client</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: 08september2020 &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/maggiecodes_&quot;&gt;@maggiecodes_&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.to/maggiecodes_/how-i-applied-to-a-tech-job-using-a-post-request-193d&quot;&gt;How I applied to a Tech Job using a POST request&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;— geeky but i love it, the job was “technical support engineer”  at plaid, an online finance company “There are numerous API tools out on the market. I chose to use Insomnia, an open-source API client  application, to send my request” &amp;lt;— need to check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://insomnia.rest/&quot;&gt;Insomnia&lt;/a&gt; which sounds great!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UPDATE: I’m using Insomnia for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/20/p1-started-my-new-job-element-io-november30/&quot;&gt;element.io work&lt;/a&gt; with Matrix APIs and it is indeed great!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/26/p1-insomnia-rest-client-applying-for-a-job-via-an-api/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/26/p1-insomnia-rest-client-applying-for-a-job-via-an-api/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Maps and cameras are neglected app runtimes aka platforms</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matt Webb: &lt;a href=&quot;http://interconnected.org/home/2021/01/20/runtimes&quot;&gt;Maps and cameras are neglected app runtimes&lt;/a&gt;  “Going further. In-view camera functionality should be user-installable. Recognise the prefix on a particular QR code, and a mini app interface pops up. Imagine how useful this would be for taking inventory or machine maintenance: show the barcode sticker to the camera, and see when this parcel is due to be picked up, or the maintenance schedule of this particular bit of kit, right in the camera, and so on.”
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;100% agree that maps and runtimes are effectively de facto platforms and runtimes and this should be made more explicit! By explicit I mean, add an app store (for add-ons like filters and other behaviour just like chat has an app store for stickers) and other affordances of a real platform!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/25/p1-matt-webb-cameras-maps-runtimes-aka-platforms/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/01/25/p1-matt-webb-cameras-maps-runtimes-aka-platforms/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
