<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:10:06 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:10:06 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>It's 2025: could websites, blog posts and newsletters use links to actually link to the restaurant, website, museum, etc that they're referring to pretty please :-) ?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;#LOLIHaveBeenAskingThisForAtLeast20Years ;-) Also I still hate newsletters (I’d rather read your website especially if it has RSS) and won’t read them even though I subscribe and I am still not starting a newsletter :-) #Ymmv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 7, 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/04/07/p1-blogs-and-rss-are-dead-but-since-nothing-to-sell-no-email-newsletter/&quot;&gt;Agree with Chuq! The blog is dead and so is RSS but since i’m not trying to sell you anything (yet) i will continue to blog, generate RSS &amp;amp; not have an email newsletter #ymmv #doWhatMakesYouHappyAndGivesYouThe’Engagement’YouSeek :-)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/18/p2000-websites-blog-posts-newsletters-should-link-to-restaurant-website-museum-websites-pretty-please/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/18/p2000-websites-blog-posts-newsletters-should-link-to-restaurant-website-museum-websites-pretty-please/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Apeman R1 Seeker rear view real-time video camera shows lots people illegally driving with their daytime running lights OFF behind me in the city of Vancouver.</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Law abiding people don’t exist when driving cars (as well as bicycles; bicycles aren’t 4000 pounds of daily danger, the consequences of law breaking are much lower on a bicycle especially an “acoustic” :-) one; I don’t condone breaking traffic laws when bicycling or driving.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I ride (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/athletes/22831652&quot;&gt;my rides on Strava&lt;/a&gt;) 12km (6km each way Trout Lake to Gastown) Monday-Friday and I see in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/667837446/seeker-4k-bike-dashcam-and-safety-lighting-system&quot;&gt;Apeman R1 seeker rear view real time video camera&lt;/a&gt; I got in 2023 or was it 2024 :-) at least a couple of cars or trucks with their daytime running lights off. These people are probably the ones who complain about bicyclists not following traffic laws LOL.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For a good time :-) see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drivesmartbc.ca/safety-equipment/viewpoint-daytime-running-lights&quot;&gt;VIEWPOINT - Daytime Running Lights&lt;/a&gt; which has this juicy &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Daytime running lights have been mandatory for vehicles in Canada since 1990. It appears many drivers and vehicle dealers are not aware of this requirement. Having driven thousands of kilometres over the last 40 years I know that DRL can help prevent accidents particularly on poor light and rainy conditions.&lt;/code&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 14, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/14/p2012-mlk-double-standard-law-enforcement-respect-for-laws/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: There is a double standard in the enforcement of law, a double standard in the respect for particular laws. &amp;lt;- ‘Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?’, 1967.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/17/p2209-apeman-seeker-rear-view-real-time-video-camera-illegally-driving-daytime-running-lights-off-vancouver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/17/p2209-apeman-seeker-rear-view-real-time-video-camera-illegally-driving-daytime-running-lights-off-vancouver/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing Tariffs are justified for two reasons: 1. to pay for international freight emissions 2. social, fiscal and environmental dumping ; Thomas Piketty:: Rethinking world trade</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 17, 2025 02:14 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lemonde.fr/blog/piketty/2025/10/07/rethinking-world-trade/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing Tariffs are justified for two reasons: 1. to pay for international freight emissions 2. social, fiscal and environmental dumping 3. ; Thomas Piketty:: Rethinking world trade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lemonde.fr/blog/piketty/2025/10/07/rethinking-world-trade/&quot;&gt;Thomas Piketty:: Rethinking world trade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The first reason for implementing tariffs is that international freight generates pollution that accounts for 7% of global emissions. Economists have long underestimated this environmental cost, using a low value for the metric ton of carbon (between €100 and €200). However, the worsening of global warming has led to a reassessment. The costs stemming from emissions – natural disasters, decline in economic activity and so on – are now estimated at about €1,000 per ton, if not more, without even factoring in loss of well-being and non-economic costs. Using this value, one would need to apply average tariffs of around 15% on global trade flows to compensate for warming linked to freight, with significant variations depending on the type of goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The second justification for tariffs is social, fiscal and environmental dumping. Some countries apply less stringent regulations than others, allowing producers based there to undercut competitors. In practical terms, China currently accounts for 30% of global emissions, with exported emissions making up about 20% of this (or 6% of the global total). At €1,000 per ton, average tariffs of about 80% would be needed on Chinese exports to account for this environmental cost. If focusing only on net exported emissions (after subtracting imported emissions), which is about 10% of China’s emissions (3% of the global total), the necessary tariffs would be around 40%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now to social dumping. Wages account for 49% of gross domestic product in China, compared to 64% in Europe. This distorts competition and would require compensatory tariffs of about 15%. A similar calculation can be made for fiscal dumping, especially regarding corporate taxes and state subsidies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As with carbon, the aim is not to penalize China per se, but to encourage it to pay better wages, at which point the compensatory tax could be lifted. China has no need to accumulate endless trade surpluses; it should first continue its plans for decarbonization (which are further along than in the US, for example) and increase its wages and domestic demand. In the long run, if the US does not change course, Europe and China will have to impose significant sanctions on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In any case, tariffs are not an end in themselves: They can be dispensed with if binding agreements are put in place to achieve the same objectives. They can also be replaced by targeted financial sanctions if those prove more effective. The exact amounts should be determined following thorough democratic deliberation, conducted transparently, ideally within transnational assemblies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p1814-thomas-piketty-tariffs-freight-emissions-socal-fiscal-environmental-dumping-rethinking-world-trade/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p1814-thomas-piketty-tariffs-freight-emissions-socal-fiscal-environmental-dumping-rethinking-world-trade/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Recipes that probably work :-) ; Margaret Bose-Johnson:: Pink Pasta - Fettuccine with Beet, Smoked Salmon, &amp;amp; Feta ¦ Kitchen Frau</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 17, 2025 00:16 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kitchenfrau.com/pink-pasta-fettuccine-with-beet-salmon-feta/&quot;&gt;ME:: Recipes that probably work :-) ; Margaret Bose-Johnson:: Pink Pasta - Fettuccine with Beet, Smoked Salmon, &amp;amp; Feta ¦ Kitchen Frau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kitchenfrau.com/pink-pasta-fettuccine-with-beet-salmon-feta/&quot;&gt;Margaret Bose-Johnson:: Pink Pasta - Fettuccine with Beet, Smoked Salmon, &amp;amp; Feta ¦ Kitchen Frau&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pink-pasta---fettuccine-with-beet-smoked-salmon-and-feta&quot;&gt;Pink Pasta - Fettuccine with Beet, Smoked Salmon, and Feta&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;½ lb (225gms) uncooked fettuccine noodles, gluten-free or regular
    1 medium beet (~2½/6.5cm diameter) (1 packed cup when shredded)
    ½ medium onion
    2 tablespoons butter
    ¼ teaspoon salt
    ¼ teaspoon pepper
    1 cup chicken broth
    ¼ cup dry white vermouth or dry white wine
    ½ cup (120ml) heavy cream
    3.5 oz (100gms) smoked salmon slices (about ½ cup, packed)
    1 tablespoon capers
    ½ cup (60gms) crumbled feta cheese, plus a bit extra for garnish
    chopped fresh dill or parsley for serving - optional&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Set a large pot of salted water on to boil. (I use 1 teaspoon salt.) When it boils, add the fettuccine and cook for one minute less than the package recommends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While the water is boiling and the pasta is cooking, prepare the sauce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Peel the beet with a vegetable peeler, leaving the stem intact for a handhold while grating it. Shred the beet on the large holes of a cheese grater. Dice the onion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Melt the butter in a heavy-bottomed saucepan over medium heat. Add the shredded beet, diced onion, salt, and pepper, and cook until the beets are wilted, 3 to 4 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Add the chicken broth and the vermouth or wine. Cover and simmer for 5 minutes. Add the cream and keep warm until the pasta is finished cooking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Reserve a few thin slices of smoked salmon to garnish the finished pasta, chop the rest into large chunks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When the pasta is one minute short of being al dente (you still want it to have a good firmness to it), drain it and add it to the beets. Toss to coat the pasta strands and cook for one minute. Remove from the heat and add the smoked salmon, capers, and ½ cup of feta cheese.  Toss gently to distribute everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Serve immediately, garnished with the reserved smoked salmon strips, feta crumbles, and chopped dill or parsley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Serves 2 as a main course, or 4 as a first course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p1616-pink-pasta-fettuccine-with-beet-salmon-feta/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p1616-pink-pasta-fettuccine-with-beet-salmon-feta/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Panasonic please add the LUT name to the EXIF in S9 JPEGs (and other cameras that support LUTs of course)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;So I can keep track of which LUT I used :-) . I doubt they will do this but can’t help to ask. I’ll see if I can file a support request or some such and if I can and do I will post a followup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oh and I hope and trust that somebody else has already asked for this feature :-) I don’t ever claim to be original in my 1000s :-) of ideas!!
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 8, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1010-lumix-s5ii-lut-package/&quot;&gt;ME:: so many free LUTs to try on the S9 and in Pearla and not boring iOS Camera Apps so little time :-) l KROLOP und GERST:: Lumix S5II LUT Package&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p0942-panasonic-lut-names-in-exif-jpegs-s9/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p0942-panasonic-lut-names-in-exif-jpegs-s9/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The more lenses you look at the world with the better. For example: food, languages, books, sports, hobbies, volunteering etc.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Find more lenses every year if you can :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p0038-lenses-food-languages-books-sports-hobbies-volunteering/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/16/p0038-lenses-food-languages-books-sports-hobbies-volunteering/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: use this to access all my computers from anywhere ; Tailscale blog:: The Tailscale node you mail to your parents</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 16, 2025 02:19 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://tailscale.com/blog/exit-node-parents-streaming-support&quot;&gt;ME:: use this to access all my computers from anywhere ; Tailscale blog:: The Tailscale node you mail to your parents&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– gotta do this to access my nodes from anywhere. &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Or the stoop, the package locker, or wherever your friends and family get their packages. Tailscale can run on tiny devices, like a Raspberry Pi or Apple TV, that fit in small boxes. Once plugged in, a pre-loaded Tailscale device can help you troubleshoot devices back home, provide an exit node for VPN purposes, and give you an off-site backup location, among other neat tricks.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/15/p1819-tailscale-exit-node-parents-streaming-support/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/15/p1819-tailscale-exit-node-parents-streaming-support/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: there is no man-boy problem, there is an underpaid and under represented problem for all minorities, not men. Grow up and do your share of the housework and childrearing man-boys :-)  !; Jessica Winter:: What Did Men Do to Deserve This? ¦ The New Yorker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 15, 2025 16:55 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/xfqTN#selection-1777.0-1777.755&quot;&gt;ME:: there is no man-boy problem, there is an underpaid and under represented problem for all minorities, not men. Grow up and do your share of the housework and childrearing man-boys :-)  !; Jessica Winter:: What Did Men Do to Deserve This? ¦ The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/xfqTN#selection-1777.0-1777.755&quot;&gt;Jessica Winter:: What Did Men Do to Deserve This? ¦ The New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The notion that fathers wander away from their families owing to some gnawing sense of existential dislocation—some humiliating certainty of their own uselessness or usurpation—is especially pungent when one takes into account the enormous gender gap in housework and child-rearing in heterosexual marriages. According to the Gender Equity Policy Institute, mothers who work full time do almost twice as much household labor as fathers. Research by the Nobel-winning economist Claudia Goldin has suggested that married men’s disinclination toward housework and other “draggy business of family life” may be holding back birth rates, which should pique the interest of Republican pronatalists such as J. D. Vance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The deeper one sinks into our nation’s alleged man-boy problem and its potential solutions, the more the woman reader may begin to feel something stronger than resentment or intellectual disdain. She may begin to feel a chauvinistic gratitude in her sex. The familiar flatness of feeling a little degraded seems preferable to the anger, entitlement, and alienation that (we are told over and over) gnaws away at so many male specimens. What a gift it is, really, to have no choice in the matter. To have to move out of your parents’ house, to show up for your shift, to change the diaper, not because any of it is gender-affirming but because life is full of tasks that need doing, and you are the person who does them. At least then you know who you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/15/p0855-no-man-boy-problem-growup-do-your-share-housework-childrearing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/15/p0855-no-man-boy-problem-growup-do-your-share-housework-childrearing/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>without-link-blogthis.rb: new ruby script for blog posts that don't reference a link I call this from linkless_blog_all_open.rb.</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;format is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;title followed by blank line followed by rest of the post in markdown format&lt;/code&gt; for example:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start of awesome post in a checkvist list item&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;awesome title

awesome rest of the post. &lt;span class=&quot;gs&quot;&gt;**awesome bold text**&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End of awesome post in a checkvist list item&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-checkvist/blob/main/without-link-blogthis.rb&quot;&gt;without-link-blogthis.rb&lt;/a&gt; autocreates the slug from the first line of a list item in a checkvist list (using the title with stop words removed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-checkvist/blob/main/linkless_blog_all_open.rb&quot;&gt;linkless_blog_all_open.rb&lt;/a&gt; calls without_blogthis.rb to create blog posts in jekyll format from my all open list items in my ‘blog this’ &lt;a href=&quot;https://checkvist.com/checklists/936619&quot;&gt;checkvist list 936619&lt;/a&gt; after you type ‘y’ to approve it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oh and along the way I improved my scripts so you don’t have to explicitly add the creation date. The created date is read from the checkvist api field &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;created_at&lt;/code&gt;. Ruby code:
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;parse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;created_at&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;logger&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;debug&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;created_at: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;ai&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;time_discovered_slug&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;getlocal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;strftime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'%Y-%m-%d-p%H%M'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 28, 2024: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/28/p1718-blog_all_open/&quot;&gt;my ruby script that’s responsible for my flurry of recent blog posts is called blog_all_open.rb.. It calls blogthis.rb to create blog posts in jekyll format with a nice slug from my all open list items in my ‘blog this’ checkvist list 74286 after you type ‘y’ to approve it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/14/p0908-without-link-blogthis-linkless_blog_all_open/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/14/p0908-without-link-blogthis-linkless_blog_all_open/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Revenge of renewables. Despite the USA and Alberta governments (and our former environmentalist PM), renewable i.e. solar and wind is the right side of history</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The global south will lead this.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is where Canada could and should (sorry about the should word :-) ) lead. The future. Renewable, green energy which provides jobs and super large infrastructure projects instead of the same old same old oil and gas projects (I am OK with being honest and saying we need some oil and gas projects for a very limited time and here is our clear and actionable roadmap and plan to get off of oil and gas. Two ideas I can hold in my head simultaneously).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And it goes with saying climate change is the number one issue for all humans! And it’s not a zero sum game in fact it’s win win. More jobs more better clean air, more more more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/13/p0841-revenge-renewables-usa-alberta-government-wrong-side-history/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/13/p0841-revenge-renewables-usa-alberta-government-wrong-side-history/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
