<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:19:01 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:19:01 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: AI stuff to code effectively requires time and $ which many minority folks simply don't have ; Dr Cat Hicks:: New research from me: AI Skill Threat &amp;amp; contest cultures on software teams</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 9, 2025 20:05 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drcathicks.com/post/new-research-from-me-ai-skill-threat-contest-cultures-on-software-teams&quot;&gt;ME:: AI stuff to code effectively requires time and $ which many minority folks simply don’t have ; Dr Cat Hicks:: New research from me: AI Skill Threat &amp;amp; contest cultures on software teams&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;And because of our deep investment in recruiting underrepresented perspectives across all of our projects, we are able to share evidence that there are critically important equity and opportunity gaps emerging across developers' experiences with AI-assisted coding. For example, 56% of Racially Minoritized developers report a negative judgment of the quality of AI outputs in coding work, compared with 28% for all developers, and report higher levels of AI Skill Threat. Women and LGBTQ+ people on software teams are less likely to report upskilling in AI-assisted coding, potentially signaling a lack of resources. It is vital to learn from these groups' insights as well as take action to ensure these gaps do not calcify into new, career-threatening barriers.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/09/p1305-new-research-from-me-ai-skill-threat-contest-cultures-on-software-teams/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/09/p1305-new-research-from-me-ai-skill-threat-contest-cultures-on-software-teams/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fuji Superia, Velvia, Kodak Ektachrome, Gold, Portra, SkyOptiimizer2, SunShadeSharp Luts from falk.wagenknecht- Google Drive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 7, 2025 15:41 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1dcxrhHJqTxhIlgwNGNO6XL5llnVh7r84&quot;&gt;Fuji Superia, Velvia, Kodak Ektachrome, Gold, Portra, SkyOptiimizer2, SunShadeSharp Luts from falk.wagenknecht- Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/LumixLUTs/comments/1kajiq6/big_lut_update_leave_a_like/&quot;&gt;Reddit post 5 months ago on r/LumixLUTs:&lt;/a&gt;: “Big LUT update, leave a like!” &amp;lt;– :) &amp;lt;– looks great, thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/07/p0841-falk-wegenknecht-luts-fuji-kodak-sunshadesharp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/07/p0841-falk-wegenknecht-luts-fuji-kodak-sunshadesharp/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Go Blacksky go!!! I doubt that Blacksky will be under the 'thumb of Bluesky's moderation service' forever (if this is true, I don't know enough about ATProto to know for sure who is under the thumb of who) ; Bruno Dias,:: Delusions of a Protocol ¦ Azhdarchid</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 6, 2025 14:42 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://azhdarchid.com/delusions-of-a-protocol/&quot;&gt;ME:: Go Blacksky go!!! I doubt that Blacksky will be under the “thumb of Bluesky’s moderation service” forever (if this is true, I don’t know enough about ATProto to know for sure who is under the thumb of who) ; Bruno Dias,:: Delusions of a Protocol ¦ Azhdarchid&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;To my knowledge there's only one alternate stack that runs atproto as a complete service, Blacksky. But this isn't a turnkey solution that you can stand up as your own independent alternative; Blacksky at present barely has documentation. And even Blacksky users are still more or less under the thumb of Bluesky's moderation service, if they intend to reach 99% of the network as it exists today.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/06/p0742-delusions-of-a-protocol/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/06/p0742-delusions-of-a-protocol/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME tl-dr-ing; lnav, a TUI tool to to colourize, filter and view multiple log files that works with zero configuration out of the box with standard log files like log files generated by ruby's logger gem ; Tim Stack:: lnav v0.13.1</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 5, 2025 05:08 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.lnav.org/en/v0.13.1/index.html&quot;&gt;ME tl-dr-ing; lnav, a TUI tool to to colourize, filter and view multiple log files that works with zero configuration out of the box with standard log files like log files generated by ruby’s logger gem ; Tim Stack:: lnav v0.13.1&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Nicely colourizes log files generated by the ruby “logger” gem &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The Log File Navigator (lnav) is an advanced log file viewer for the console. If you have a bunch of log files that you need to look through to find issues, lnav is the tool for you.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/04/p2208-lnav-view-colourize-multiple-log-files-including-ruby-logger-gem-logs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/04/p2208-lnav-view-colourize-multiple-log-files-including-ruby-logger-gem-logs/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: Attack the ideas and emotions that make The Convicted Criminal worship appealing ; Dave Rahardja::  It is impossible to reason these people out of their unhinged views, because they have a different epistemological system: they believe in divine revelation through authority figures, not collaborative observation ; Matthew Sheffield:: The Convicted Criminal super fans are impossible to argue with because they don’t actually believe in logic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 3, 2025 03:36 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.patreon.com/posts/trump-super-fans-99819454&quot;&gt;ME:: t;dr-ing: Attack the ideas and emotions that make The Convicted Criminal worship appealing ; Dave Rahardja::  It is impossible to reason these people out of their unhinged views, because they have a different epistemological system: they believe in divine revelation through authority figures, not collaborative observation ; Matthew Sheffield:: The Convicted Criminal super fans are impossible to argue with because they don’t actually believe in logic&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfba.social/@drahardja/115308067418870501&quot;&gt;Dave Rahardja’s toot&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Wanting to help your deluded friend or relative escape from the clutches of traditions that bind their minds, steal their money, and waste their time is a wonderful desire, but you should understand that people who are caught deeply in the clutches of authoritarianism’s embrace have tremendous difficulty escaping. The best way to help them out is to attack the ideas and emotions that make The Convicted Criminal worship appealing. Attacking their belief in the leader himself is ineffective, because submitting to The Convicted Criminal has become part of their very self-concept.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/02/p2036-the-convicted-criminal-super-fans-99819454/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/02/p2036-the-convicted-criminal-super-fans-99819454/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME: tl;dr-ing Stock firmware works (Unlike Rui, I have no need for low-level control) and so does OpenWRT. Something to consider in 2027 or something but by then there will be something shinier :-)  LOL! ; Rui:: The Cudy AX3000 Wi-Fi 6 System (with OpenWRT) - Tao of Mac</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 26, 2025 06:52 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://taoofmac.com/space/reviews/2025/09/14/1630&quot;&gt;ME: tl;dr-ing Stock firmware works (Unlike Rui, I have no need for low-level control) and so does OpenWRT. Something to consider in 2027 or something but by then there will be something shinier :-)  LOL! ; Rui:: The Cudy AX3000 Wi-Fi 6 System (with OpenWRT) - Tao of Mac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Cudy AX3000/M3000 models make for pretty great Airport Extreme replacements, and in this age of networking devices with cloud features nobody asked for OpenWRT turns them into very nice locally managed access points that I will never have to worry about again (until I break the configuration myself, of course).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Although it is much too early to weigh in on hardware reliability (some of the 802.11ac Airport Extremes I was using were manufactured over a decade ago), the price/performance ratio is great, and right now I don’t mind it not being Wi-Fi 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After all, it took almost ten years for the 2.4GHz band to become saturated in my building, and it doesn’t look as if the 5GHz band is going to be massively swamped anytime soon, so I’m expecting something like 3-4 years of hassle-free operation if the hardware holds up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A relevant thing I should point out again is that people who have less need for low-level control might actually be fine with the stock firmware—I did not use it extensively (nor did I try the Cudy app or any of the router/firewall features), but it already exposes a lot more functionality (and seems a lot more flexible) than ISP gear, so I would encourage people to give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/25/p2352-rui-carno-likes-cudy-ax3000-wifi6-router-openwrt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/25/p2352-rui-carno-likes-cudy-ax3000-wifi6-router-openwrt/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: When we write the code to pass the test, it must be failing;  Jason Gorman:: Test Driven Development Under The Microscope #1 – Usage-Driven Design</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 24, 2025 08:45 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://codemanship.wordpress.com/2025/09/24/tdd-under-the-microscope-1-usage-driven-design/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: When we write the code to pass the test, it must be failing;  Jason Gorman:: Test Driven Development Under The Microscope #1 – Usage-Driven Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://codemanship.wordpress.com/2025/09/24/tdd-under-the-microscope-1-usage-driven-design/&quot;&gt;Jason Gorman:: TDD Under The Microscope #1 – Usage-Driven Design – Codemanship’s Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A more flexible and robust way to describe workflow is to imply ordering of events declaratively*. Instead of “Boil the kettle, then pour the water into the teapot”, we might say “When the water is poured into the teapot, it must be at near boiling”. Now all of our edge cases work. We could have boiled it in a pan. We could have boiled it in a microwave. We could have watched the squirrel and then boiled the kettle again. Workflow is implied: the water has been boiled, but we leave ourselves many more routes to pouring it in the teapot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A similar approach can be taken with workflows like TDD; instead of “Run the test to see it fail, then write the simplest code to pass it”, we could say “When we write the code to pass the test, it must be failing”. It’s a subtle but important distinction, and one which I’ve realised I’ve been using for a long time when I observe developers working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/24/p0145-tdd-under-the-microscope-1-usage-driven-design/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/24/p0145-tdd-under-the-microscope-1-usage-driven-design/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Zero to working space invaders code in 1 prompt! From Chinese 'frontier' ai company Z.ai way back :-) 2 months ago to July 29, 2025 ; Simon Willison:: My 2.5 year old laptop can write Space Invaders in JavaScript now, using GLM-4.5 Air and MLX</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 20, 2025 14:56 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/29/space-invaders/&quot;&gt;ME:: Zero to working space invaders code in 1 prompt! From Chinese “frontier” ai company Z.ai way back :-) 2 months ago to July 29, 2025 ; Simon Willison:: My 2.5 year old laptop can write Space Invaders in JavaScript now, using GLM-4.5 Air and MLX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jul/29/space-invaders/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison:: My 2.5 year old laptop can write Space Invaders in JavaScript now, using GLM-4.5 Air and MLX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My 2.5 year old laptop can write Space Invaders in JavaScript now, using GLM-4.5 Air and MLX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I wrote about the new GLM-4.5 model family yesterday—new open weight (MIT licensed) models from Z.ai in China which their benchmarks claim score highly in coding even against models such as Claude Sonnet 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The models are pretty big—the smaller GLM-4.5 Air model is still 106 billion total parameters, which is 205.78GB on Hugging Face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ivan Fioravanti built this 44GB 3bit quantized version for MLX, specifically sized so people with 64GB machines could have a chance of running it. I tried it out… and it works extremely well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I fed it the following prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Write an HTML and JavaScript page implementing space invaders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And it churned away for a while and produced the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Clearly this isn’t a particularly novel example, but I still think it’s noteworthy that a model running on my 2.5 year old laptop (a 64GB MacBook Pro M2) is able to produce code like this—especially code that worked first time with no further edits needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/20/p0756-space-invaders/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/20/p0756-space-invaders/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: oh brother yet another governance error (this time by Ruby Central) screws my favourite programming language Jan Lehnardt :couchdb:: 'What the f*ck is going on with Ruby?.... For the moment we have to consider all gems compromised:' - narrativ.es</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 19, 2025 15:06 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://narrativ.es/@janl/115230600677063843&quot;&gt;ME:: oh brother yet another governance error (this time by Ruby Central) screws my favourite programming language Jan Lehnardt :couchdb:: “What the f*ck is going on with Ruby?…. For the moment we have to consider all gems compromised:” - narrativ.es&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– See Ellenn Dash aka duckinator’s resignation from Ruby Central https://pup-e.com/goodbye-rubygems.pdf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@pierstoval/115231088070271632&quot;&gt;Alex Rock writes&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;How to make sure *existing* gems aren't compromised somehow? ... That's the main point of failure with supply-chain instability in general (and the node.js ecosystem knows a huge lot about it). ... Not only if rubygems dies they can't update stuff, but will they find a reliable mirror that will allow to *keep* the existing gems downloadable without risk?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/19/p0806-ruby-central-compromised-freenode-meets-wordpress/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/19/p0806-ruby-central-compromised-freenode-meets-wordpress/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: We all make sh*tty software as Dave Winer has said so many times! Including Microsoft and Samsung! ; Thom Holwerda:: Dark patterns killed my wife’s Windows 11 installation  –  OSnews via Mike Hoye</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 19, 2025 14:58 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.osnews.com/story/143376/dark-patterns-killed-my-wifes-windows-11-installation/&quot;&gt;ME:: We all make sh*tty software as Dave Winer has said so many times! Including Microsoft and Samsung! ; Thom Holwerda:: Dark patterns killed my wife’s Windows 11 installation  –  OSnews via Mike Hoye&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This tragedy of dark patterns then neatly cascaded into a catastrophic comedy of bugs, where a full root drive apparently corrupts online Microsoft accounts on Windows 11 so hard they become essentially unrecoverable. There were no warnings and no informational popups. Ominous user accounts started to appear on the login screen. Weird suggestions to use corporate-looking security USB keys pop up. Windows wrongfully tells my wife the PIN code and password she enters are incorrect. The suggestion to change the password or PIN code breaks completely. All the well-known rescue options any average user would turn to in WinRE throw up cryptic errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May 4, 2017: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/05/14/p1-we-all-make-shtty-software-including-mcrosoft/&quot;&gt;We all make sh*tty software including M$crosoft part 8888 – www.iuqerfsodp9ifjaposdfjhgosurijfaewrwergwea.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/19/p0758-dark-patterns-killed-my-wifes-windows-11-installation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/19/p0758-dark-patterns-killed-my-wifes-windows-11-installation/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
