<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:57:50 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:57:50 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hepatitis vaccination like all scientifically tested vaccinations saves lives.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just like when people don’t vaccinate for measles and other preventable diseases, people are going to die unnecessarily if they don’t get their hepatitis vaccinations. And that’s on you Convicted Criminal and your cronies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/07/p0756-hepatitis-vaccination-scientifically-tested-vaccinations-saves-lives/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/07/p0756-hepatitis-vaccination-scientifically-tested-vaccinations-saves-lives/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Super hilarious when Canadian bloggers, vloggers, etc recommend products that don't ship to Canada #RealFreeTradeWithEntireWorldNotJustSuperLoopholeFilledUSMCAWithTheUSAAndMexico</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;e.g. The Shifter guy in his YouTube video:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/j01meiJyLeI&quot;&gt;Cycling Gift Guide 2025: Things I Actually Use&lt;/a&gt; recommending the Light Rail light from Intrinsic Cycles. I tried to buy it and LOL they don’t ship to Canada.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This happens all the time. Canada  / USA free trade has always been a sham and scam. #BanMulroneyReaganEtcEtcNeverLikedThemNeverWill :-) #RealFreeTradeWithEntireWorldNotJustSuperLoopholeFilledUSMCAWithTheUSAAndMexico&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Having said all the above, I do like the Shifter guy, Tom Babin, and his videos :-)
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 30, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/30/p0835-light-rail/&quot;&gt;ME:: Be seen plus SEE bicycle Light Rail light from Intrinsic Cycles looks good but how do I install this on my Wald basket (the basket blocks lights mounted on the handlebar)? Not a big deal I guess Wald basket bicyclists are not mainstream yet :-) Light Rail Kit – Intrinsic Cycles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/06/p2043-super-hilarious-canadian-bloggers-vloggers-recommend-products-that-dont-ship-to-canada-usmca-is-a-sham/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/06/p2043-super-hilarious-canadian-bloggers-vloggers-recommend-products-that-dont-ship-to-canada-usmca-is-a-sham/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: All the benefits sound plausible but I still think self driving cars won't work in 2034 and we'd be better improving 'low tech' non self driving trains and buses ; The Economist:: Self-driving cars will transform urban economies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 7, 2025 02:29 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/B6zPd#selection-1359.0-1363.560&quot;&gt;ME:: All the benefits sound plausible but I still think self driving cars won’t work in 2034 and we’d be better improving ‘low tech’ non self driving trains and buses ; The Economist:: Self-driving cars will transform urban economies&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;San Francisco may not yet have seen job losses, but that is likely to change as costs fall. America is home to 1m taxi and bus drivers, as well as over 3m truck drivers—adding up to 3% of the working population. Other potential losers are less obvious. Without car accidents there will, for instance, be less demand for personal-injury lawyers. If people stop buying cars, dealers and used-car salesmen will go. Robotaxis might compete with short-haul air travel and even hotels if some are kitted out with beds. Although new jobs will be created—in, say, managing fleets or manning depots—they will hardly make up for the losses. Social disruption is likely; at the same time, job losses will be an opportunity. Workforces in the rich world are shrinking as populations age. Freeing people to work elsewhere might be invaluable. ... Productivity in the transport industry would surge. The rest of the economy ought to perk up, too. An average working American spends just under an hour commuting each day, against eight hours on the job. Turning even a sliver of that into work could boost output appreciably, says Will Denyer of Gavekal, a research firm. Self-driving cars offer a smoother ride, which, along with better suspension, should make it easier to get work done onboard. And fewer accidents not only mean fewer human tragedies—they also mean lower hospital and rehabilitation bills.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;COUNTERPOINT to me :-) :: &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/&quot;&gt;Jonathan Slotkin neurosurgeon:: NYT: The Data on Self-Driving Cars Is Clear. We Have to Change Course&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Federal leadership is essential. Current regulations require companies to report crashes, but not the number of miles driven or where. We need the denominator, not just the numerator. Data-reporting requirements should include crash rates, miles driven and where, and safety performance. Independent auditors should verify this data against police reports, insurance claims and privacy-protected medical records. ... This transformation will happen. We can guide it toward a safer, more equitable future or let it unfold haphazardly around us. There’s a future in which manual driving becomes uncommon, perhaps even quaint, the way riding horses is today. It’s a future where we no longer accept thousands of deaths and tens of thousands of broken spines as the price of mobility. It’s time to stop treating this like a tech moonshot and start treating it like a public health intervention.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– I still think the full data with the denominator will show it’s not safe and barring a breakthrough it won’t be safe by 2034. Love to be proven wrong :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May 28, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/28/p1444-elon-fsd-2034-still-wont-work-for-tesla-without-lidar-bitter-lessons/&quot;&gt;PROBABLY WRONG PREDICTION:: ME:: By Jan 1, 2034 Tesla still won’t have full self driving cars (unless they add LiDAR and/or humans in the loop :-) !) ; Ben Thompson Oct 15, 2024:: Elon Dreams and Bitter Lessons – Stratechery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/06/p1829-if-self-driving-cars-worked-there-would-be-benefits-selfdriving-wont-work-before-2034-lets-deploy-more-trains-buses-first/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/06/p1829-if-self-driving-cars-worked-there-would-be-benefits-selfdriving-wont-work-before-2034-lets-deploy-more-trains-buses-first/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: go 'Te Hiku, Apertus and other smaller models for preserving small languages' go :-) ! ; Ethan Zuckerman:: Gramsci's Nightmare: AI, Platform Power and the Automation of Cultural Hegemony</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 6, 2025 23:15 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethanzuckerman.com/2025/12/05/gramscis-nightmare-ai-platform-power-and-the-automation-of-cultural-hegemony/&quot;&gt;ME:: go ‘Te Hiku, Apertus and other smaller models for preserving small languages’ go :-) ! ; Ethan Zuckerman:: Gramsci’s Nightmare: AI, Platform Power and the Automation of Cultural Hegemony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ethanzuckerman.com/2025/12/05/gramscis-nightmare-ai-platform-power-and-the-automation-of-cultural-hegemony/&quot;&gt;Ethan Zuckerman:: Gramsci’s Nightmare: AI, Platform Power and the Automation of Cultural Hegemony&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m inspired by a project in New Zealand launched by a cultural organization called Te Hiku Media. The CEO of Te Hiku, Peter-Lucas Jones, is Maori and the organization has worked since 1990 to put voices in te reo Maori, the Maori language, on the radio, ending decades during which the New Zealand government suppressed the teaching and speaking of the language. A few years ago, he asked his husband, Keoni Mahelona, a native Hawaiian and a polymathic scholar and technologist, to help the organization build a website. The two ended up realizing that the three decades of recorded Maori speech in the radio archives represented a cultural heritage that likely existed nowhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That archive of spoken te reo Maori becomes more powerful if it’s indexed, and that requires transcribing many thousands of hours of tape, or building a speech to text model. Mahelona visited with gatherings of Maori elders and explained how machine learning models worked, what a speech to text model might make possible and got buy-in and consent from the broader community. That allowed Te Hiku to recruit a truly amazing number of participants into the project of recording snippets of spoken Maori. Over ten days, 2500 speakers recorded 300 hours of the language, creating 200,000 labeled snippets of speech. Jones and Mahelona relied on a set of cultural institutions to accomplish this – they held a contest between traditional canoe racing teams to see which could record the most phrases. They ended up with training data that powers a language transcription model that is 92% accurate… and they’ve got engaged volunteers who could work to correct transcription errors and add data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This Maori ML project is already being used to power a language learning application, similar to DuoLingo, but using tools built by the community rather than extracted from them. Young Maori speakers are able to check their pronunciation against a database of voices of elders who’ve worked to keep the language alive. And the 30+ years of audio that Te Hiku has collected are now both an indexable archive, but also potentially the corpus for a small LLM built around Maori language, knowledge and values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Te Hiku corpus is probably too small to build a large language model using the techniques we use today, which rely on ready access to massive data sets. But there are projects similar in spirit, notably Apertus, a Swiss project to create an open, multilingual language model that emphasizes the importance of non-English languages, especially Romansh and Swiss German. 40% of Apertus’s model is non-English… which gives you a sense of just how dominant English is in most models… and the goal is to build models for chatbots, translation systems and educational tools that emphasize transparency and diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/06/p1515-gramscis-nightmare-ai-platform-power-and-the-automation-of-cultural-hegemony/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/06/p1515-gramscis-nightmare-ai-platform-power-and-the-automation-of-cultural-hegemony/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl-dr-ing: substage is a macOS app that makes pandoc, ffmpeg, imagemagick, sips, etc usable for normal people via LLMs (using LLMs via OpenRouter and many LLMs) or something :-) Substage: Command line power, natural language ease.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 5, 2025 20:44 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://selkie.design/substage/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl-dr-ing: substage is a macOS app that makes pandoc, ffmpeg, imagemagick, sips, etc usable for normal people via LLMs (using LLMs via OpenRouter and many LLMs) or something :-) Substage: Command line power, natural language ease.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Substage converts natural language prompts into command line commands.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/05/p1244-substage/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/05/p1244-substage/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hey Canadian Facebook people, post news links to your blog and then link to your blog post in FB. Easy peasy stop whingeing :-)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;LOL. Blogs are better according to this grumpy old man part 888888888888 :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/05/p0840-canadian-facebook-people-post-news-links-to-your-blog-then-post-blog-link-to-facebook-stop-whingeing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/05/p0840-canadian-facebook-people-post-news-links-to-your-blog-then-post-blog-link-to-facebook-stop-whingeing/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: part 8888 All software not just games will run on any device. Windows, macOS and linux software will run (or be emulated) on all machines is the future of software ; The Verge:: Steam Machine today, Steam Phones tomorrow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 3, 2025 17:06 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/report/820656/valve-interview-arm-gaming-steamos-pierre-loup-griffais&quot;&gt;ME:: part 8888 All software not just games will run on any device. Windows, macOS and linux software will run (or be emulated) on all machines is the future of software ; The Verge:: Steam Machine today, Steam Phones tomorrow&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;It’s a big deal that Valve is making a game console. But I’m beginning to think the Steam Machine may end up a footnote in gaming history. What if Valve could bring PC games not just to its own living room consoles, but also to the Arm chips that billions of people have in their phones? What if you no longer had to wait for game developers to do the hard work of porting PC games to your phone, Mac, or other Arm hardware, because games built for desktop PCs could just work?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/03/p0906-all-software-will-run-everywhere-valve-arm-gaming-steamos-pierre-loup-griffais/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/03/p0906-all-software-will-run-everywhere-valve-arm-gaming-steamos-pierre-loup-griffais/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Always be coding in 2025 is always be writing specifications for LLMs to code and for you to verify?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;October 16, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/16/p0748-natural-language-as-code/&quot;&gt;ME:: if you can break a problem into a series of sub-problems and write that list of sub-problems you have always been capable of being a software developer. Now more than ever with or without LLMs ; Brandon Dixon:: Febuary 16, 2024:: Can you write? Great, you’re a developer.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/02/p2339-always-be-coding-2025-writing-specifications-llms-code-verify/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/02/p2339-always-be-coding-2025-writing-specifications-llms-code-verify/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: I 100% agree with my friend :-) Alan! Always be Attributing (TASL-Title, Source, Author, Licence(s) all with links if possible) and Always be Linking; Alan Levine:: Tools for Attribution of Open Content – CogDogBlog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 2, 2025 04:32 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://cogdogblog.com/2025/11/tools-for-attribution-of-open-content/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: I 100% agree with my friend :-) Alan! Always be Attributing (TASL-Title, Source, Author, Licence(s) all with links if possible) and Always be Linking; Alan Levine:: Tools for Attribution of Open Content – CogDogBlog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cogdogblog.com/2025/11/tools-for-attribution-of-open-content/&quot;&gt;lan Levine:: Tools for Attribution of Open Content – CogDogBlog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Its essentially all the information needed to create the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wiki.creativecommons.org/wiki/Recommended_practices_for_attribution&quot;&gt;Creative Commons TASL Best Practice form of attribution&lt;/a&gt; Title, Source (with link), Author (with link), Licences (with link).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;see-also&quot;&gt;See also&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alan Levin:: November 30, 2014:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cogdogblog.com/2014/11/always-be-attributing/&quot;&gt;Always be Attributing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/01/p2032-always-be-attributing-tools-for-attribution-of-open-content/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/01/p2032-always-be-attributing-tools-for-attribution-of-open-content/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl-dr-ing: Courtesy of the oppressive Spanish Empire, Filipinos have been in North America since forever :-) Louisana in the mid-18th century is just one example of many! ; Wikipedia:: Saint Malo, Louisiana</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 1, 2025 15:17 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Malo,_Louisiana&quot;&gt;ME:: tl-dr-ing: Courtesy of the oppressive Spanish Empire, Filipinos have been in North America since forever :-) Louisana in the mid-18th century is just one example of many! ; Wikipedia:: Saint Malo, Louisiana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Saint Malo (Spanish: San Maló [samaˈlo]) was a small fishing village that existed along the shore of Lake Borgne in St. Bernard Parish, Louisiana as early as the mid-18th century until it was destroyed by the 1915 New Orleans hurricane.[1] Located along Bayou Saint Malo, about 6 miles (9.7 km) east of the Isleño fishing village of Shell Beach, it was the first permanent settlement of Filipinos and perhaps the first Asian American settlement in the United States.[2][3][4][5]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The exact date of the establishment of Saint Malo is disputed.[6][4] The settlement may have been formed as early as 1763 or 1765 by Filipino deserters and escaped slaves of the Spanish Manila galleon trade.[7][8][9][10] The members of the community were commonly referred to as Manila men, or Manilamen, and later Tagalas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/01/p0717-saint_malo,_louisiana/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/01/p0717-saint_malo,_louisiana/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
