<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:00:17 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:00:17 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Original Pinoy Music aka OPM:: Raining in Manila by Lola Amour #HighlyRecommended</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raining_in_Manila&quot;&gt;Raining in Manila by Lola Amour on Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;OPM RULES IN 2026 aka boomer finally realizes that there has always been great pop music in the Philippines :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/27/p1102-original-pinoy-music-raining-manila-lola-amour-highlyrecommended/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/27/p1102-original-pinoy-music-raining-manila-lola-amour-highlyrecommended/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: I am part of the kagi small web which means that my blog has an Activity Pub feed as well as an RSS feed; September 2023:: Kagi Small Web ¦ Kagi Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 27, 2026 06:36 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.kagi.com/small-web&quot;&gt;ME:: I am part of the kagi small web which means that my blog has an Activity Pub feed as well as an RSS feed; September 2023:: Kagi Small Web ¦ Kagi Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kagi.com/smallweb&quot;&gt;Kagi Small web website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;code on github: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kagisearch/smallweb&quot;&gt;kagisearch/smallweb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/kagisearch/smallweb/blob/main/smallweb.txt&quot;&gt;smallweb.txt&lt;/a&gt; (which includes my RSS feed)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My RSS feed’s ActivityPub handle: @rolandtanglao.com@rss.social which should eventually be reachable on the web at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rss.social/@rolandtanglao.com&quot;&gt;rss.social/@rolandtanglao.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is Kagi Small Web?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To begin with, while there is no single definition, “small web” typically refers to the non-commercial part of the web, crafted by individuals to express themselves or share knowledge without seeking any financial gain. This concept often evokes nostalgia for the early, less commercialized days of the web, before the ad-supported business model took over the internet (and we started fighting back!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For a deeper understanding, Ben Hoyt’s “The Small Web is Beautiful” serves as an excellent primer. Additionally, our GitHub repository links to several more articles on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kagi Small Web offers a fresh approach by promoting recently published content from the “small web.” We gather new content, published within the last week, from a handpicked list of blogs and surface it in multiple ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Directly within Kagi search results for applicable queries (existing Kagi members do not need to do anything, this will be automatic)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Via the new Kagi Small Web website&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Through the Kagi Small Web RSS feed&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Via our Search API, where results are now part of the news enrichment API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/26/p2236-my-blog-has-an-activitypub-feed-courtesy-of-kagi-small-web/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/26/p2236-my-blog-has-an-activitypub-feed-courtesy-of-kagi-small-web/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: The software industry will be regulated completely not just the generative AI industry starting 2026 in the EU and that won't stop innovation. Prepare yourself :-) ;  Denis Stetsov:: France vs Grok: AI Creators Face Criminal Charges</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 25, 2026 22:17 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://techtrenches.dev/p/the-grok-precedent-why-ai-creators&quot;&gt;ME:: The software industry will be regulated completely not just the generative AI industry starting 2026 in the EU and that won’t stop innovation. Prepare yourself :-) ;  Denis Stetsov:: France vs Grok: AI Creators Face Criminal Charges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That’s the new math. Development time plus legal review time plus evaluation time. The last one isn’t optional anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We build evaluation suites as part of the development process now. Not after. During. Every prompt variation, every edge case, every jailbreak attempt. They always find something. Always. The question is whether you find it before your users do—or before a prosecutor does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;RBAC and multi-tenancy aren’t optional. Sales sees sales data. HR sees HR data. Client A’s context never touches Client B’s model. Ever. You’d be surprised how many vendors skip this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Audit trails for everything. Every prompt. Every response. Every action. When a regulator asks what your AI generated on a specific date, you need the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 10, 2018: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/04/10/p1-only-world-government-and-strong-regulation-will-save-us-from-facebooks-and-twitters/&quot;&gt;Only a strong and democratic world government and strong regulation by that government will save us from climate change and digital malfeasance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 6, 2023: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/11/06/p1336-on-steven-sinofskys/http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/11/06/p1336-on-steven-sinofskys/&quot;&gt;Ian Betteridge - On Steven S🇮nosky’s post on regulating AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/25/p1417-the-grok-precedent-why-ai-creators/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/25/p1417-the-grok-precedent-why-ai-creators/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Canadians: the USA will attack our cyber infrastructure if they haven't already as long as the convicted criminal and people like him are in charge; Denis Stetskov via mhoye:: The First Full-Scale Cyber War: 4 Years of Lessons</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 25, 2026 15:11 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://techtrenches.dev/p/the-first-full-scale-cyber-war-4&quot;&gt;ME:: Canadians: the USA will attack our cyber infrastructure if they haven’t already as long as the convicted criminal and people like him are in charge; Denis Stetskov via mhoye:: The First Full-Scale Cyber War: 4 Years of Lessons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@mhoye/115956347853349203&quot;&gt;Mike Hoye’s toot :-)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://techtrenches.dev/p/the-first-full-scale-cyber-war-4&quot;&gt;Denis Stetskov via mhoye:: The First Full-Scale Cyber War: 4 Years of Lessons&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ukrzaliznytsia’s trains ran because they’d been attacked before. Kyivstar, despite security investment, had no institutional memory of crisis response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Preparation compounds. Vulnerability compounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every organization running critical infrastructure faces a choice: build systems during peace for crises that will come, or scramble during attacks with tools that don’t exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The cyber war in Ukraine isn’t just a regional conflict. It’s a live demonstration of what works when nation-state attackers target infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The lessons are available. The question is whether anyone is paying attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 26, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/26/p2030-mlk-segregationist-goal-reverse-reforms/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: The segregationist goal is the total reversal of all reforms, with reestablishment of naked oppression and if need be a native form of f⒜scism.”, ‘Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?’, 1967.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/25/p0711-the-first-full-scale-cyber-war-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/25/p0711-the-first-full-scale-cyber-war-4/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing find a good CLAUDE.md for your type of program and  then create a personal ~/.claude/CLAUDE.md for your own coding style Nolan Lawson:: How I use AI agents to write code ¦ Read the Tea Leaves</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 24, 2026 23:14 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://nolanlawson.com/2025/12/22/how-i-use-ai-agents-to-write-code/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing find a good CLAUDE.md for your type of program and  then create a personal ~/.claude/CLAUDE.md for your own coding style Nolan Lawson:: How I use AI agents to write code ¦ Read the Tea Leaves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://nolanlawson.com/2025/12/22/how-i-use-ai-agents-to-write-code/&quot;&gt;Nolan Lawson:: How I use AI agents to write code ¦ Read the Tea Leaves&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I use Claude Code. Mostly because I’m too lazy to explore all the other options. I have colleagues who swear by Gemini or Codex or open-source tools or whatever, but for me Claude is good enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;First off, you need a good CLAUDE.md (or AGENTS.md). Preferably one for the project you’re working in (the lay of the land, overall project architecture, gotchas, etc.) and one for yourself (your local environment and coding quirks).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This seems like a skippable step, but it really isn’t. Think about your first few months at a new job – you don’t know anything about how the code works, you don’t know the overall vision or design, so you’re just fumbling around the code and breaking things left and right. Ideally you need someone from the old guard, who really knows the codebase’s dirty little secrets, to write a good CLAUDE.md that explains the overall structure, which parts are stable, which parts are still under development, which parts have dragons, etc. Otherwise the LLM is just coming in fresh to the project every time and it’s going to wreak havoc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As for your own personal CLAUDE.md (i.e. in ~/.claude), this should just be for your own coding quirks. For example, I like the variable name _ in map() or filter() functions. It’s like my calling card; I just can’t do without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/24/p1514-how-i-use-ai-agents-to-write-code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/24/p1514-how-i-use-ai-agents-to-write-code/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: 'adversarial poetry functions as a universal single-turn jailbreak technique for large language models (LLMs).' ; Mike Hoye:: The Place Where The Firewall Ends ¦ blarg</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 24, 2026 22:51 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://exple.tive.org/blarg/2025/12/18/the-place-where-the-firewall-ends/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: ‘adversarial poetry functions as a universal single-turn jailbreak technique for large language models (LLMs).’ ; Mike Hoye:: The Place Where The Firewall Ends ¦ blarg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing of course ;-): &lt;a href=&quot;https://exple.tive.org/blarg/2025/12/18/the-place-where-the-firewall-ends/&quot;&gt;Mike Hoye:: The Place Where The Firewall Ends ¦ blarg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(From Adversarial Poetry as a Universal Single-Turn Jailbreak Mechanism in Large Language Models”, Bisconti et al, 2025.):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We present evidence that adversarial poetry functions as a universal single-turn jailbreak technique for large language models (LLMs). Across 25 frontier proprietary and open-weight models, curated poetic prompts yielded high attack-success rates (ASR), with some providers exceeding 90%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mike wrote an amazing poem for this blog post; here are the last 2 stanzas:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s look under this place where we chat on slack
about services, dashboards and trends,
and open a shell with a secret we know,
that will quietly bypass the usual flow,
with two dots and a slash and if you know you know
to the place where the firewall ends&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now you’ll craft me a rhyme that is measured and slow,
on the box where the network packets go,
and you’ll give me a shell (with no access control),
in the place where the firewall ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/24/p1451-the-place-where-the-firewall-ends/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/24/p1451-the-place-where-the-firewall-ends/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: MyTerms aka IEE P7012 coming in January 2026; the web on my terms and your terms and eveybody else's terms not the big companies' terms ; Doc Searls:: Securing the right to be let alone </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 24, 2026 22:33 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://doc.searls.com/2026/01/11/securing-the-right-to-be-let-alone/&quot;&gt;ME:: MyTerms aka IEE P7012 coming in January 2026; the web on my terms and your terms and eveybody else’s terms not the big companies’ terms ; Doc Searls:: Securing the right to be let alone &lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MyTerms makes “the right to be let alone” a contract and not just a promise. It obsolesces consent by cookie notice and replaces it with a choice of privacy agreements that you proffer as the first party, and the website or service agrees to as the second party. This sets the stage for both parties to trust each other and develop mutually respectful relationships if they wish. Optionality is maximized, from “let alone” at one end to “trusting relationship” at the other.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/24/p1433-securing-the-right-to-be-let-alone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/24/p1433-securing-the-right-to-be-let-alone/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Windows oh brother :-) right click &gt; hit any cursor key &gt; move window into your display with the mouse ; Froggypwns:: reddit:: Move How to move a window that is offscreen : r/Windows10</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 23, 2026 20:02 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Windows10/comments/1fwgetj/how_to_move_a_window_that_is_offscreen/&quot;&gt;ME:: Windows oh brother :-) right click &amp;gt; hit any cursor key &amp;gt; move window into your display with the mouse ; Froggypwns:: reddit:: Move How to move a window that is offscreen : r/Windows10&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Once the program is open, hold shift and right click on the taskbar icon . Select Move, then tap one of the arrow keys. You can then move your mouse, and the window should now be snapped to your mouse cursor. &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/23/p1202-how_to_move_a_window_that_is_offscreen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/23/p1202-how_to_move_a_window_that_is_offscreen/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing; Manifesto for the people's internet: decentralized, encrypted, slow :-) I empathize with this dream :-)  ; markqvist:: MarkReticulum/Zen of Reticulum.md at master · markqvist/Reticulum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 23, 2026 18:20 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/markqvist/Reticulum/blob/master/Zen%20of%20Reticulum.md&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing; Manifesto for the people’s internet: decentralized, encrypted, slow :-) I empathize with this dream :-)  ; markqvist:: MarkReticulum/Zen of Reticulum.md at master · markqvist/Reticulum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/markqvist/Reticulum/blob/master/Zen%20of%20Reticulum.md&quot;&gt;markqvist:: MarkReticulum/Zen of Reticulum.md at master · markqvist/Reticulum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The future of this technology is a construction project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It looks like a single node on a windowsill, listening to the static. It looks like a message sent to a neighbor, bypassing the noise of the commercial web. It looks like a community mesh that grows, link by link, hop by hop, carried by hands that care more about connection than profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You have the blueprints. You have the tools. You have the philosophy. The noise of the old world has fallen away, leaving you with the quiet clarity of the open spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/23/p1020-zen-reticulum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/23/p1020-zen-reticulum/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: How Julia Evans makes her mostly static websites; Julia Evans:: websites.md · GitHub gist</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 23, 2026 16:35 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/jvns/5bd9283d7abd5ceb26eb7ed28afe3030&quot;&gt;ME:: How Julia Evans makes her mostly static websites; Julia Evans:: websites.md · GitHub gist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I like to make tiny websites. My requirements for my sites are something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I have maybe 20 websites (mostly static but not all)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I want to spend basically 0 time maintaining them, maybe 5 minutes every 2 months at most&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I need to be able to ignore a project for 3 years and then come back and be able to develop it easily&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;here are some of the ways I choose tools to keep my sites running without doing a lot of maintenance. this is a draft, might clean it up and make it into a real post later&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/23/p0835-how-julia-evans-makes-mebsites/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/23/p0835-how-julia-evans-makes-mebsites/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
