<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 18:12:44 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 18:12:44 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>BinderHub to run federated Jupyter notebooks in the cloud?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The problem with interactive notebooks that have R or python or other computer software code is that you have nowhere to execute since it won&amp;#39;t execute in a browser (at least not YET :-), c&amp;#39;mon just translate R to javascript easy peasy :-)!). Binder hub solves this problem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juicy quotes from &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ouseful.info/2017/12/01/my-emerging-workflow-for-working-with-binderhub/&quot;&gt;Note On My Emerging Workflow for Working With Binderhub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

For anyone not familiar with Binder / MyBinder, it’s a service that will launch a fully running Jupyter notebook server and computing environment based the contents of a Github repository (config files as well as notebooks).  What this means is that if you put your Jupyter notebooks into a Github repository, along with one or two simple files that least any Linux or Python packages you need to install in order to run the code in the notebooks (or R packages and perhaps Rmd files if you also install an R kernel/RStudio), you can get a browser access to that running environment at just the click of a link. And the generosity of whoever is paying for the servers the notebook server runs on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

....&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

    We would love to see others deploy their own BinderHub servers, either for their own communities, or as part of a federated public service of BinderHubs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

I’d love to see the OU get behind this, either directly or under the banner of OpenLearn, as part of an effort to help make Jupyter powered interactive open educational materials available without the need to install any software


&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ENDQUOTE
* &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ouseful.info/2017/12/01/my-emerging-workflow-for-working-with-binderhub/&quot;&gt;Read the whole thing!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/12/04/p1-binderhub-to-run-federated-notebooks-in-the-cloud/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/12/04/p1-binderhub-to-run-federated-notebooks-in-the-cloud/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Karoo #iWantToBelieve But You are Based on Android 6.0 which was introduced in October 2015 which means monthly security updates will cease on October 2019 or earlier so if I buy a Karoo in late 2017 I can only use it for a year or two until it's vulnerable forever right? What am I missing?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hammerhead.io/karoo-vs-smartphone-98b5fe89d30b&quot;&gt;Karoo&lt;/a&gt; #iWantToBelieve But You are Based on Android 6.0 which was introduced in October 2015 which means monthly security updates will cease on October 2019 (&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/05/27/p1-going-to-have-to-disagree-with-the-wirecutter-about-android-buy-every-2-years/&quot;&gt;since Android OS updates only happen for 2-4 years from launch of that OS version&lt;/a&gt;) or earlier so if I buy a Karoo in late 2017 I can only use it for a year or two until it&amp;#39;s vulnerable forever right? What am I missing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/12/03/p1-karoo-i-want-to-believe-but-i-also-dont-want-to-buy-a-new-bike-computer-every-2-4-years/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/12/03/p1-karoo-i-want-to-believe-but-i-also-dont-want-to-buy-a-new-bike-computer-every-2-4-years/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>David Robinson: DataCamp course: Introduction to the R package: Tidyverse</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On November 9, 2017 David Robinson wrote: &lt;a href=&quot;http://varianceexplained.org/r/intro-tidyverse/&quot;&gt;Announcing &amp;quot;Introduction to the Tidyverse&amp;quot;, my new DataCamp course&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks great but at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datacamp.com/pricing&quot;&gt;$29/month or $13/year i.e. pay $156 every twelve months for unlimited access&lt;/a&gt; it looks pricey for me :-) #ymmv&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For me paying $20 or $30 on a course I will never finish isn&amp;#39;t worthwhile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because I can never find the time to finish an online course, I prefer books or ebooks and for the tidyverse there are lots of great ones luckily:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/08/06/p1-modern-dive-really-is-a-modern-introduction-to-r/&quot;&gt;Modern Dive - An Introduction to Statistical and Data Sciences via R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/01/24/p1-reading-hadley-wickhams-r-data-science-book/&quot;&gt;R for Data Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/12/02/p1-david-robinson-introduction-to-the-tidyverse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/12/02/p1-david-robinson-introduction-to-the-tidyverse/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Feverbee's analysis of the Apple community</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.feverbee.com/apple-community/&quot;&gt;Feverbee&amp;#39;s analysis of the Apple community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not sure why they use Jive but it seems to do the job. And the gamification seems to be from Jive; it seems too complicated to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting an accepted answer is hard for Apple and most communities on the internet! I guess it&amp;#39;s hard to get folks to mark a reply as an accepted answer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

Apple has had an online community ecosystem since the earliest days of the internet.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The current incarnation of the official community was launched in 2006, revamped in 2011, and has been gradually tweaked and upgraded since then to the site we see today (hosted on Jive).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The community is designed as a customer support channel. The primary goal is most likely to deflect customer support tickets (and calls) and provide a superior level of customer service customers can get through other channels.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

The community also provides a less noticeable area for user tips. Members above a certain level can share their best advice to use products more effectively. This can have an impact upon customer satisfaction and retention.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

...&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Apple suffers greatly from not being able to get an accepted answer to most of the questions which appear in the community. This is the single biggest flaw the community faces today. Most of the online communities we looked at, the number of solved questions was extremely low. These were questions asked days, if not weeks ago. This discourages future people from responding. Questions with solutions should be featured near the top along with any trending or ever-present questions.

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/12/01/p1-feverbee-apple-community-assessment/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/12/01/p1-feverbee-apple-community-assessment/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simon Willison - Datasette: instantly create and publish a read-only API for your SQLite databases</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2017/Nov/13/datasette/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison&amp;#39;s - Datasette: instantly create and publish a read-only API for your SQLite databases&lt;/a&gt; looks fabulous. Perfect for instagram and flickr historical data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I hate SQL because I&amp;#39;m crazy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But hey what a great way to make your data available in the cloud with docker and any dataset that you want to make available to the entire world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/30/p1-simon-willison-Datasette-instantly-create-publish-API-SQLite-databases/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/30/p1-simon-willison-Datasette-instantly-create-publish-API-SQLite-databases/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Used ruby watir gem instead of capybara maybe try capybara next time?</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For my &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/22/p1-add-command-line-parameters-london-drugs-photo-downloading-scraping-script/&quot;&gt;London Drugs Scraping photo downloads script&lt;/a&gt;, I used the ruby watir gem instead of &lt;a href=&quot;http://teamcapybara.github.io/capybara/&quot;&gt;capybara&lt;/a&gt; because I couldn&amp;#39;t get capybara to work?!?!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tutorials.jumpstartlab.com/topics/scraping-with-capybara.html&quot;&gt;nice capybara tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, I need to try capybara next time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally here are some capybara versus watir posts: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/watir/watir/issues/444&quot;&gt;github watir issue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://watirmelon.com/2011/12/03/a-tale-of-three-ruby-automated-testing-apis-redux/&quot;&gt;A tale of three ruby automated testing APIs (redux)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/29/p1-i-used-ruby-watir-to-drive-selenium-capybara-next-time/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/29/p1-i-used-ruby-watir-to-drive-selenium-capybara-next-time/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Narrate all your work including your software work with Mathematica and Jupyter notebooks aka 'computational essays'</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I agree with &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ouseful.info/2017/11/15/programming-meh-lets-teach-how-to-write-computational-essays-instead/&quot;&gt;Programming, meh… Let’s Teach How to Write Computational Essays Instead&lt;/a&gt; that we should narrate all of our work including software work with online notebooks. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And if that&amp;#39;s software work or the work includes software then we should use something like Mathematica and Jupyter notebooks that are great at documenting text, computer software code and output from that code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.ouseful.info/2017/11/15/programming-meh-lets-teach-how-to-write-computational-essays-instead/&quot;&gt;Read the whole thing but here&amp;#39;s a relevant quote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
hen we originally drafted the OU/FutureLearn course Learn to Code for Data Analysis (also available on OpenLearn), we wrote the explanatory text – delivered as HTML but including static code fragments and code outputs – as a notebook, and then ‘ran” the notebook to generate static HTML (or markdown) that provided the static course content. These notebooks were complemented by actual notebooks that students could work with interactively themselves.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Actually, we prototyped authoring both the static text, and the elements to be used in the student notebooks, in a single document, from which the static HTML and “live” notebook documents could be generated: Authoring Multiple Docs from a Single IPython Notebook. )&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst the notion of the computational essay as a form is really powerful, I think the added distinction between between generative and generated documents is also useful. For example, a raw Rmd document of Jupyter notebook is a generative document that can be used to create a document containing text, code, and the output generated from executing the code. A generated document is an HTML, Word, or PDF export from an executed generative document.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the generating code can be omitted from the generated output document, leaving just the text and code generated outputs. Code cells can also be collapsed so the code itself is hidden from view but still available for inspection at any time:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/28/p1-narrate-your-work-including-your-software-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/28/p1-narrate-your-work-including-your-software-work/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Run Firefox with Selenium Web Extensions and how to develop a simple Firefox WebExtension</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have been saying since forever that I should write a Firefox WebExtension!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And this post makes it sound easy :-) !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://intoli.com/blog/firefox-extensions-with-selenium/&quot;&gt;Using Firefox WebExtensions with Selenium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

In this article, I’ll walk through the process of hacking support for Firefox WebExtensions into the Selenium Python client’s FirefoxProfile class. I’ve also put my money where my mouth is and submitted these changes as a pull request on the Selenium repository. This means that hopefully the workaround described in this article will eventually not be necessary. I’ll be sure to update this once that’s the case.

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/27/p1-how-create-a-simple-firefox-webextension-that-works-with-selenium/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/27/p1-how-create-a-simple-firefox-webextension-that-works-with-selenium/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An App to automatically commit this blog to git and upload to github</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dave had a great idea: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2017/11/26.html#a141824&quot;&gt;an app to automatically commit this blog to git and upload to github daily&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we had a github post commit hook that ran jekyll  in the cloud and then uploaded to surge.sh again in the cloud perhaps using heroku we&amp;#39;d then wouldn&amp;#39;t need a computer with jekyll and ruby installed, just a phone or anything that runs a web browser so we could update this blog from everywhere! I&amp;#39;ve tried heroku in the past but I&amp;#39;ve found it clunky and I don&amp;#39;t trust their free plan to stick around forever! (and as always I need to re-try heroku again, maybe it&amp;#39;s less clunky now?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/26/p1-an-app-to-automatically-upload-this-blog-to-github/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/26/p1-an-app-to-automatically-upload-this-blog-to-github/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SUMO aka support.mozilla.org Kitsune search api</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kitsune.readthedocs.io/en/latest/api.html&quot;&gt;Unofficial Search API for support.mozilla.org&amp;#39;s Kitsune platform&lt;/a&gt;   that may go away at any day :-) to search for the word videos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;curl &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/api/2/search/suggest/&quot;&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-H&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Content-Type: application/json&quot;&lt;/span&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-d&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'
{
   &quot;q&quot;: &quot;videos&quot;,
   &quot;max_documents&quot;: 3,
   &quot;max_questions&quot;: 0
}'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;response from server is:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-&quot; data-lang=&quot;&quot;&gt;HTTP/1.1 200 OK
Server: Apache
X-Backend-Server: support4.webapp.phx1.mozilla.com
Vary: X-Mobile,User-Agent
Cache-Control: no-cache, must-revalidate
Content-Type: application/json
Strict-Transport-Security: max-age=31536000
Public-Key-Pins: max-age=1296000; pin-sha256=&quot;r/mIkG3eEpVdm+u/ko/cwxzOMo1bk4TyHIlByibiA5E=&quot;; pin-sha256=&quot;WoiWRyIOVNa9ihaBciRSC7XHjliYS9VwUGOIud4PB18=&quot;;
Date: Wed, 22 Nov 2017 23:07:54 GMT
Expires: Thu, 19 Nov 1981 08:52:00 GMT
X-XSS-Protection: 1; mode=block
Pragma: no-cache
Transfer-Encoding: chunked
X-Content-Type-Options: nosniff
X-Robots-Tag: noodp
Set-Cookie: multidb_pin_writes=y; expires=Wed, 22-Nov-2017 23:08:09 GMT; httponly; Max-Age=15; Path=/
Allow: POST, OPTIONS, GET
X-Frame-Options: DENY
X-Cache-Info: not cacheable; request wasn't a GET or HEAD

{&quot;documents&quot;:[{&quot;id&quot;:15114,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;Download music, photos and videos&quot;,&quot;slug&quot;:&quot;download-music-photos-and-videos&quot;,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;/en-US/
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;etc&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/25/p1-sumo-kitsune-search-api/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/11/25/p1-sumo-kitsune-search-api/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
