<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 22:59:39 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 22:59:39 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: The legal structures have in practise proved to be neither structures nor law. ... Legislation that is evaded, substantially nullified and unenforced is a mockery of the law. 'Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?', 1967.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drmartinlutherkingjr.com/drking/mlk-quotes/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: The legal structures have in practise proved to be neither structures nor law. … Legislation that is evaded, substantially nullified and unenforced is a mockery of the law. &amp;lt;- “Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?”, 1967.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Read the book –&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Where_Do_We_Go_from_Here:_Chaos_or_Community&quot;&gt;‘Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?’, 1967, wiki page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 20, 2025 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/20/p0713-mlk-quotes/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: Darkness cannot drive out darkness; only light can do that. Hate cannot drive out hate; only love can do that.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/22/p2300-mlk-law-not-law/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/22/p2300-mlk-law-not-law/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: Wh⒤tes, it must frankly be said, are not putting in a similar mass effort to reeducate themselves out of their their sense of superiority that the wh⒤te people of America believe they so little to learn &lt;- 'Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?', 1967.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 21, 2025 08:04 &lt;a href=&quot;https://devdilettante.com/@roland/113866922877235152&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: Wh⒤tes, it must frankly be said, are not putting in a similar mass effort to reeducate themselves out of their their sense of superiority that the wh⒤te people of America believe they so little to learn &amp;lt;- “Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?”, 1967.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Read the book –&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Where_Do_We_Go_from_Here:_Chaos_or_Community&quot;&gt;‘Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?’, 1967, wiki page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 20, 2025 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/20/p0713-mlk-quotes/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: Darkness cannot drive out darkness; only light can do that. Hate cannot drive out hate; only love can do that.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/21/p0804-mlk-reeducate-yourself-out-your-sense-superiority/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/21/p0804-mlk-reeducate-yourself-out-your-sense-superiority/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recipes that work:: I used Barb's home made chili oil instead of chili crisp and it was also good! tl;dr Marinate cut up chicken in 6 Tbsp Chii Oil, 1 Tbsp honey , 1Tbsp Mirin  and then 30 min at 400 Robin Miller:: Honey-Chili Crisp Chicken</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 20, 2025 18:56 &lt;a href=&quot;https://robinmillercooks.com/pasta/f/honey-chili-crisp-chicken&quot;&gt;Recipes that work:: I used Barb’s home made chili oil instead of chili crisp and it was also good! tl;dr Marinate cut up chicken in 6 Tbsp Chii Oil, 1 Tbsp honey , 1Tbsp Mirin  and then 30 min at 400 Robin Miller:: Honey-Chili Crisp Chicken&lt;/a&gt; –&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The commingling of spicy chili crisp with honey creates the most incredible glaze for this chicken! This gorgeous sheet pan meal features moist chicken thighs that are spicy, nutty, and subtly sweet. And the dish is made with 4 ingredients and ready in about 30 minutes! &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/20/p1856-honey-chili-crisp-chicken/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/20/p1856-honey-chili-crisp-chicken/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: Darkness cannot drive out darkness; only light can do that. Hate cannot drive out hate; only love can do that.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drmartinlutherkingjr.com/drking/mlk-quotes/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: Darkness cannot drive out darkness; only light can do that. Hate cannot drive out hate; only love can do that.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 28, 2017: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/01/28/p1-americans-friends-other-than-donating-to-the-aclu-what-else/&quot;&gt;Other than donating to the ACLU monthly, what can Canadians do?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/20/p0713-mlk-quotes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/20/p0713-mlk-quotes/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things that work:: I've been using RNI Films iOS app for at least 6 years for black and white conversion of iPhone, Android and 'real camera' photos! Love the Tri X High Contrast Filter! RNI Films: Photo &amp;amp; RAW Editor on the App&amp;nbsp;Store</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 18, 2025 21:00 &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/rni-films-photo-raw-editor/id1017098672&quot;&gt;Things that work:: I’ve been using RNI Films iOS app for at least 6 years for black and white conversion of iPhone, Android and ‘real camera’ photos! Love the Tri X High Contrast Filter! RNI Films: Photo &amp;amp; RAW Editor on the App Store&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– if you love high contrast black and white and have an iPhone or iPad this app is for you. I wish there was a version of this app for Android!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/18/p2100-rnifilms-highly-recommended-ios-only/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/18/p2100-rnifilms-highly-recommended-ios-only/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Komoot doesn't know about the Dunsmuir viaduct bicycling path instead it directs me to use the Central Valley Greenway which is better than Google Maps but not optimal Bike ride from Revolver to St. Joseph’s | Komoot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 17, 2025 18:21  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.komoot.com/tour/2018367957&quot;&gt;Me:: Komoot doesn’t know about the Dunsmuir viaduct bicycling path instead it directs me to use the Central Valley Greenway which is better than Google Maps but not optimal Bike ride from Revolver to St. Joseph’s ¦ Komoot&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– oh well. The path it chose isn’t a bad one, it’s just obviously in need of Vancouver data or something :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 11, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/11/p1746-13319298712-google-maps-error-nanaimo-victoria-instead-lakewood/&quot;&gt;I am really going to have to try another app for bicycle route finding. Not impressed by Google Maps and Transit app. Google Maps once more steers me wrong (recommended Nanaimo and Victoria instead of Lakewood - Strava:: Zum Pho Dundas :-)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/17/p1821-2018367957-komoot-nonoptimal-central-valley-greenway-route/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/17/p1821-2018367957-komoot-nonoptimal-central-valley-greenway-route/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: use flexoki's high contrast colour scheme for future data visualizations?!? Flexoki — Steph Ango</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 16, 2025 07:05 &lt;a href=&quot;https://stephango.com/flexoki&quot;&gt;Me:: use flexoki’s high contrast colour scheme for future data visualizations?!? Flexoki — Steph Ango&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– QUOTE: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Flexoki is minimalistic and high-contrast. The colors are calibrated for legibility and perceptual balance across devices and when switching between light and dark modes.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/16/p0705-flexoki/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/16/p0705-flexoki/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Everybody is 'technical' in one or more domains and provides 'value' (value and productivity are bogus concepts since they are so arbitrary) and can learn more domains Sasha Laundy:: 'Technical' skills</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 15, 2025 09:09 &lt;a href=&quot;https://sashalaundy.com/writing/technical-skills/&quot;&gt;Me:: Everybody is ‘technical’ in one or more domains and provids ‘value’ (value and productivity are bogus concepts since they are so arbitrary) and can learn more domains Sasha Laundy:: “Technical” skills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://sashalaundy.com/writing/technical-skills/&quot;&gt;Sasha Laundy:: “Technical” skills&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m going to define “technical” skills and then make the case that they’re everywhere and severely underrated. Handwaving over them allows us to dismiss the work of wide swaths of the population. And noticing them will light up your life and unlock new worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;….&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My point is: sewing is very technical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And we can ONLY write sewing off as “just arts and crafts” and unimpressive compared to the Maker movement if we choose to ignore that sewing is very technical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Likewise, we can ONLY write off marketing, sales, management, design, product, HR, etc etc etc etc as less important because “they’re not technical” if we choose to ignore that they are very technical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This distinction isn’t just about semantics. It’s also about value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Erasing technical skills lets you erase value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 21, 2024 &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2024/04/21/p1-hazel-weakly-humans-wired-to-be-productive-by-sharing-growing-loving/&quot;&gt;The Trap of Soulless Productivity: Hazel Weakly: instead humans are wired to be productive by sharing, loving, growing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/15/p0909-technical-skills/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/15/p0909-technical-skills/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: it's family background and luck more than 'meritocracy'. The authors' proposed 'moderated causal model' makes sense Ian R. Hadden, Céline Darnon, Lewis Doyle, Matthew J., Sébastien Goudeau, Andrei Cimpian :: Why the belief in meritocracy is so pervasive - ScienceDirect</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 14, 2025 19:14 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1364661324003292&quot;&gt;Me:: it’s family background and luck more than ‘meritocracy’. The authors’ proposed ‘moderated causal model’ makes sense Ian R. Hadden, Céline Darnon, Lewis Doyle, Matthew J., Sébastien Goudeau, Andrei Cimpian :: Why the belief in meritocracy is so pervasive - ScienceDirect&lt;/a&gt; via grimalkina’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@grimalkina/113827451914611149&quot;&gt;toot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1364661324003292&quot;&gt;Ian R. Hadden, Céline Darnon, Lewis Doyle, Matthew J., Sébastien Goudeau, Andrei Cimpian : Why the belief in meritocracy is so pervasive - ScienceDirect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘You can make it if you try.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is the rallying cry of meritocracy: that hard work – not luck or family background – determines success in life. The appeal of this idea runs deep [1]. Although people recognize, to varying degrees across countries [2], that factors other than hard work matter, they typically fail to grasp the true extent of their influence. For example, people underestimate the levels of inequalities in wealth [1] and overestimate the extent to which people move between economic strata through their own efforts [3].
This ‘myth of meritocracy’ is far from cost-free: it contributes to the acceptance and legitimation of historical inequalities between demographic groups. For example, when people believe they live in a meritocratic society, they are less likely to support policies that reduce income inequality [4] and more likely to allocate resources to individuals who already have the most [5].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Instead, a more promising avenue is to invoke a more nuanced and more accurate moderated causal model, wherein the dose–response relation between effort and success is calibrated by external factors (Figure 1C). This conveys the reality that the same amount of effort yields greater dividends for people in more favorable social circumstances (e.g., better-resourced schools, better-connected families). Just as a seed planted in fertile soil will fare quite differently from an identical one planted in a desert, the same ‘dose’ of effort does not take everyone equally far. This moderated causal model, with its balance of accuracy and intuitive appeal, is likely to be a valuable communication device in efforts to debunk the myth of meritocracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 30, 2024 &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/30/p0030-yes-americans-are-much-richer-than/&quot;&gt;Me:: file this under d⭕minant hegemony gotta d⭕minant hegemony :-) Yes, 🇦mericans are much richer when it comes to stuff than Japanese people (according to rich 🇦mericans like N⭕ah Sm🇮th LOL), easy for N⭕ah to say from his position of privilege, stuff and the ability to ‘innovate’ is priority 1. Doesn’t health, safety and quality of life and less inequality for all matter to entitled, wealthy 🇦mericans :-) ? Evidently not ?!?!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/14/p1914-s1364661324003292-why-belief-meritocracy-pervasive/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/14/p1914-s1364661324003292-why-belief-meritocracy-pervasive/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: The entshᜁttification rot is everywhere because software is everywhere! Ed Zitron:: Never Forgive Them</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 13, 2025 11:27  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wheresyoured.at/never-forgive-them/&quot;&gt;Me:: The entshᜁttification rot is everywhere because software is everywhere! Ed Zitron:: Never Forgive Them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wheresyoured.at/never-forgive-them/&quot;&gt;Ed Zitron:: Never Forgive Them&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be clear, I don’t believe that this gradual enshᜁttification is part of some grand, Machiavellian long game by the tech companies, but rather the product of multiple consecutive decisions made in response to short-term financial needs. Even if it was, the result would be the same — people wouldn’t notice how bad things have gotten until it’s too late, or they might just assume that tech has always sucked, or they’re just personally incapable of using the tools that are increasingly fundamental to living in a modern world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You are the victim of a con — one so pernicious that you’ve likely tuned it out despite the fact it’s part of almost every part of your life. It hurts everybody you know in different ways, and it hurts people more based on their socioeconomic status. It pokes and prods and twists millions of little parts of your life, and it’s everywhere, so you have to ignore it, because complaining about it feels futile, like complaining about the weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It isn’t. You’re battered by the Rot Economy, and a tech industry that has become so obsessed with growth that you, the paying customer, are a nuisance to be mitigated far more than a participant in an exchange of value. A death cult has taken over the markets, using software as a mechanism to extract value at scale in the pursuit of growth at the cost of user happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These people want everything from you — to control every moment you spend working with them so that you may provide them with more ways to make money, even if doing so doesn’t involve you getting anything else in return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;July 12, 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/12/p1-the-whole-miasma-of-the-internet/&quot;&gt;The whole miasma of the internet has blocked me from blogging but not for long :-)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/13/p1127-never-forgive-them/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/13/p1127-never-forgive-them/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
