<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:25:44 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:25:44 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Lumos Nyxel Helmet USB-C broke, aargh! Glue issue? Weird because my Lumos Ultra's USB-C port has lasted 5 years!</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lumoshelmet/lumos-nyxel-the-safest-and-smartest-urban-bike-and-e-bike-helmet&quot;&gt;Lumos Nyxel Kickstarter from 2024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/lumoshelmet/lumos-ultra-the-new-standard-in-bike-helmets/description&quot;&gt;Lumos Ultra Kickstarter from 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/25/p2211-lumos-nyxel-helmet-usb-c-broke-glue-issue-perhaps-ultra-usbc-port-lasted-5-years/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/25/p2211-lumos-nyxel-helmet-usb-c-broke-glue-issue-perhaps-ultra-usbc-port-lasted-5-years/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Filipino bread is actually awesome. Read Panaderia: Philippine Bread, Biscuit and Bakery Traditions by Jenny Orillos and Amy Uy to learn the full breadth and depth of it.</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s just that people (the diaspora and the ones living in the Philippines)  don’t actually know beyond the common place and the cliché. Perhaps because it takes a lot of time and it’s expensive to to check it out in the USA and Canada (and in the Philippines).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s way more to Filipino baking than just ensaymada, hopia, pan de sal etc etc. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://panaderiaph.wordpress.com/panaderia-book/&quot;&gt;Panaderia: Philippine Bread, Biscuit and Bakery Traditions by Jenny Orillos and Amy Uy&lt;/a&gt; (https://www.facebook.com/panaderiaph/) to learn all about it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s not all overly sweet or bland. It’s that :-) and everything marvelously in between.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jenny Orillos:: 2021:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gridmagazine.ph/story/the-path-of-pan-de-sal&quot;&gt;The Path Of Pan de Sal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jenny Orillos:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yummy.ph/lessons/baking/ensaymada-how-to-bake-a1523-20161213-lfrm&quot;&gt;The Story of Ensaymada&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amy Uy:: 2019:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.philstar.com/lifestyle/food-and-leisure/2019/10/17/1960714/after-100-years-pan-de-sal-panaderia-dimas-alang-stands-strong&quot;&gt;After 100 years of pan de sal, Panaderia Dimas-Alang stands strong&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/24/p0024-filipino-bread-is-awesome-read-panaderia-philippine-biscuit-bakery-traditions-orillos-uy-for-details/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/24/p0024-filipino-bread-is-awesome-read-panaderia-philippine-biscuit-bakery-traditions-orillos-uy-for-details/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 cars with their daytime running lights off Sunday November 23, 2025 during my 40 minute bicycle ride</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;LOL. Not old cars either and not super old vans for tradespeople. Follow the law car driving people :-) !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 17, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/17/p2209-apeman-seeker-rear-view-real-time-video-camera-illegally-driving-daytime-running-lights-off-vancouver/&quot;&gt;My Apeman R1 Seeker rear view real-time video camera shows lots people illegally driving with their daytime running lights OFF behind me in the city of Vancouver.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/23/p1050-three-cars-daytime-running-lights-illegally-off-23-november-2025-minute-bicycle-ride/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/23/p1050-three-cars-daytime-running-lights-illegally-off-23-november-2025-minute-bicycle-ride/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: 100% write one clear thought a day even if you don't share it publicly you'll get better at writing. 1 clear thought = 10 minutes IMNSHO :-) And you do have 10 minutes a day I guarantee it :-) ; Joan Westenberg:: Why You Should Write Every Day (Even if You’re Not a Writer)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 22, 2025 00:09 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joanwestenberg.com/p/why-you-should-write-every-day-even-if-you-re-not-a-writer&quot;&gt;ME:: 100% write one clear thought a day even if you don’t share it publicly you’ll get better at writing. 1 clear thought = 10 minutes IMNSHO :-) And you do have 10 minutes a day I guarantee it :-) ; Joan Westenberg:: Why You Should Write Every Day (Even if You’re Not a Writer)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joanwestenberg.com/p/why-you-should-write-every-day-even-if-you-re-not-a-writer&quot;&gt;Joan Westenberg:: Why You Should Write Every Day (Even if You’re Not a Writer)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But I don’t have time to write every day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fair enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everyone’s got limited hours and too many demands on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But I think we’re probably talking about fifteen to twenty minutes here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Maybe thirty on a good day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You’re not writing War and Peace. You’re writing enough to clarify one thought, work through one problem, capture one observation. That’s perhaps the length of three or four text messages to a friend, composed without chatGPT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/21/p1609-why-you-should-write-every-day-even-if-you-re-not-a-writer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/21/p1609-why-you-should-write-every-day-even-if-you-re-not-a-writer/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Broken CFMU podcast scene :-) due to React perhaps?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I can’t listen to my friend Kevin’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://cfmu.ca/episode/alternative-pre-89-episode-for-2025-11-12/&quot;&gt;second&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cfmu.ca/episode/alternative-pre-89-episode-for-2025-11-19/&quot;&gt;third&lt;/a&gt; pre 1989 alternative 80s shows because the web developer failed or something or React fails? &lt;a href=&quot;https://cfmu.ca/episode/alternative-pre-89-episode-for-2025-11-05/&quot;&gt;The first episode&lt;/a&gt; works fine. I tried debugging it with Firefox web tools and couldn’t figure it out i.e. I’m a terrible hobbyist web developer part 8888 :-).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/21/p0842-broken-cfmu-podcast-scene-react/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/21/p0842-broken-cfmu-podcast-scene-react/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Starcloud hides their 'secret compute in space' or something :-) ; Vaclav Vincalek:: Is this SciFi enough?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 20, 2025 15:17 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/scifienough-vaclav-vincalek-zcnhc/&quot;&gt;ME:: Starcloud hides their “secret compute in space” or something :-) ; Vaclav Vincalek:: Is this SciFi enough?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/scifienough-vaclav-vincalek-zcnhc/&quot;&gt;Vaclav Vincalek:: Is this SciFi enough?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are witnessing another SciFi idea turned into reality. A startup company, Starcloud, launched and placed in orbit the first AI Data Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This project is not about cheap power and cooling and locating fires in California. This project is about taking data and moving it outside of any jurisdiction, oversight and control. I am sure that there will be lots of takers for that offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The recurrent pattern? This is not SciFi turned reality project. It’s just a new place to hide family jewels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/20/p0717-scifienough-vaclav-vincalek-zcnhc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/20/p0717-scifienough-vaclav-vincalek-zcnhc/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: pre magellan Philippines was super interesting; Celestino C. Macachor:: Searching for Kali in the Indigenous Chronicles of Jovito Abellana By: Retracing our Past on Pandan Leaves – Pre-colonial Cebu</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 20, 2025 15:00 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20120703210211/http://cebueskrima.s5.com/custom3.html&quot;&gt;ME:: pre magellan Philippines was super interesting; Celestino C. Macachor:: Searching for Kali in the Indigenous Chronicles of Jovito Abellana By: Retracing our Past on Pandan Leaves – Pre-colonial Cebu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Legends and myth have been told about how the ancient name of Cebu City or as some old timers fondly call Sugbo originated.  None of these versions so far have held up to the scrutiny of scholars and historians until Jovito Abellana published his book Bisaya Patronymesis Sri Visjaya where he extensively wrote about Aginid, Bayok sa atong Tawarik (Glide on, Odes to our History)[1].  The Aginid a discovery made by Jovito Abellana’s great grandfather is probably the only pre-colonial chronicle of the history of Cebu written in ancient alibata script on pandan leaves and other indigenous materials.  Unfortunately most of the materials were lost in the subsequent upheaval that followed the Spanish defeat by Cebuano guerillas and the ensuing Filipino American War.     Amidst strong support by some scholars to institutionalize the Aginid, the Cebu Normal University published it in 1998.  Abellana wrote it in alibata (Cebuano hieroglyphic) form with an English translation.    The Aginid tells of the fiery story of pre-colonial Cebu then known as Sugbo – which means scorched earth.  This version on the origins of Sugbo, is important as it establishes the basic hypothesis why eskrima was invented in the first place – in defense against Moro invaders.  And to add credence to the discovery of the Aginid by Jovito Abellana, other cognates of the word Sugbo can be found in the Cebuano lexicon such as: sugba – to grill, subu’ – to forge steel, sug-ang – set a cooking fire, sugnod – to burn.     Let us go back to the story of how Sugbo got its name.  In the olden times Sugbo (now present day Cebu City) was part of the island of Pulua Kang Dayang or Kangdaya.  The ancient poem Diyandi tells us that so many hundred years ago natives had burned the town Sugbo as a way to drive away Muslim invaders from Mindanao.  The natives would then flee to the mountains and later launch a counter offensive against the demoralized and exhausted invaders.  The first ruler of Sugbo Sri Lumay who came from Sumatra successfully repulsed the invaders with his scorched earth tactics.  Thus the place became known as Sugbo or scorched town. Jovito Abellana translated the Diyandi which was written in ancient alibata script and probably written during the time of Datu Tupas.  It is a stirring chronicle of the story of the rich culture and colorful history of  pre-colonial Cebu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Aginid, Bayok sa Atong Tawarik (Glide on, Odes to Our History)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Extracted from Marivir Montebon’s book Retracing Our Roots – A Journey into Cebu’s Pre-Colonial Past[2] are excerpts of the story of pre-colonial Cebu according to the Aginid,  Bayok sa atong Tawarik (Glide on, Odes to Our History) as translated by Jovito Abellana:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Sri Lumay of Sumatra settled in Sugbo with his son, Sri Alho, ruling the south known as Sialo which included Valladolid, Carcar, up to Santander.     His other son, Sri Ukob, ruled the north known as Nahalin which includes the present towns of Consolacion, Liloan, Compostela, Danao, Carmen, and Bantayan.   As a ruler, Sri Lumay was known to be strict, merciless, and brave.  He assigned magalamags to teach his people to read and write ancient letterings.  He ordered routinary patrol by boats from Nahalin to Sialo by his mangubats (warriors).     A strict ruler, Sri Lumay was a loving person that not a single slave ran away from him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/20/p0700-pre-magellan-cebu-sugbu/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/20/p0700-pre-magellan-cebu-sugbu/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Dominant Hegemony (DH) historically &amp; today choose to NOT acknowledge their privilege &amp; value their convenience (for food delivery, mobility etc) over paying non-DH folks a living wage. Cities aren't going away despite pundits and their dreams :-) of  self driving cars (which we don't need and won't work; we already have public transit, trains and buses) and food delivery.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The DH is fine anywhere: suburbia, urban core, etc because everything comes to them &amp;amp; is built for them so it doesn’t matter where they live. Since the 1918 pandemic, pundits have been wrongly predicting the demise of cities. Wrong then, wrong now :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/19/p2129-dominant-hegemony-do-not-acknowledge-their-privilege-convenience-food-delivery-mobility-dont-want-pay-living-wages-to-non-dh-folks-selfdriving-cars-wont-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/19/p2129-dominant-hegemony-do-not-acknowledge-their-privilege-convenience-food-delivery-mobility-dont-want-pay-living-wages-to-non-dh-folks-selfdriving-cars-wont-work/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It's 2025: could websites, blog posts and newsletters use links to actually link to the restaurant, website, museum, etc that they're referring to pretty please :-) ?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;#LOLIHaveBeenAskingThisForAtLeast20Years ;-) Also I still hate newsletters (I’d rather read your website especially if it has RSS) and won’t read them even though I subscribe and I am still not starting a newsletter :-) #Ymmv&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 7, 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/04/07/p1-blogs-and-rss-are-dead-but-since-nothing-to-sell-no-email-newsletter/&quot;&gt;Agree with Chuq! The blog is dead and so is RSS but since i’m not trying to sell you anything (yet) i will continue to blog, generate RSS &amp;amp; not have an email newsletter #ymmv #doWhatMakesYouHappyAndGivesYouThe’Engagement’YouSeek :-)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/18/p2000-websites-blog-posts-newsletters-should-link-to-restaurant-website-museum-websites-pretty-please/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/18/p2000-websites-blog-posts-newsletters-should-link-to-restaurant-website-museum-websites-pretty-please/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Apeman R1 Seeker rear view real-time video camera shows lots people illegally driving with their daytime running lights OFF behind me in the city of Vancouver.</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Law abiding people don’t exist when driving cars (as well as bicycles; bicycles aren’t 4000 pounds of daily danger, the consequences of law breaking are much lower on a bicycle especially an “acoustic” :-) one; I don’t condone breaking traffic laws when bicycling or driving.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I ride (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/athletes/22831652&quot;&gt;my rides on Strava&lt;/a&gt;) 12km (6km each way Trout Lake to Gastown) Monday-Friday and I see in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/667837446/seeker-4k-bike-dashcam-and-safety-lighting-system&quot;&gt;Apeman R1 seeker rear view real time video camera&lt;/a&gt; I got in 2023 or was it 2024 :-) at least a couple of cars or trucks with their daytime running lights off. These people are probably the ones who complain about bicyclists not following traffic laws LOL.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For a good time :-) see &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drivesmartbc.ca/safety-equipment/viewpoint-daytime-running-lights&quot;&gt;VIEWPOINT - Daytime Running Lights&lt;/a&gt; which has this juicy &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Daytime running lights have been mandatory for vehicles in Canada since 1990. It appears many drivers and vehicle dealers are not aware of this requirement. Having driven thousands of kilometres over the last 40 years I know that DRL can help prevent accidents particularly on poor light and rainy conditions.&lt;/code&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 14, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/14/p2012-mlk-double-standard-law-enforcement-respect-for-laws/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: There is a double standard in the enforcement of law, a double standard in the respect for particular laws. &amp;lt;- ‘Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?’, 1967.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/17/p2209-apeman-seeker-rear-view-real-time-video-camera-illegally-driving-daytime-running-lights-off-vancouver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/17/p2209-apeman-seeker-rear-view-real-time-video-camera-illegally-driving-daytime-running-lights-off-vancouver/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
