<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 14:57:42 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 14:57:42 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to: retain selected fields and remove the rest in a CSV file using mlr aka miller</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following miller aka &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mlr&lt;/code&gt; script removes all fields except &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;title&lt;/code&gt;and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;mlr &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;--csv&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;cut&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;-f&lt;/span&gt; title,content id-1279731-unixtime-1583100833-by-id-firefox-creator-answers-desktop-all-locales.csv 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(previously blogged not as clearly: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2019/02/15/p1-using-miller-aka-mlr-to-combine-selected-fields-from-a-csv-file/&quot;&gt;Using mlr aka miller to combine selected fields from multiple CSV files&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/03/01/p1-howto-mlr-miller-remov-fields-from-csv/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/03/01/p1-howto-mlr-miller-remov-fields-from-csv/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I want off Mr. Golang's Wild Ride: 'Go is a Bell Labs fantasy, and not a very good one at that' (kind of like C++ before it, am I right :-) ?)</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Computers, operating systems, networks are a hot mess. They’re barely manageable, even if you know a decent amount about what you’re doing. Nine out of ten software engineers agree: it’s a miracle anything works at all.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;So all the complexity is swept under the rug. Hidden from view, but not solved.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go is a Bell Labs fantasy, and not a very good one at that.” &amp;lt;— not sure I recommend reading the very long thing LOL but if you want: &lt;a href=&quot;https://fasterthanli.me/blog/2020/i-want-off-mr-golangs-wild-ride/&quot;&gt;I want off Mr. Golang’s Wild Ride&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/29/p1-go-bell-labs-fantasy-just-like-cplusplus/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/29/p1-go-bell-labs-fantasy-just-like-cplusplus/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use Transfer Learning from prior image models to generate tshirt graphics?</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Machine learning engineering is becoming a real ecosystem&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Looking at software engineering as a parallel, we typically see ecosystems “mature” in pretty standard patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;A new programming language will emerge with some exciting features, and  people will use it for specialized use-cases, research projects, and  toys. At this stage, anyone who uses it has to build all their basic  utilities from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Down the line, people within the community develop libraries and projects  that abstract common utilities away, until the tooling is capable and  stable enough to be used in production.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In this approach, a team takes a pre-trained model and removes/retrains  the last layers of the model to focus on a new, related task.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;” &amp;lt;— Read the whole thing:  “&lt;a href=&quot;https://towardsdatascience.com/deep-learning-isnt-hard-anymore-26db0d4749d7&quot;&gt;Deep learning isn’t hard anymore&lt;/a&gt; – At least, building software with deep learning isn’t”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The above article links to: &lt;a href=&quot;https://ruder.io/transfer-learning/&quot;&gt;Transfer Learning - Machine Learning’s Next Frontier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I think it is and it isn’t. It is but as a newbie there are far too many choices. Hard to figure out where to start!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/28/p1-use-transfer-learning-from-images-for-tshirt-graphics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/28/p1-use-transfer-learning-from-images-for-tshirt-graphics/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fastpages from fastai I don't fully understand: you still need a server to render python notebooks for testing purposes, right? Altair Python Visualizations seem excellent &amp; Blogging via Word files is great though</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is why I love the premise of &lt;a href=&quot;https://alpha.iodide.io/&quot;&gt;iodide&lt;/a&gt; as I understand it :  you don’t need a server! Any web browser can run your notebook code just like any web browser can render your static web pages. No extra server required.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anyways,  I am probably over-thinking the need for a server. We will always need servers :-) ! It’s just that in my opinion every node even if it’s just a laptop or better yet phone running a browser should be a server as well as a client!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check out the intro post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://fastpages.fast.ai/fastpages/jupyter/2020/02/21/introducing-fastpages.html&quot;&gt;introducing fastpages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And then check out Stephen Downe’s attempt to clarify “introducing fastpages” :-) :  &lt;a href=&quot;https://halfanhour.blogspot.com/2020/02/how-to-use-fastpages.html&quot;&gt;How to Use Fastpages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All in all something I should try!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/26/p1-fastpages-notebooks-good-altair-good-i-dont-understand-the-rest-still-need-server/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/26/p1-fastpages-notebooks-good-altair-good-i-dont-understand-the-rest-still-need-server/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How To: Fact Check the corona virus aka Covid-19 crisis </title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“So often when news reaches us we act like we &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; make a decision on &lt;em&gt;this particular&lt;/em&gt; tweet, or post, or website. But the web is abundant! If it’s a true  story there are likely many better sources than the one that happened to find you. And if it is a false one, maybe someone already looked into  that for you. “ &amp;lt;— read the whole thing from  &lt;a href=&quot;https://siftingthroughtheoutbreak.wordpress.com/2020/02/23/find-a-better-source/&quot;&gt;News Search cross-check&lt;/a&gt; on Mike Caulfield’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://siftingthroughtheoutbreak.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;Sifting Through the Coronavirus Outbreak blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/25/p1-fact-checking-corona-virus/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/25/p1-fact-checking-corona-virus/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The good ole days at Bryght :-) 'Web 1.0' versus 'Web 2.0'</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/beanjammin/status/1232119216330899459&quot;&gt;Ben&lt;/a&gt; from from August 2004:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20041013212319/http://www.bryght.com/node/view/50&quot;&gt;Web 2.0 Websites - 1.0 just say NO!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember when the internet wasn’t a ‘miasma’ of lies and mis-information back in 2004? Neither do I :-) !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/24/p1-the-good-ole-days-at-bryght/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/24/p1-the-good-ole-days-at-bryght/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SQLite, JSON, CSV :-) the eternal golden braid of formats? so many tools for normal folks to grok them without programming e.g. sqlitebrowser</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For many years, I thought I needed a “real” database for my hobbyist programming of tshirts and other things. So I learned and used MongoDB starting in 2011 for my Thunderbird support scripts (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2011/04/04/mongodb-is-my-current-persistent-data-structure-store-of-choice-aka-how-to-slurp-your-get-satisfaction-data-into-mongodb/&quot;&gt;MongoDB is my current persistent data structure store of choice aka “how to slurp your Get Satisfaction data into MongoDB”&lt;/a&gt; from April 2011)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A legacy of growing up with small files and slow disks? i.e. programming since 1977&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anyhow it’s the 21st century and you can do everything with SQLite, JSON and CSV up until about what 1-2GB per file, perhaps even larger?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In other words, you don’t need MongoDB or indeed any “real database” like PostgreSQL until you have many gigabytes of data! And most small scale projects have less than 1 GB of data in their datasets even in plain text formats like JSON and CSV and in SQLite.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And the cool thing is SQLite, JSON and CSV can be consumed, queried and manipulated by “normal” folks without programming using Google Docs for CSV, the numerous tools for JSON and many tools for SQLite like SQLiteBrowser aka &lt;a href=&quot;https://sqlitebrowser.org/&quot;&gt;DB Browser for SQLite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/23/p1-sqlite-csv-json-the-eternal-golden-braid-sqlitebrowser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/23/p1-sqlite-csv-json-the-eternal-golden-braid-sqlitebrowser/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Payak 2020: 1:40 oops fell 3 times in the first 5km, but mountain view climb was fast because of the klaebo running up hill diagonal stride technique</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Payak &lt;a href=&quot;https://zone4.ca/race/2020-02-22/08c387e2/results/&quot;&gt;2020&lt;/a&gt; (on classic skins with fake skins): 1:40 (same time as &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/02/26/p1-payak-2018-skate-skiing-140/&quot;&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt; on skate, slower than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/payak-2019-10-minuten-schneller-super-fun-2170380303&quot;&gt;2019&lt;/a&gt; on skate) oops fell 3 times in the first 5km, but mountain view climb was fast because of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xcskiforum.com/viewtopic.php?t=5087&quot;&gt;“klaebo running up hill diagonal stride”&lt;/a&gt; technique, so that’s something positive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did I fall so much? I fell on the downhills which is weird for me. I know one of the falls was due to skin sticking. Maybe it was due to the snow which was fast but sticky randomly and finally maybe it was due to the great waxing job the Swix folks did speeding up my downhills? Don’t know it was probably mostly me not having the same core and cardio and less time on classic skis (did a lot of skate on Mondays).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I figure if I hadn’t fallen I would have been 5-10 minutes faster! Could have, should have, would have :-) Onwards to 2021!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe height=&quot;405&quot; width=&quot;590&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/3123321178/embed/0c1b0cb6323732db26e51beb071b6652679c6d76&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/22/p1-payak-2020-slower-because-i-fell-3-times-in-first-5-mountain-view-climb-was-fast-klaebo-rules/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/22/p1-payak-2020-slower-because-i-fell-3-times-in-first-5-mountain-view-climb-was-fast-klaebo-rules/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eugene Wallingford: Programming feels like home. &lt;-- To me it feels like a comfortable chesterfield :-) Ton's got a great take on it too #ymmv</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Sloan reminds us that programming can be – is – more than a line on a  resume. It is something that everyone can do,  and want to do, for a lot of different reasons. It would  be great if programming “were marbled deeply into domesticity and comfort, nerdiness and curiosity, health and love” in  the way that cooking is. That is what makes Computing for All  &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; worth doing.” &amp;lt;— read Eugene’s  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.uni.edu/~wallingf/blog/archives/monthly/2020-02.html#e2020-02-18T16_00_24.htm&quot;&gt;Programming Feels like home&lt;/a&gt; which is a fantastic riff on &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/16/p1-robin-sloan-an-app-home-cooked-meal/&quot;&gt;Robin Sloan: An app can be a home-cooked meal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And like cooking you don’t have to cook and some don’t want to ever and that’s fine too (you can’t do everything but like cooking I think it’s worth a try at some point in your life)!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bonus take from Ton’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zylstra.org/blog/2020/02/i-am-the-programming-equivalent-of-a-home-cook/&quot;&gt;I am the programming equivalent of a home cook&lt;/a&gt; “Eating better, more  affordably or in a specific way, translates to programming with the  purpose to hone the laptop as your tool of trade and adapt it to your  own personal workflows, making it support and work with your very own  quirks. “&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/20/p1-programming-feels-like-home-comfy-chesterfield/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/20/p1-programming-feels-like-home-comfy-chesterfield/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Imagemagick v7 is much faster than OilyPNG or VIPS for creating images, cropping them and montaging i.e. collaging them</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;pontifications&quot;&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forgot to mention 2 days ago in &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/17/p1-how-i-made-art-of-where-tights-berlin/&quot;&gt;How I made Art of Where Tights from Berlin photos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Imagemagick aka magick version 7 even on a “slow” ARM64 processor is much faster at cropping and montaging images (probably because it’s in C/C++) than ruby solutions like VIPS and OilyPNG/ChunkyPNG. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2019/01/23/p1-did-you-get-catch-the-error-vips-code-yesterday-oilypng-twice-as-fast/&quot;&gt;Did you catch the bug in yesterday’s vips code? I’ve coded an oily_png version that is at least twice as fast!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extra bonus about using magick is that you don’t have to write code. You just have to master its arcane syntax :-) which isn’t that bad!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/19/p1-magick-is-faster-than-vips-or-ruby-oilypng-chunkypng/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/19/p1-magick-is-faster-than-vips-or-ruby-oilypng-chunkypng/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
