<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 22:14:14 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 22:14:14 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Does this AI notes thing work :-) ?!? ; Notability note taking startup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 12, 2025 14:50 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://notability.com/&quot;&gt;Notability&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;— yet another note taking startup powered by “AI” :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/12/p0750-notability-com/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/12/p0750-notability-com/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: this seems to work on macOS Big Sur 11.7 ;  huksley's github gist:: Disabling photoanalysisd on macOS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 10, 2025 03:19 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/huksley/564be2c903312bcee7dffe415d128f90&quot;&gt;ME: this seems to work on macOS Big Sur 11.7 ;  huksley’s github gist:: Disabling photoanalysisd on macOS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following seemed to work on 11.7, note that this changed slightly in Monterrey and later ; read the gist for those newer macOS versions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;launchctl disable gui/$UID/com.apple.photoanalysisd&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;launchctl kill -TERM gui/$UID/com.apple.photoanalysisd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/09/p2019-how-to-kill-photoanalysisd/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/09/p2019-how-to-kill-photoanalysisd/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Death of a disco dancer er Google Web search :-) Killed by Google AI mode and ChatGPT with GPT-5 search ; Simon Willison:: Google's AI mode is good, actually</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 7, 2025 14:43 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Sep/7/ai-mode/&quot;&gt;ME:: Death of a disco dancer er Google Web search :-) Killed by Google AI mode and ChatGPT with GPT-5 search ; Simon Willison:: Google’s AI mode is good, actually&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Sep/7/ai-mode/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison:: Google’s AI mode is good, actually&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When I wrote about how good ChatGPT with GPT-5 is at search yesterday I nearly added a note about how comparatively disappointing Google’s efforts around this are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m glad I left that out, because it turns out Google’s new “AI mode” is genuinely really good! It feels very similar to GPT-5 search but returns results much faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/07/p0743-ai-mode/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/07/p0743-ai-mode/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Go science go! Explaining COVID science to privileged folks with 'educations' should NOT be required ; Jess Steier:: I inserted myself into a conversation at a bar about Covid and vaccines. Here’s what happened :: How to talk to strangers at a bar about Covid, dispel misinformation and explain the real science behind vaccines and mRNA vaccines ¦ STAT</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 7, 2025 06:02 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/06/covid-misinformation-bar-strangers-public-health-science/&quot;&gt;ME:: Go science go! Explaining COVID science to privileged folks with ‘educations’ should NOT be required ; Jess Steier:: I inserted myself into a conversation at a bar about Covid and vaccines. Here’s what happened :: How to talk to strangers at a bar about Covid, dispel misinformation and explain the real science behind vaccines and mRNA vaccines ¦ STAT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing of course: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/06/covid-misinformation-bar-strangers-public-health-science/&quot;&gt;Jess Steier:: I inserted myself into a conversation at a bar about Covid and vaccines. Here’s what happened :: How to talk to strangers at a bar about Covid, dispel misinformation and explain the real science behind vaccines and mRNA vaccines ¦ STAT&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To those of us in public health, it feels like the world is on fire. We’re watching the systematic dismantling of institutions that have protected Americans from disease for decades. But to most people? They have no idea any of this is happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The damage isn’t just rhetorical. In six months under Kennedy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The CDC has lost nearly half its budget and thousands of employees.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;He fired all vaccine advisory experts, replacing them with vaccine skeptics.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Multiple CDC leaders have resigned in protest.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The agency is described as broken by former directors.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Important programs targeting cancer, heart disease, strokes, lead poisoning, injury prevention, and violence have been severely weakened or defunded.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The largest measles outbreak in a generation occurred during this period, while Kennedy downplayed the importance of vaccines and promoted unproven treatments.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Funding for global vaccination efforts protecting millions of children worldwide has been halted.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jim O’Neill, a non-medically trained investment adviser, was appointed as acting CDC director, raising concerns about leadership expertise.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A gunman attacked CDC staff, motivated by Covid vaccine opposition.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The agency’s focus was narrowed to infectious diseases only, abandoning key chronic disease and injury prevention roles.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Writing out these bullet points feels futile because it is difficult to convey the magnitude of destruction. This is demolition, not reform. And it’s happening while the public thinks Kennedy is fighting for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/06/p2302-covid-misinformation-bar-strangers-public-health-science/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/06/p2302-covid-misinformation-bar-strangers-public-health-science/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: seems like platitudes :-)  to baseline, experiment, have a community of practice and read DORA and other's research papers?!?!? ; Amanda Lewis:: August 2024:: DORA:: How to enable your software delivery teams to innovate with generative AI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 6, 2025 21:35 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://dora.dev/guides/how-to-innovate-with-generative-ai/&quot;&gt;ME:: seems like platitudes :-)  to baseline, experiment, have a community of practice and read DORA and other’s research papers?!?!? ; Amanda Lewis:: August 2024:: DORA:: How to enable your software delivery teams to innovate with generative AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing and what’s linked: &lt;a href=&quot;https://dora.dev/guides/how-to-innovate-with-generative-ai/&quot;&gt;Amanda Lewis:: August 2024:: DORA ¦ How to enable your software delivery teams to innovate with generative AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To innovate your software delivery and operations with generative AI, a culture of continuous improvement and user-centricity is essential. Begin by establishing a baseline, nurture curiosity and experimentation, and cultivate a collaborative community of practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Set a baseline: it’s always good to know where you are before you start introducing new practices and capabilities. Be sure you know the software delivery performance of your team so that you can see how introducing generative AI affects your development and delivery processes. The DORA Quick Check is a great place to start your baselining efforts, and you can bookmark your results for easy reference.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Encourage curiosity and experimentation: the early findings show that generative AI can improve well-being. Remember the importance of having a generative and learning culture when you introduce generative AI into your organization. Foster a space where your teams can see this technology as an opportunity for experimenting and innovating, and not as a threat.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Establish a generative AI community of practice: high-performing teams prioritize strategies that foster a sense of community across various organizational levels. These strategies include establishing communities of practice and supporting proofs of concept. As your organization experiments with generative AI, encourage collaboration based on best practices, knowledge sharing, and learning from failures.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read our most recent research: DORA continues to research an publish findings about adoption, attitudes, and downstream impacts of AI.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Join the DORA Community of Practice: share your experience with fellow travelers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/06/p1435-how-to-innovate-with-generative-ai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/06/p1435-how-to-innovate-with-generative-ai/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Machine learning assisted coding doesn't increase the number of apps part 8888 :-) ?!? ; Mike Judge:: Where's the Shovelware? Why AI Coding Claims Don't Add Up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 4, 2025 15:23 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://mikelovesrobots.substack.com/p/wheres-the-shovelware-why-ai-coding&quot;&gt;ME:: Machine learning assisted coding doesn’t increase the number of apps part 8888 :-) ?!? ; Mike Judge:: Where’s the Shovelware? Why AI Coding Claims Don’t Add Up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And yet, despite the most widespread adoption one could imagine5, these tools don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;My argument: If so many developers are so extraordinarily productive using these tools, where is the flood of shovelware? We should be seeing apps of all shapes and sizes, video games, new websites, mobile apps, software-as-a-service apps — we should be drowning in choice. We should be in the middle of an indie software revolution. We should be seeing 10,000 Tetris clones on Steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/04/p0823-wheres-the-shovelware-why-ai-coding/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/04/p0823-wheres-the-shovelware-why-ai-coding/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME::  Tempted to try this but $CDN40/month for streaming is a lot ; Fedihost:: Create New Peertube Service</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 4, 2025 15:14 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://fedihost.co/create&quot;&gt;ME::  Tempted to try this but $CDN40/month for streaming is a lot ; Fedihost:: Create New Peertube Service&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– I probably should wait until a co-op does this or something :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Peertube 30
$39.99
Monthly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Always included:
Daily Backups
10 GB Base Storage
Global CDN&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Specifications:
Priority Support
4 Encoders Guaranteed
Video Studio
1 Concurrent Livestream&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Multiple user instance with frequent uploads and live streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/04/p0814-create/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/04/p0814-create/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: yet another Tailscale HOW TO, i have to try this someday! ; Avush Pande:: I use Tailscale to remotely access my self-hosted services - here's how</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Sep 3, 2025 15:00 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xda-developers.com/tailscale-guide/&quot;&gt;ME:: yet another Tailscale HOW TO, i have to try this someday! ; Avush Pande:: I use Tailscale to remotely access my self-hosted services - here’s how&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- QUOTE: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;As if that’s not enough, your home network could be afflicted with the scourge called CGNAT, making port forwarding even more of a hassle. While it’s not exactly a fully self-hosted solution since you’re relying on a company’s servers, Tailscale simplifies the process of exposing your local services to external networks. So, here’s a quick guide on how you can configure Tailscale to remotely access your favorite self-hosted services.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/03/p0800-tailscale-guide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/09/03/p0800-tailscale-guide/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Oh Pharmacy in Coquitlam had unexpired vaccines as of August 11 2025 ; Ducky :: 2025-08-11 oops 13  General – Pandemics in British Columbia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Aug 31, 2025 19:26 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://covidbc.webfoot.com/2025/08/13/2025-08-11-general/&quot;&gt;ME:: Oh Pharmacy in Coquitlam had unexpired vaccines as of August 11 2025 ; Ducky :: 2025-08-11 oops 13  General – Pandemics in British Columbia&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: “Addendum2: An alert reader says that there is in fact at least one pharmacy in BC which has unexpired COVID-19 vaccines: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.healthlinkbc.ca/clinic/oh-pharmacy&quot;&gt;Oh Pharmacy&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/31/p1226-2025-08-11-general/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/31/p1226-2025-08-11-general/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Not tested on Humans yet but sounds promising go science go; September 2024:: Brigham and Women’s Hospital. PCANS Drug-free nasal spray blocks, neutralizes viruses, bacteria — Harvard Gazette</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Aug 31, 2025 19:05 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2024/09/drug-free-nasal-spray-blocks-neutralizes-viruses-bacteria/&quot;&gt;ME:: Not tested on Humans yet but sounds promising go science go; September 2024:: Brigham and Women’s Hospital. PCANS Drug-free nasal spray blocks, neutralizes viruses, bacteria — Harvard Gazette&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;via &lt;a href=&quot;https://sfba.social/@nwchapman/115124195881987830&quot;&gt;@nwchapman’s toot&lt;/a&gt; and also there’s a an earlier drug free nasal spray using Iota-Carrageenan: see October 2021:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC8493111/&quot;&gt;Efficacy of a Nasal Spray Containing Iota-Carrageenan in the Postexposure Prophylaxis of COVID-19 in Hospital Personnel Dedicated to Patients Care with COVID-19 Disease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2024/09/drug-free-nasal-spray-blocks-neutralizes-viruses-bacteria/&quot;&gt;PCANS Drug-free nasal spray blocks, neutralizes viruses, bacteria — Harvard Gazette&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Experiments in mice showed that a single dose of the PCANS nasal spray could effectively block infection from an influenza virus (PR8) at 25 times the lethal dose. Virus levels in the lungs were reduced by &amp;gt;99.99 percent, and the inflammatory cells and cytokines in the lungs of PCANS-treated animals were normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The formulation’s ability to inactivate a broad spectrum of pathogens, including the deadly PR8 influenza virus, demonstrates its high effectiveness,” said co-senior author Yohannes Tesfaigzi, AstraZeneca Professor of Medicine in the Field of Respiratory and Inflammatory Diseases at BWH. “In a rigorous mouse model study, prophylactic treatment with PCANS demonstrated exceptional efficacy, with treated mice exhibiting complete protection, while the untreated group showed no such benefit.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While the study’s limitations include the lack of human studies of PCANS, it provides a strong foundation for future research to explore the full potential of PCANS in a broader context. The researchers are exploring whether PCANS can also block allergens, opening a potential new avenue for allergy relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/31/p1205-drug-free-nasal-spray-blocks-neutralizes-viruses-bacteria/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/31/p1205-drug-free-nasal-spray-blocks-neutralizes-viruses-bacteria/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
