<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:58:55 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:58:55 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl-dr-ing: Courtesy of the oppressive Spanish Empire, Filipinos have been in North America since forever :-) Louisana in the mid-18th century is just one example of many! ; Wikipedia:: Saint Malo, Louisiana</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 1, 2025 15:17 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Malo,_Louisiana&quot;&gt;ME:: tl-dr-ing: Courtesy of the oppressive Spanish Empire, Filipinos have been in North America since forever :-) Louisana in the mid-18th century is just one example of many! ; Wikipedia:: Saint Malo, Louisiana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Saint Malo (Spanish: San Maló [samaˈlo]) was a small fishing village that existed along the shore of Lake Borgne in St. Bernard Parish, Louisiana as early as the mid-18th century until it was destroyed by the 1915 New Orleans hurricane.[1] Located along Bayou Saint Malo, about 6 miles (9.7 km) east of the Isleño fishing village of Shell Beach, it was the first permanent settlement of Filipinos and perhaps the first Asian American settlement in the United States.[2][3][4][5]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The exact date of the establishment of Saint Malo is disputed.[6][4] The settlement may have been formed as early as 1763 or 1765 by Filipino deserters and escaped slaves of the Spanish Manila galleon trade.[7][8][9][10] The members of the community were commonly referred to as Manila men, or Manilamen, and later Tagalas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/01/p0717-saint_malo,_louisiana/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/01/p0717-saint_malo,_louisiana/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Today is World AIDS day. Bring back the funding Canada, USA, etc
We are all one. When so many are sick and funding can help reduce that now and in the future it's 100% common sense. Go science go!</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/01/p0709-restore-aids-funding-canada-it-is-common-sense/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/01/p0709-restore-aids-funding-canada-it-is-common-sense/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Be seen plus SEE bicycle Light Rail light from Intrinsic Cycles looks good but how do I install this on my Wald basket (the basket blocks lights mounted on the handlebar)? Not a big deal I guess Wald basket bicyclists are not mainstream yet :-) Light Rail Kit  – Intrinsic Cycles</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 30, 2025 16:35 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://intrinsiccycles.com/products/light-rail&quot;&gt;ME:: Be seen plus SEE bicycle Light Rail light from Intrinsic Cycles looks good but how do I install this on my Wald basket (the basket blocks lights mounted on the handlebar)? Not a big deal I guess Wald basket bicyclists are not mainstream yet :-) Light Rail Kit  – Intrinsic Cycles&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Most bike lights make you choose: see or be seen. The Light Rail does both—at the same time. With two independently controlled lighting systems—one to illuminate your path and one to keep you visible to others—you get unmatched safety and control, all in one light.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/30/p0835-light-rail/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/30/p0835-light-rail/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: nobody mentions the considerable cost for LLMs and the considerable amount of time you need to experiment to see if an LLM works for you. Time and money require privilege and wealth;  Federico Viticci:: The AI App Experience Matters More Than Benchmarks Now - MacStories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 30, 2025 07:55 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.macstories.net/notes/the-ai-app-experience-matters-more-than-benchmarks-now/&quot;&gt;ME:: nobody mentions the considerable cost for LLMs and the considerable amount of time you need to experiment to see if an LLM works for you. Time and money require privilege and wealth;  Federico Viticci:: The AI App Experience Matters More Than Benchmarks Now - MacStories&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Which brings me to my takeaway: from my perspective, despite a stronger baseline, there is still no single LLM that “does it all” these days. Beyond my nerdy experiments, I generally alternate between two modes: Claude for most work-related tasks, and either ChatGPT or Perplexity for web search. The combination of these two modalities gives me everything I need from modern LLMs, and it provides me with the mix of performance, design, and app integrations I like best. ... Ultimately, choosing between any LLM at the frontier of AI right now is a highly subjective matter that comes down to cost, workflow, app ecosystem, design, and, yes, pure “vibes”. Personally, I try to avoid fixating on benchmarks and instead prioritize these qualities in my decisions&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/29/p2355-the-ai-app-experience-matters-more-than-benchmarks-now/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/29/p2355-the-ai-app-experience-matters-more-than-benchmarks-now/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Specifications can be version controlled much easier than prompts and are therefore the future for AI assisted software development; Marc Brooker:: Kiro and the future of AI spec-driven software development</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 30, 2025 07:49 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://kiro.dev/blog/kiro-and-the-future-of-software-development/&quot;&gt;ME:: Specifications can be version controlled much easier than prompts and are therefore the future for AI assisted software development; Marc Brooker:: Kiro and the future of AI spec-driven software development&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Approaching development with specifications has three significant benefits. First, it provides a way for developers and stakeholders to understand and agree on the goals of the program. It’s crisp documentation on what we want the program to do, the interface to look like, and how it should be implemented. Working at the specification level allows programmers to move faster, and spend more time thinking about the things that really matter. Second, it provides a guide for AI agents to work from, refer to, and validate their work against. A North Star to guide the work of the agent, allowing it to take on larger tasks without getting lost. Third, the specification tames the chaos of prompt-driven vibe coding on large code bases, moving away from an ad-hoc exercise in prompt engineering, to way for programmers to crisply express their intent to agents. A specification is a kind of (version controlled, human-readable) super prompt.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/29/p2349-kiro-and-the-future-of-software-development/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/29/p2349-kiro-and-the-future-of-software-development/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LLMs are just tools that are part of your problem solving system part 8888 :-) ; Marc Brooker:: LLMs as Parts of Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 30, 2025 07:46 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://brooker.co.za/blog/2025/08/12/llms-as-components.html&quot;&gt;LLMs are just tools that are part of your problem solving system part 8888 :-) ; Marc Brooker:: LLMs as Parts of Systems&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;As a system builder, I’m much more interested in what systems of LLMs and tools can do together. LLMs and code interpreters. LLMs and databases. LLMs and browsers. LLMs and SMT solvers. These systems can do things, today, that LLMs alone simply can’t, and will never be able to do. More importantly, they can do things today orders of magnitude more cheaply and quickly than LLMs can, even in the case where they can do the same things.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/29/p2346-llms-as-components/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/29/p2346-llms-as-components/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl-dr-ing: 100 characters, medium, subject, hints about the meaning of the artwork ; Mibs:: Mibyle: alt text 101 for artists</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 29, 2025 23:23 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://mibyleonline.tumblr.com/post/722824746438426624/alt-text-101-for-artists&quot;&gt;ME:: tl-dr-ing: 100 characters, medium, subject, hints about the meaning of the artwork ; Mibs:: Mibyle: alt text 101 for artists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://mibyleonline.tumblr.com/post/722824746438426624/alt-text-101-for-artists&quot;&gt;Mibyle: alt text 101 for artists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It all goes down to including what is relevant to give the user an accurate idea of your artwork:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the medium you used to make the artwork (is it a digital illustration? a traditional oil painting? a graphite pencil sketchbook doodle?)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the subject of the artwork&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;anything that is relevant for understanding the meaning of the artwork. For instance, is the lighting important, or does it bring a particular meaning or mood?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Write sentences - don’t just throw away key words. EDIT: don’t write full sentences, but phrases and fragments to keep your description concise&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;adding one more thing after getting feedback: keep it concise! Under 125 characters (even 100 is best)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/29/p1523-alt-text-101-for-artists/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/29/p1523-alt-text-101-for-artists/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: LLMs are good at: writing SQL. get datacleaning 95% right and data enrichment running stuff in a loop against 1000s of records. Amazing it's too bad nobody does data journalism like this in the mainstream media in Canada :-) Lots of people doing non mainstream stuff like this in Canada I would guess ; CL Kao, Dori Wilson:: Data Renegades ¦ Ep. #2, Data Journalism Unleashed with Simon Willison ¦ Heavybit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 29, 2025 07:25 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heavybit.com/library/podcasts/data-renegades/ep-2-data-journalism-unleashed-with-simon-willison&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: LLMs are good at: writing SQL. get datacleaning 95% right and data enrichment running stuff in a loop against 1000s of records. Amazing it’s too bad nobody does data journalism like this in the mainstream media in Canada :-) Lots of people doing non mainstream stuff like this in Canada I would guess ; CL Kao, Dori Wilson:: Data Renegades ¦ Ep. #2, Data Journalism Unleashed with Simon Willison ¦ Heavybit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/28/p2325-ep-2-data-journalism-unleashed-with-simon-willison/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/28/p2325-ep-2-data-journalism-unleashed-with-simon-willison/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>'Twas a beautiful sunny day to enjoy Fish and Chips at Go Fish at Granville Island with Dale and record over 40 in Vancouver #Lucky #Thanks</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go Fish (who oddly don’t have a website and don’t have an instagram account LOL)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://over40invan.com/94-pluribus-episode-5/&quot;&gt;#94 – Pluribus Episode 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/28/p2309-twas-beautiful-sunny-enjoy-fish-chips-go-fish-granville-island-over40invancouver/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/28/p2309-twas-beautiful-sunny-enjoy-fish-chips-go-fish-granville-island-over40invancouver/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Yes please, corporations should pay their fair share for open source software, 100% agree with Erlend; Erlend Sogge Heggen:: Open Source Power</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 26, 2025 19:48 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.muni.town/open-source-power/&quot;&gt;ME:: Yes please, corporations should pay their fair share for open source software, 100% agree with Erlend; Erlend Sogge Heggen:: Open Source Power&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The top 10 biggest programming languages in the world are collectively responsible for trillions of dollars in generated value. How much of that value is cycling back into the maintenance of these languages and their ecosystems? 0.01% maybe, if even that? ... Is it really that crazy to imagine a community-governed and institution-owned package management stack that's licensed such that corporations have to pay their fair share, to the tune of some tens of millions of dollar per year in revenue? Keep in mind that non-profits are welcome to make lots of revenue, it's the excess profits that's a probem.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/26/p1148-open-source-power-corporations-should-pay-fair-share-for-open-source-software/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/26/p1148-open-source-power-corporations-should-pay-fair-share-for-open-source-software/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
