<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 00:10:00 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 00:10:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Broken 10th Avenue Rat Running Scene aka How drivers routinely break traffic laws and get away with it because the city of Vancouver and VPD traffic enforcement don't care about ensuring safety by enforcing traffic laws ;  Nic Laporte:: YouTube:: How Did This Become Vancouver’s Busiest Shortcut?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 27, 2026 07:45 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0ZFp6xMPVnk&quot;&gt;ME:: Broken 10th Avenue Rat Running Scene aka How drivers routinely break traffic laws and get away with it because the city of Vancouver and VPD traffic enforcement don’t care about ensuring safety by enforcing traffic laws ;  Nic Laporte:: YouTube:: How Did This Become Vancouver’s Busiest Shortcut?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/26/p2345-broken-10th-avenue-rat-running-scene/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/26/p2345-broken-10th-avenue-rat-running-scene/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>“how many agents do you have running?” is 2026's tell me you are privileged without telling me you are privileged :-)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 27, 2026 04:44 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://devdilettante.com/@roland/116123712020175107&quot;&gt;“how many agents do you have running?” is 2026’s tell me you are privileged without telling me you are privileged :-)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;So 2026. I figure we’ll look back on 2026 in 2036 and laugh at the stupidity of it all! Either the AI winter will come or we’ll have a breakthrough before 2036 that makes these 2026 ‘AI’ things cringe :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;March 18, 2017: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2017/03/18/p1-When-is-the-ml-winter/&quot;&gt;When is the ML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/26/p2044-how-many-agents-shows-your-privilege-in-2026/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/26/p2044-how-many-agents-shows-your-privilege-in-2026/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Claude is so over :-) as if. It is so pre February 25, 2026 LOL . Haven't used Codex ; I have tried Claude Code super briefly. ; Manton Reece:: Developers who still use Claude are burning cash. Codex is good.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 25, 2026 20:32 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.manton.org/2026/02/25/ben-werdmuller-has-a-long.html&quot;&gt;ME:: Claude is so over :-) as if. It is so pre February 25, 2026 LOL . Haven’t used Codex ; I have tried Claude Code super briefly. ; Manton Reece:: Developers who still use Claude are burning cash. Codex is good.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/25/p1232-manton-reece-claude-is-over-codex-is-better-ben-werdmuller-has-a-long/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/25/p1232-manton-reece-claude-is-over-codex-is-better-ben-werdmuller-has-a-long/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fare thee well Kathykins</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://checkvist.com/p/MVg7Me1Z01Rz7KOTRFjBf1&quot;&gt;Draft&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/14/p0908-without-link-blogthis-linkless_blog_all_open/&quot;&gt;created&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 25, 2026 20:10 (UTC).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 2025 was way too soon to lose your amazing spirit!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/25/p1210-fare-thee-kathykins/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/25/p1210-fare-thee-kathykins/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing; Anybody who can write a spec i.e. a text file of requirements can create software with tests and you don't know have to know a programming language just how to write, it's expensive (although open source tools are improving quickly which will decrease costs) and super geeky because you have to configure lots of moving parts and not super great for large legacy codebases at the moment ; Anil Dash:: January 2026:: Codeless: From idea to software</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 25, 2026 15:28 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anildash.com/2026/01/22/codeless/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing; Anybody who can write a spec i.e. a text file of requirements can create software with tests and you don’t know have to know a programming language just how to write, it’s expensive (although open source tools are improving quickly which will decrease costs) and super geeky because you have to configure lots of moving parts and not super great for large legacy codebases at the moment ; Anil Dash:: January 2026:: Codeless: From idea to software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anildash.com/2026/01/22/codeless/&quot;&gt;Anil Dash:: January 2026:: Codeless: From idea to software&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a quick bullet-point summary, here’s something skimmable:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Codeless” is a way to describe a new way of orchestrating large numbers of AI coding bots to build software at scale, controlled by a plain-English strategic plan for the bots to follow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In this approach, you don’t write code directly. Instead, you write a plan for the end result or product that you want, and the system directs your bots to build code to deliver that product. (Codeless abstracts away directly writing code just like “serverless” abstracted away directly managing servers.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This codeless approach is credible because it emerged organically from influential coders who don’t work for the Big AI companies, and independent devs are already starting to make it easier and more approachable. It’s not a pitch from a big company trying to sell a product, and in fact, codeless tools make it easy to swap out one LLM for another.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Today, codeless tools themselves don’t cost anything. The systems are entirely open source, though setting them up can be complicated and take some time. Actually running enough bots to generate all that code gets expensive quickly if you use cutting-edge commercial LLMs, but mixing in some lower-cost open tools can help defray costs. We can also expect that, as this approach gains momentum, more polished paid versions of the tools will emerge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many coders didn’t like using LLMs to generate code because they hallucinate. Codeless systems assume that the code they generate will be broken sometimes, and handle that failure. Just like other resilient systems assume that hard drives will fail, or that network connections will be unreliable, codeless systems are designed to handle unreliable code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This has nothing to do with the “no code” hype from years ago, because it’s not locked-in to one commercial vendor or one proprietary platform. And codeless projects can be designed to output code that will run on any regular infrastructure, including your existing systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Codeless changes power dynamics. People and teams who adopt a codeless approach have the potential to build a lot more under their own control. And those codeless makers won’t necessarily have to ask for permission or resources in order to start creating. Putting this power in the hands of those individuals might have huge implications over time, as people realize that they may not have to raise funding or seek out sponsors to build the things that they imagine.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The management and creation interfaces for codeless systems are radically more accessible than many other platforms because they’re often controlled by simple plain text Markdown files. This means it’s likely that some of the most effective or successful codeless creators could end up being people who have had roles like product managers, designers, or systems architects, not just developers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Codeless approaches are probably not a great way to take over a big legacy codebase, since they rely on accurately describing an entire problem, which can often be difficult to completely capture. And coding bots may lack sufficient context to understand legacy codebases, especially since LLMs are sometimes weaker with legacy technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In many prior evolutions of coding, abstractions let coders work at higher levels, closer to the problem they were trying to solve. Low-level languages saved coders from having to write assembly language; high-level languages kept coders from having to write code to manage memory. Codeless systems abstract away directly writing code, continuing the long history of letting developers focus more on the problem to be solved than on manually creating every part of the code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/25/p0728-anildash-codeless-just-like-nobody-writes-in-assembler/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/25/p0728-anildash-codeless-just-like-nobody-writes-in-assembler/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: bring back the pre Reаgan/Thаtcher/Mulroney small c conservаtives, all the other 'conservаtives' are fаscists sad face ; Thomas Zimmer:: How Conservatives Gave Themselves Permission to Go MᗅGᗅ - Democracy Americana</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 24, 2026 15:39 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://steady.page/en/democracyamericana/posts/cc8aefed-942a-4d82-a2ee-65856400e889&quot;&gt;ME:: bring back the pre Reаgan/Thаtcher/Mulroney small c conservаtives, all the other ‘conservаtives’ are fаscists sad face ; Thomas Zimmer:: How Conservatives Gave Themselves Permission to Go MᗅGᗅ - Democracy Americana&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;For a political movement so constituted, the question has always been: Is there a limiting principle – or just a principled commitment that demands you do whatever it takes? Is there a line a “Modern Conservative” (as opposed to a small-c conservative) is not permitted to cross in the struggle against the forces of leftism, even if it meant accepting the liberalization and pluralization of American life? ...The answer the leaders of the modern Right have given themselves and us, over and over again, is: No, there is not.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/24/p0739-many-small-c-conservatives-became-fscists/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/24/p0739-many-small-c-conservatives-became-fscists/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: Because there is no payment deficit, the new 15% tariffs imposed by The Convicted Criminal are also illegal ; Thom Hogan:: Weekly News and Commentary for February 16 to 23 ¦ Cameras and Photography</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 24, 2026 07:52 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://bythom.com/newsviews/weekly-news-and-commentary-7.html&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: Because there is no payment deficit, the new 15% tariffs imposed by The Convicted Criminal are also illegal ; Thom Hogan:: Weekly News and Commentary for February 16 to 23 ¦ Cameras and Photography&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;So, two things about that: (1) Congress will have to act within 150 days to extend these new 15% tariffs, and that's unlikely in the current environment because it would happen just before the next election; and (2) the reasoning is once again problematic, and will likely get tested by the courts as once again exceeding the authority given by Congress. Section 122 doesn't actually refer to &quot;trade deficit&quot; it refers to &quot;payment deficit&quot;, of which the US has very little (the US heavily exports &quot;services&quot;, which balances out &quot;trade&quot;). In essence, we have an autocratic regime that can't read and has indicated that they will do what they want and keep trying to find some methodology that might make tariffs stick. In other words, businesses still have no idea what their costs are (and will be), as they keep fluctuating as the tariff battle continues. &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/23/p2352-thom-hogan-convicted-criminal-new-tariffs-illegal-because-no-payment-deficit/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/23/p2352-thom-hogan-convicted-criminal-new-tariffs-illegal-because-no-payment-deficit/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Reminder 88888888 that CSS + HTML is Turing complete on Chromium browsers, is this a bug or a feature :-) Could this work someday in Firefox ?!?!? ; Lyra Rebane:: x86CSS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 24, 2026 05:39 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://lyra.horse/x86css/&quot;&gt;ME:: Reminder 88888888 that CSS + HTML is Turing complete on Chromium browsers, is this a bug or a feature :-) Could this work someday in Firefox ?!?!? ; Lyra Rebane:: x86CSS&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;There is a script tag on this site, which is there to provide a clock to the CSS - but this is only there to make the entire thing a bit faster and more stable. The CSS also has a JS-less clock implementation, so if you disable scripts on this site, it will still run. JavaScript is not required.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/23/p2139-x86-in-turingcomplete-css/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/23/p2139-x86-in-turingcomplete-css/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing just like AIDS, COVID-19 doesn't have a sterilizing vaccine aka cure in 2026 ; Laurie Garrett, author of the 1994 Pulitzer Prize winning book, 'The Coming Plague', in Foreign Policy Magazine::  May 2023:: The COVID Public Health Emergency Is Over. What Does That Even Mean?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 24, 2026 00:58 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20230524123648/https://foreignpolicy.com/2023/05/09/pandemic-covid-who-epidemic-aids/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing just like AIDS, COVID-19 doesn’t have a sterilizing vaccine aka cure in 2026 ; Laurie Garrett, author of the 1994 Pulitzer Prize winning book, ‘The Coming Plague’, in Foreign Policy Magazine::  May 2023:: The COVID Public Health Emergency Is Over. What Does That Even Mean?&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– archive.is link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/oPoqC&quot;&gt;https://archive.is/oPoqC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20230524123648/https://foreignpolicy.com/2023/05/09/pandemic-covid-who-epidemic-aids/&quot;&gt;Laurie Garrett, author of the 1990s Pulitzer Prize winning book, the coming plague in May 2023:: The COVID Public Health Emergency Is Over. What Does That Even Mean?&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;lt;– archive.is link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/oPoqC&quot;&gt;https://archive.is/oPoqC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As was the case with AIDS, the muted victory now declared that COVID-19 was “won” with a tough mix of behavioral restrictions (less sex for AIDS, fewer crowded events for COVID-19), barriers (condoms/masks), drugs (antiretrovirals/antivirals) and “vaccines.” Dutch doctor Joep Lange famously declared some 20 years ago that anti-HIV drugs so effectively blocked transmission of the virus that treatment is prevention. Out of the limelight, in meetings with HIV research colleagues, Lange argued that the drugs, taken as prophylactics—dubbed PrEP—by sexually active individuals, were “vaccines,” as the medicines prevented most lasting infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And in practice, PrEP is now widely used to prevent HIV infection. But the drugs aren’t genuine vaccines, akin to measles immunization, for example, as they can’t be administered and boosted to provide lifelong protection against infection. Thus, the financial spigot must flow in perpetuity, and sexually active adults who fear their partners carry HIV, and drug users that share syringes, must take their PrEP assiduously and frequently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There is no AIDS cure, despite a handful of isolated cases of individuals treated with heroic measures to effectively clear HIV from their bodies. And there is no HIV vaccine.
We have followed the same path with COVID-19. The mRNA “vaccines” used by billions of people do not block COVID-19 infection or prevent the vaccinated individual from passing the virus on to others. Moreover, vaccine efficacy in preventing acute COVID-19 disease and death wanes within months, as the viral evolution process appears today to be primarily a natural selection phenomenon aimed at evading host immune systems. (Natural infection also provides very short-lived protection against future reinfections and severe disease.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 6, 2022: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/11/06/p1544-1589344554586886144/&quot;&gt;Laurie Garrett on Twitter: ‘There’s a cottage  industry is tearing apart the @ProPublica + @VanityFair ‘expose’ of the  origins of #SARSCoV2 – so many reports on the inaccuracies &amp;amp;  failures in the story, it seems hard to imagine more. But @janeqiuchina  is a Chinese-speaking writer, &amp;amp; this thread is intense.’ /  Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/23/p1658-laurie-garrett-pandemic-covid-just-like-aids-no-preventative-vaccine-yet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/23/p1658-laurie-garrett-pandemic-covid-just-like-aids-no-preventative-vaccine-yet/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: $3913/month for a 4 bedroom and $2556/month for a 2 bedroom is about 50% too much to be 'affordable'; Anthony Floyd on Bluesky:: Want to live in Vancouver's 2010 Olympic Village? There's a 2 bdrm and a 4 bdrm available in my building</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 23, 2026 16:08 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/did:plc:rokedkwde6uxqsmothcketwn/post/3mfa3folpzc25&quot;&gt;ME:: $3913/month for a 4 bedroom and $2556/month for a 2 bedroom is about 50% too much to be ‘affordable’; Anthony Floyd on Bluesky:: Want to live in Vancouver’s 2010 Olympic Village? There’s a 2 bdrm and a 4 bdrm available in my building&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/23/p0808-olympic-village-vancouver-rent-too-high-4br-4000-per-month-2br-2600/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/23/p0808-olympic-village-vancouver-rent-too-high-4br-4000-per-month-2br-2600/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
