<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 17:24:33 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 17:24:33 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Saving for future reference. I have met Doug! Inspiring person! READ:: What is digital literacy? A Pragmatic investigation. A thesis submitted in 2011 to the Department of Education at Durham University by Douglas Alan Jonathan Belshaw for the degree of Doctor of Education (Ed.D.)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Apr 20, 2025 07:52 &lt;a href=&quot;https://dougbelshaw.com/doug-belshaw-edd-thesis-final.pdf&quot;&gt;ME:: Saving for future reference. I have met Doug! Inspiring person! READ:: What is digital literacy? A Pragmatic investigation. A thesis submitted in 2011 to the Department of Education at Durham University by Douglas Alan Jonathan Belshaw for the degree of Doctor of Education (Ed.D.)&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– It’s only 200 plus pages :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/20/p0752-doug-belshaw-edd-thesis-final/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/20/p0752-doug-belshaw-edd-thesis-final/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Also because measles, RSV and other things that could be prevented if we as a society cared about public health ; READ Nicholas Russell:: Why I Keep Masking | Defector</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Apr 20, 2025 07:27 &lt;a href=&quot;https://defector.com/why-i-keep-masking&quot;&gt;ME:: Also because measles, RSV and other things that could be prevented if we as a society cared about public health ; READ Nicholas Russell:: Why I Keep Masking ¦ Defector&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://defector.com/why-i-keep-masking&quot;&gt;Nicholas Russell:: Why I Keep Masking ¦ Defector&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Masking is a reminder that I share a bustling, contradictory world with other people who deserve some assurance that their health, and my own, isn’t taken for granted. So maybe it is a symbol after all. A lasting existential consequence of pandemic fatigue is capitulation to the sentiment that there are some people who deserve to get sick, who deserve to die. At every turn, we must reject this idea as insidious, pernicious, and unforgivable. There are graceful gestures we can offer one another, no matter if we deserve them. Masking will remain a lifelong baseline priority for me for this lofty reason, among more practical considerations. Make no mistake, it would be more convenient if I never had to again. I don’t cling to my boxes of N95s and often dread wearing them for long periods of time. But in the grand scheme, it’s a small thing, and worth doing.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/20/p0727-why-i-keep-masking/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/20/p0727-why-i-keep-masking/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Everybody is technical in multiple areas no matter what the gatekeepers say :-) ; READ:: Cat Hicks:: Why I Cannot Be Technical</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Apr 18, 2025 18:32 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fightforthehuman.com/why-i-cannot-be-technical/&quot;&gt;ME:: Everybody is technical in multiple areas no matter what the gatekeepers say :-) ; READ:: Cat Hicks:: Why I Cannot Be Technical&lt;/a&gt; and subscribe to Cat’s newsletter: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fightforthehuman.com/about/#/portal/&quot;&gt;Fight for the Human&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;lt;- Bravo, read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fightforthehuman.com/why-i-cannot-be-technical/&quot;&gt;Cat Hicks:: Why I Cannot Be Technical&lt;/a&gt; Juicy &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The Technical needs to exclude women in daycares, women in cafes, women in grocery stores and now even women in labs in order to continue its own existence. It needs to be separate from all other areas of work in order to get different rules for itself. After all, objects do not suffer. There is a very direct connection between explaining the experiences of the people I care about in tech and explaining to the people in tech about the people I care about. And because of who I am and who I love, I cannot be Technical here and now for the exact same reasons that I could not be smart back when I was fifteen and working instead of going to school no matter how obvious the proof of smartness was. In some systems otherness causes smartness to dissolve because otherness is more useful to the system than the smartness. It is therefore not very difficult for me in this system to understand why software looks at me and gets surprised when I know what code is, and then gets angry when I don’t care about code all that much and instead care about the people so much more. Caring about the code is supposed to be what you do to earn being here and I refuse that. I cannot be Technical because I put my caring, my hope, my love, and the center of my universe somewhere else.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/18/p1832-why-i-cannot-be-technical/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/18/p1832-why-i-cannot-be-technical/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Twitter-like systems are harmful for the web because there's no links, character limits, etc ; READ Coyote:: Twitterlike is a Bad Shape</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Apr 18, 2025 01:13 &lt;a href=&quot;https://osteophage.neocities.org/essays/twitterlike&quot;&gt;ME:: Twitter-like systems are harmful for the web because there’s no links, character limits, etc ; READ Coyote:: Twitterlike is a Bad Shape&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/2025/04/17.html#a144359&quot;&gt;Dave on scripting.com&lt;/a&gt; –&amp;gt; Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://osteophage.neocities.org/essays/twitterlike&quot;&gt;Coyote:: Twitterlike is a Bad Shape&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Twitter and its imitators have adopted a structural design that is fundamentally bad for people. This isn't just a matter of who's in charge; it's a problem with the thing itself. Forcing users to adhere to a tight character limit, discouraging link culture, preventing people from editing their own posts, steering people into sharing things they hate, incentivizing rage bait with trending feeds, subjecting people to decontextualized encounters, encouraging conflict by discouraging tags, and leaving users powerless to clean up the resulting mess—all of this is bad shape. &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/18/p0113-twitterlike/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/18/p0113-twitterlike/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Keep an eye on ActivityPub + OCap the universe that could have been and could still be ; READ BlueSky Proposal from 2019 pre 2025 Bluesky débacle:: Bluesky proposal submitted by Christine Lemmer-Webber and Jay Graber, 2020-07-29 ($2535398) · Snippets · GitLab</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Apr 18, 2025 00:42 &lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.com/-/snippets/2535398&quot;&gt;ME:: Keep an eye on ActivityPub + OCap the universe that could have been and could still be ; READ BlueSky Proposal from 2019 pre 2025 Bluesky débacle:: Bluesky proposal submitted by Christine Lemmer-Webber and Jay Graber, 2020-07-29 ($2535398) · Snippets · GitLab&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;by Christine Lemmer-Webber and Jay Graber, 2020-07-29 ... ActivityPub is a federated social network protocol published by the W3C. The ActivityPub network consists of millions of users, and is implemented across a large number and variety of applications. The core concepts and extension mechanism of ActivityPub are summarized in the ecosystem overview. Advantages of ActivityPub include a conceptual foundation that follows the actor model (with pubsub layered on top), and a flexible spec which supports extensions. However, ActivityPub as currently deployed falls short on some desirable qualities, such as decentralized storage and identity. Research into evolving ActivityPub has been in progress under the Spritely project and the OcapPub writeup. This document explains how the objects/actor model of ActivityPub could be further decentralized, and with the addition of object capabilities (OCap), could enable better moderation, payment, and collaboration mechanisms. The object capability design direction provides a foundation from which unanticipated use cases can be met, whether that future involves economic uses, business communication integration, or distributed virtual worlds.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-cool-stuff-from-christine-lemmer-webber-on-mastodon&quot;&gt;More Cool Stuff from Christine Lemmer-Webber on Mastodon&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://social.coop/@cwebber/114352019414577407&quot;&gt;If you keep thinking ‘wow, Christine keeps being right in retrospect’ You can get in early on smug correctness by paying attention: the work we are doing at @spritely is the future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://social.coop/@cwebber/114352795295444542&quot;&gt;@laurenshof @spritely It’s not instance-oriented in the way the fediverse is, and with OCapN, is more p2p&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To learn more: just follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://social.coop/@spritely&quot;&gt;@spritely&lt;/a&gt; and support them at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://spritely.institute/donate/&quot;&gt;spritely.institute/donate/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/18/p0042-christine-lemmer-webber-spritely-ocap-activity-pub-more-p2p/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/18/p0042-christine-lemmer-webber-spritely-ocap-activity-pub-more-p2p/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: To define much of white America as self-deluded on the commitment to equality and to apprehend the broad base on which it rests are not to enthrone pessimism. The racism of today is real, but the democratic spirit that has always faced it is equally real&lt;- 'Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?', 1967.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drmartinlutherkingjr.com/drking/mlk-quotes/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: “To define much of white America as self-deluded on the commitment to equality and to apprehend the broad base on which it rests are not to enthrone pessimism. The racism of today is real, but the democratic spirit that has always faced it is equally real.” 
&amp;lt;- “Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?”, 1967.&lt;/a&gt; 
&amp;lt;– Read the book –&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Where_Do_We_Go_from_Here:_Chaos_or_Community&quot;&gt;‘Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?’, 1967, wiki page&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;lt;– 2025 seems to be 1967 all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 20, 2025 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/20/p0713-mlk-quotes/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: Darkness cannot drive out darkness; only light can do that. Hate cannot drive out hate; only love can do that.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/15/p1042-mlk-whte-amrica-self-deluded-commitment-equality-not-enthrone-pessimism-racism-today-real-democratic-spirit-facing-it-equally-real/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/15/p1042-mlk-whte-amrica-self-deluded-commitment-equality-not-enthrone-pessimism-racism-today-real-democratic-spirit-facing-it-equally-real/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: There is a double standard in the enforcement of law, a double standard in the respect for particular laws. &lt;- 'Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?', 1967.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drmartinlutherkingjr.com/drking/mlk-quotes/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: “There is a double standard in the enforcement of law, a double standard in the respect for particular laws.” 
&amp;lt;- “Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?”, 1967.&lt;/a&gt; 
&amp;lt;– Read the book –&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Where_Do_We_Go_from_Here:_Chaos_or_Community&quot;&gt;‘Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community?’, 1967, wiki page&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;lt;– 2025 seems to be 1967 all over again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 20, 2025 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/20/p0713-mlk-quotes/&quot;&gt;Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.:: Darkness cannot drive out darkness; only light can do that. Hate cannot drive out hate; only love can do that.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/14/p2012-mlk-double-standard-law-enforcement-respect-for-laws/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/14/p2012-mlk-double-standard-law-enforcement-respect-for-laws/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: We're not the problem, the system is but how do we fix it, I don't know?!? Universal Basic Income?!?? ; READ:: Greg Storey:: LinkedIn is a waiting room of doom: 'It's time to wake the zombies'</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Apr 13, 2025 15:19 &lt;a href=&quot;https://brilliantcrank.com/linkedin-is-a-waiting-room-of-doom/&quot;&gt;ME:: We’re not the problem, the system is but how do we fix it, I don’t know?!? Universal Basic Income?!?? ; READ:: Greg Storey:: LinkedIn is a waiting room of doom: ‘It’s time to wake the zombies’&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Far easier said than done :-) &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Because that’s what we’ve been trained to do: look hirable. Be valuable. Not human. .... If you’re reading this while doom scrolling, somewhere between your 200th application and your fourth coffee, I’m not going to tell you to keep grinding. ... I’m just going to say:  You’re not alone. You’re not imagining it. And you’re not the problem. This system was built to extract your ambition and sell it back to you in monthly installments. The sooner we stop playing along, the sooner something else becomes possible. ....It's time to wake the zombies.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/13/p1519-linkedin-is-a-waiting-room-of-doom/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/13/p1519-linkedin-is-a-waiting-room-of-doom/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: YES... The thing about The Economist is that's it's full of mansplaining Oxbrᜁdge folks who are not calling out the rᜀcism and lᜁes of the current administration of the ӮSA and RЭpublicans in general since Reᜀgan AND... they are right that Europe is the actual land of the free now :-) AND of course the European model is sustainable if you think beyond your narrow worldview :-)  ; READ:: The Economist:: The thing about Europe: it’s the actual land of the free now</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Apr 12, 2025 14:45 &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/i0gpo#selection-1133.0-1133.60&quot;&gt;ME:: YES… The thing about The Economist is that’s it’s full of mansplaining Oxbrᜁdge folks who are not calling out the rᜀcism and lᜁes of the current administration of the ӮSA and RЭpublicans in general since Reᜀgan AND… they are right that Europe is the actual land of the free now :-) AND of course the European model is sustainable if you think beyond your narrow worldview :-)  ; READ:: The Economist:: The thing about Europe: it’s the actual land of the free now&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The thing about Europe is that it is like an open-air museum, yesterday’s continent. Is its model even sustainable? A good question—one that presupposes the European model is worth defending. It is a place blessed with walkable cities, long life expectancies and vaccinated kids who do not need to be trained to dodge school shooters. Charlemagne’s realm is a place of many flaws, lots of them enduring. But in their own plodding way, Europeans have created a place where they are guaranteed rights to what others yearn for: life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.&lt;/code&gt; (‘ᜀ’ is Tagalog ‘a’ and ‘ᜁ’ is Tagalog ‘i’ and ‘Ӯ’ is ‘U’ in the Cyrillic alphabet since you know who is a Russian asset)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/12/p1445-the-economist-is-right-europe-actual-land-of-the-free/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/12/p1445-the-economist-is-right-europe-actual-land-of-the-free/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: There is a world where a truly excellent User Experience for Mastodon and Matrix and other open decentralized networks is funded just like Bluesky and Slack are funded ; READ and LISTEN:: Ethan Zuckerman and Nathan Schneider:: 110. Is there hope for democracy in a social media-driven world? Nathan Schneider sees it every day. - Initiative for Digital Public Infrastructure at UMass Amherst</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Apr 10, 2025 07:11 &lt;a href=&quot;https://publicinfrastructure.org/podcast/110-nathan-schneider-governable-spaces/&quot;&gt;ME:: There is a world where a truly excellent User Experience for Mastodon and Matrix and other open decentralized networks is funded just like Bluesky and Slack are funded ; READ and LISTEN:: Ethan Zuckerman and Nathan Schneider:: 110. Is there hope for democracy in a social media-driven world? Nathan Schneider sees it every day. - Initiative for Digital Public Infrastructure at UMass Amherst&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;As much as the (Bluyesky) team talks about trying to make their platform billionaire-proof, it’s really not quite built that way. And the Fediverse, Mastodon and related apps offer this opportunity to really turn toward a network that is not captureable. But this is a network whose total expenditure, whose total investment in technology is like what, around a million dollars a year in that kind of order of magnitude compared to companies that are running on billions. &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/10/p0711-110-me-open-decentralized-can-be-usable-government-funding-nathan-schneider-governable-spaces/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/04/10/p0711-110-me-open-decentralized-can-be-usable-government-funding-nathan-schneider-governable-spaces/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
