<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 20:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 20:05:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: And so it begins go Firefox for Enterprise go :-) ! I was involved in the last Firefox Enterprise effort 2018-2020 and it didn't go anywhere; hopefully it will go further this time! ; Brian Smith:: Introducing early access for Firefox Support for Organizations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 18:25 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/en/firefox/firefox-support-for-organizations/&quot;&gt;ME:: And so it begins go Firefox for Enterprise go :-) ! I was involved in the last Firefox Enterprise effort 2018-2020 and it didn’t go anywhere; hopefully it will go further this time! ; Brian Smith:: Introducing early access for Firefox Support for Organizations&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Multiple Firefox logos forming a curved trail on a dark background. ... Increasingly, businesses, schools, and government institutions deploy Firefox at scale for security, resilience, and data sovereignty. Organizations have fine-grained administrative and orchestration control of the browser’s behavior using policies with Firefox and the Extended Support Release (ESR). Today, we’re opening early access to Firefox Support for Organizations, a new program that begins operation in January 2026.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1025-firefox-support-for-organizations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1025-firefox-support-for-organizations/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI by an AI maximalist who seems more reasonable than most of them. Daniel Miessler:: February 2024:: Why I Created Fabric</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 18:22 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://danielmiessler.com/blog/fabric-origin-story&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI by an AI maximalist who seems more reasonable than most of them. Daniel Miessler:: February 2024:: Why I Created Fabric&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI. ...The goal of the project is to provide a universally accessible layer of AI that anyone can use to enhance their life or work. &lt;/code&gt;`&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1022-fabric-origin-story/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1022-fabric-origin-story/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: clearly we know nothing about minds :-) ; Norman, Johnson, van er Linden:: 2024:: Do Minds Have Immune systems?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 18:14 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/fulltext/2025-55535-001.pdf&quot;&gt;ME:: clearly we know nothing about minds :-) ; Norman, Johnson, van er Linden:: 2024:: Do Minds Have Immune systems?&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;:: Do minds have immune systems? In this article, we remove several obstacles to treatingthe question in a rigorously scientific way. After giving the hypothesis that minds do have such subsystems a name—we call it mental immune systems theory—we show why it merits serious consideration. The issue hinges on our definition of an immune system, so we examine the definition that currently prevails, demonstrate its shortcomings, and offer an alternative that addresses those shortcomings. We then lay out the empirical evidence that minds really do have immune systems in the specified sense. Findings about psychological inoculation, identity-protective cognition, cognitive dissonance, psycho-logical reactance, information diffusion, and cognitive bias all point to the existence of evolved cognitive defenses—informational “immune systems” that function in much the way that bodily immune systems do. Finally, we discuss the prospects of cognitive immunology, a research program that (a) posits mental immune systems and (b) proceeds to investigate their functioning`&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1014-2025-55535-001/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1014-2025-55535-001/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: so many free LUTs to try on the S9 and in Pearla and not boring iOS Camera Apps so little time :-) l  KROLOP und GERST:: Lumix S5II LUT Package</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 18:10 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://krolop-gerst.com/product/lumix-s5ii-lut-package/&quot;&gt;ME:: so many free LUTs to try on the S9 and in Pearla and not boring iOS Camera Apps so little time :-) l  KROLOP und GERST:: Lumix S5II LUT Package&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Mit dem Erscheinen der S5II von Panasonic ist eine neue Ära in Sachen JPG-Fotografie angebrochen. So hoffen wir zumindest. Als erste Kamera kann sie LUTs nicht nur zur Hilfsansicht nutzen, sondern auch den geladenen Look direkt ins JPG speichern. Es ist einfach irre, was sich daraus für Möglichkeiten für die eigene Fotografie ergeben. Ganz besondere Looks ohne Bearbeitung direkt aus der Kamera!... Achtung: Diese LUTs sind speziell für die Lumix S5II in Kombination mit flachem Bildstil („flat“) entwickelt. Heißt, sie sind nicht (wie auch andere Presets, Bildlooks, etc.) 1:1 auf andere Kameras bzw. Stile zu übertragen. Und natürlich passt nicht jedes LUT zur jeder fotografischen Situation. Ein gewisses Gespür entwickelt man aber sehr schnell und lädt definitiv dazu ein, sehr bewusst zu fotografieren!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1010-lumix-s5ii-lut-package/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1010-lumix-s5ii-lut-package/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tidyplots in R looks easier and better for non software developers and software developers than Hadley's older ggplot2. Perhaps use it for art and SUMO data?!?! ; Jan Broder Engler:: Get started • tidyplots</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 18:07 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://jbengler.github.io/tidyplots/articles/tidyplots.html&quot;&gt;ME:: tidyplots in R looks easier and better for non software developers and software developers than Hadley’s older ggplot2. Perhaps use it for art and SUMO data?!?! ; Jan Broder Engler:: Get started • tidyplots&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;This getting started guide aims to empower individuals without a programming background to engage in code-based plotting with tidyplots. We will start by covering essential software tools and discussing data preparation. Next, we will introduce the tidyplots workflow, which includes adding, removing, and adjusting plot components. Finally, we will showcase the application of themes and multiplot layouts.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1007-tidyplots/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1007-tidyplots/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Seems to me like fancy bidirectional database open source schema converters?!? That can be used to solve the ATProto Lexicon Interop problem among others. What am I missing?!? From 2020, what's the update in 2025?!? Geoffrey Litt, Peter van Hardenberg, Orion Henry:: Ink and Switch:: October 2020:: Project Cambria: Translate your data with lenses</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 17:58 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inkandswitch.com/cambria/&quot;&gt;ME:: Seems to me like fancy bidirectional database open source schema converters?!? That can be used to solve the ATProto Lexicon Interop problem among others. What am I missing?!? From 2020, what’s the update in 2025?!? Geoffrey Litt, Peter van Hardenberg, Orion Henry:: Ink and Switch:: October 2020:: Project Cambria: Translate your data with lenses&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;–  See also Anuj’s post from September 2025:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://augment.leaflet.pub/3lxxnzrh6pc24&quot;&gt;The Lexicon Interop Problem Competing AT platforms are using different lexicons. Should we be worried?&lt;/a&gt; and Noel De Martin’s 2021 post:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://noeldemartin.com/blog/interoperable-serendipity&quot;&gt;Interoperable Serendipity&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;We propose a principled replacement for these messy solutions: an isolated software layer that translates data between schemas on demand. This layer allows developers to maintain strong compatibility with many schema versions without complicating the main codebase. Translation logic is defined by composing bidirectional lenses, a kind of data transformation that can run both forward and backward.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0958-cambria/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0958-cambria/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Ollama is something worth looking into in my copious free time :-) i also need a 64GB RAM computer if I want to run local models it seems still! ; Ivan Palomares Carrascosa:: March 11, 2025:: The Beginner's Guide to Language Models with Python</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 17:55 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://machinelearningmastery.com/the-beginners-guide-to-language-models-with-python/&quot;&gt;ME:: Ollama is something worth looking into in my copious free time :-) i also need a 64GB RAM computer if I want to run local models it seems still! ; Ivan Palomares Carrascosa:: March 11, 2025:: The Beginner’s Guide to Language Models with Python&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ollama is a framework that enables running language models locally in a streamlined and efficient way. For example, one of its available models is Qwen, which is a versatile open-source LLM capable of generating human-like text.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0955-the-beginners-guide-to-language-models-with-python/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0955-the-beginners-guide-to-language-models-with-python/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: I guess I should try the $20/month stuff?!!? I don't really want to though LOL ; Ethan Mollick:: October 19, 2025:: An Opinionated Guide to Using AI Right Now</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 17:51 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oneusefulthing.org/p/an-opinionated-guide-to-using-ai&quot;&gt;ME:: I guess I should try the $20/month stuff?!!? I don’t really want to though LOL ; Ethan Mollick:: October 19, 2025:: An Opinionated Guide to Using AI Right Now&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;If you want to use an advanced AI seriously, you’ll need to pay either $20 or around $200 a month, depending on your needs (though companies are now experimenting with other pricing models in some parts of the world). The $20 tier works for the vast majority of people, while the $200 tier is for people with complex technical and coding needs. ... You will want to pick among three systems to spend your $20: Claude from Anthropic, Google’s Gemini, and OpenAI’s ChatGPT. With all of the options, you get access to advanced, agentic, and fast models, a voice mode, the ability to see images and documents, the ability to execute code, good mobile apps, the ability to create images and video (Claude lacks here, however), and the ability to do Deep Research. They all have different personalities and strengths and weaknesses, but for most people, just selecting the one they like best will suffice. Some people, especially big users of X, might want to consider Grok by Elon Musk’s xAI, which has some of the most powerful AI models and is rapidly adding features, but has not been as transparent about product safety as some of the other companies. Microsoft’s Copilot offers many of the features of ChatGPT and is accessible to users through Windows, but it can be hard to control what models you are using and when. So, for most people, just stick with Gemini, Claude, or ChatGPT.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0951-an-opinionated-guide-to-using-ai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0951-an-opinionated-guide-to-using-ai/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: I wonder how much further Paolo has taken this since June?!? Paolo Valdemarin:: June 13, 2025:: Building a WordPress MCP Server for Claude: Automating Blog Posts with AI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 17:48 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://val.demar.in/2025/06/building-a-wordpress-mcp-server-for-claude-automating-blog-posts-with-ai/&quot;&gt;ME:: I wonder how much further Paolo has taken this since June?!? Paolo Valdemarin:: June 13, 2025:: Building a WordPress MCP Server for Claude: Automating Blog Posts with AI&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Building a custom MCP server to connect Claude directly to WordPress, enabling automated blog post creation with proper formatting and intelligent categorisation.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0948-building-a-wordpress-mcp-server-for-claude-automating-blog-posts-with-ai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0948-building-a-wordpress-mcp-server-for-claude-automating-blog-posts-with-ai/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Need to explore Flame Graphs for support data and need to read the The Flame Graph ACM Paper ; Brendan Gregg:: Flame Graphs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 17:42 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brendangregg.com/flamegraphs.html&quot;&gt;ME:: Need to explore Flame Graphs for support data and need to read the The Flame Graph ACM Paper ; Brendan Gregg:: Flame Graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gotta read the original ACMQ paper: &lt;a href=&quot;https://queue.acm.org/detail.cfm?id=2927301&quot;&gt;The Flame Graph&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brendangregg.com/flamegraphs.html&quot;&gt;Brendan Gregg:: Flame Graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The x-axis shows the stack profile population, sorted alphabetically (it is not the passage of time), and the y-axis shows stack depth, counting from zero at the bottom. Each rectangle represents a stack frame. The wider a frame is is, the more often it was present in the stacks. The top edge shows what is on-CPU, and beneath it is its ancestry. Original flame graphs use random colors to help visually differentiate adjacent frames. Variations include inverting the y-axis (an “icicle graph”), changing the hue to indicate code type, and using a color spectrum to convey an additional dimension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Flame graphs are both a static and dynamic visualization. As a static visualization, a flame graph can be saved as an image, included in print (books), and will still convey the “big picture” as only the most frequent frames have enough width for labels. A dynamic visualization allows interactive features to aid navigation and comprehension, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Mouse hover shows additional frame details in a status bar.
   Mouse click zooms the visualization horizontally, revealing function names previously elided.
   Search matches and highlights a given term and shows the “cumulative percentage” of stacks including the search term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This visualization is fully explained in my ACMQ article &lt;a href=&quot;https://queue.acm.org/detail.cfm?id=2927301&quot;&gt;The Flame Graph&lt;/a&gt;, also published in Communications of the ACM, Vol. 59 No. 6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0942-flamegraphs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p0942-flamegraphs/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
