<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 20:55:16 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 20:55:16 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to use SQLite to search all the Firefox and Thunderbird kb articles including the HTML (sadly Markdown not available)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using datasette lite, load the CSV files.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lite.datasette.io/?csv=https%3A%2F%2Fraw.githubusercontent.com%2Frtanglao%2Frt-kits-tb-api%2Fmain%2Fdetails-firefox-kb-title-slug-all-articles.csv#/data/details-firefox-kb-title-slug-all-articles&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;: Load &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kits-tb-api/blob/main/details-firefox-kb-title-slug-all-articles.csv&quot;&gt;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kits-tb-api/blob/main/details-firefox-kb-title-slug-all-articles.csv&lt;/a&gt; into datasette lite&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lite.datasette.io/?csv=https%3A%2F%2Fraw.githubusercontent.com%2Frtanglao%2Frt-kits-tb-api%2Fmain%2Fdetails-thunderbird-kb-title-slug-all-articles.csv&quot;&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt;: Load &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kits-tb-api/blob/main/details-thunderbird-kb-title-slug-all-articles.csv&quot;&gt;details-thunderbird-kb-title-slug-all-articles.csv&lt;/a&gt; into datasette lite&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May 8, 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/05/08/p1-query-my-firefox-201-sumo-support-data-from-your-web-browser-mobile-desktop-no-server-no-app-required/&quot;&gt;Thanks  to Simon Willison’s lite.datasette.io you can now query any SQLite data  with CORS headers anywhere and share the query URL with others so it  can spread virally :-)!  (e.g. 2021 Firefox SUMO Support questions) on  any web browser including desktop, iOS and Android&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/06/06/p1-howto-sqlite-search-all-thunderbird-firefox-sumo-knowledge-base-articles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/06/06/p1-howto-sqlite-search-all-thunderbird-firefox-sumo-knowledge-base-articles/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ChatGPT and other 'AI' models representational bias: misrepresentation, underrepresentation and overrepresentation; extrinsic harms: representational, performance disparities from 'On the Opportunities and Risks of Foundation Models' (2021) </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;via Ulrike Hahn’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://fediscience.org/@UlrikeHahn/110407268640707229&quot;&gt;toot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;@baldur academics, ie non AI vendors, are saying the same things
though when it comes to LLMs.
We simultaneously know exactly what they do and don’t really…
that’s not just a matter of documentation desire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following paper was written in 2021. It’s 2023! Have we made any progress since then regarding: “representational bias: misrepresentation, underrepresentation and overreprsentation; extrinsic harms: representational, performance disparities”?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here’s some juicy quotes from the 161 page paper (plus many pages of references!). Read the whole thing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2108.07258.pdf&quot;&gt;On the Opportunities and Risks of Foundation Models (2021)&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://fsi.stanford.edu/publication/opportunities-and-risks-foundation-models&quot;&gt;overview&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
This report investigates an emerging paradigm for building artificial intelligence (AI) systems
based on a general class of models which we term foundation models. A foundation model is any
model that is trained on broad data (generally using self-supervision at scale) that can be adapted
(e.g., fine-tuned) to a wide range of downstream tasks; current examples include BERT [Devlin et al .
2019], GPT-3 [Brown et al . 2020], and CLIP [Radford et al . 2021]. From a technological point of view,
foundation models are not new — they are based on deep neural networks and self-supervised
learning, both of which have existed for decades. However, the sheer scale and scope of foundation
models from the last few years have stretched our imagination of what is possible; 
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;…page 131&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intrinsic biases&lt;/strong&gt;. Properties of the foundation model can lead to harm in downstream systems.
As a result, these intrinsic biases can be measured directly within the foundation model, though
the harm itself is only realized when the foundation model is adapted, and thereafter applied,
i.e., these are latent biases or harms [DeCamp and Lindvall 2020]. We focus on the most widely
studied form of intrinsic bias, &lt;strong&gt;representational bias&lt;/strong&gt;, specifically considering &lt;strong&gt;misrepresentation&lt;/strong&gt;,
&lt;strong&gt;underrepresentation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;overrepresentation&lt;/strong&gt;. People can be misrepresented by pernicious stereo-
types [Bolukbasi et al . 2016; Caliskan et al . 2017; Abid et al . 2021; Nadeem et al . 2021; Gehman et al .
2020] or negative attitudes [Hutchinson et al . 2020], which can propagate through downstream
models to reinforce this misrepresentation in society [Noble 2018; Benjamin 2019]. People can be
underrepresented or entirely erased, e.g., when LGBTQ+ identity terms [Strengers et al. 2020;
Oliva et al. 2021; Tomasev et al. 2021] or data describing African Americans [Buolamwini and Gebru
2018; Koenecke et al. 2020; Blodgett and O’Connor 2017] is excluded in training data, downstream
models will struggle with similar data at test-time. People can be overrepresented, e.g., BERT
appears to encode an Anglocentric perspective [Zhou et al. 2021a] by default, which can amplify
majority voices and contribute to homogenization of perspectives [Creel and Hellman 2021] or
monoculture [Kleinberg and Raghavan 2021] (§5.6: ethics). &lt;strong&gt;These representational biases pertain to&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;all AI systems, but their significance is greatly heightened in the foundation model paradigm.&lt;/strong&gt; Since
the same foundation model serves as the basis for myriad applications, biases in the representation
of people propagate to many applications and settings. Further, since the foundation model does
much of the heavy-lifting (compared to adaptation, which is generally intended to be lightweight),
we anticipate that many of the experienced harms will be significantly determined by the internal
properties of the foundation model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extrinsic harms&lt;/strong&gt;. Users can experience specific harms from the downstream applications that are
created by adapting a foundation model. These harms can be &lt;strong&gt;representational&lt;/strong&gt; [Barocas et al. 2017;
Crawford 2017; Blodgett et al . 2020], such as the sexualized depictions of black women produced by
information retrieval systems [Noble 2018], the misgendering of persons by machine translation
systems that default to male pronouns [Schiebinger 2013, 2014], or the generation of pernicious
stereotypes [Nozza et al . 2021; Sheng et al. 2019; Abid et al. 2021]. They can consist of &lt;strong&gt;abuse&lt;/strong&gt;, such
as when dialogue agents based on foundation models attack users with toxic content [Dinan et al.
2021; Gehman et al . 2020] or microaggressions [Breitfeller et al . 2019; Jurgens et al . 2019]. All of
these user-facing behaviors can lead to psychological harms or the reinforcement of pernicious
stereotypes [Spencer et al. 2016; Williams 2020].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In addition to harms experienced by individuals, groups or sub-populations may also be subject
to harms such as &lt;strong&gt;group-level performance disparities&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, systems may perform poorly
on text or speech in African American English [Blodgett and O’Connor 2017; Koenecke et al . 2020],
incorrectly detect medical conditions from clinical notes for racial, gender, and insurance-status
minority groups [Zhang et al . 2020b], or fail to detect the faces of people with darker skin tones
[Wilson et al . 2019; Buolamwini and Gebru 2018]. As foundation models are more pervasively
applied, including in high-stakes domains, these disparities can spiral into further, and more severe,
harms. Koenecke et al . [2020] discuss how if African American English speakers cannot reliably
use speech recognition technologies (e.g., due to inequities in underlying foundation models), this
may mean they cannot benefit from certain derivative products (e.g., voice assistants, assistive
technologies) and will be disadvantaged if these technologies are used to conduct interviews for
employment or transcribe courtroom proceedings. More generally, characterizing these group-level
harms (and working towards justice for those harmed) also requires the AI community to improve
its understanding of group-based prejudice [Allport 1954] and social groups: we point to relevant
work in the social sciences and other communities on moving beyond binary treatments of gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 9, 2023: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/09/p3-simon-wilison-chatgpt-lies-so-how-can-we-trust-it/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison: ChatGPT lies. Me: so how can we trust its output to truly be helpful even if we are experts in the domain of discourse? And therefore know how to fact check it?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/05/21/p1-intrinsic-biases-extrinsic-harms-foundation-ai-models/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/05/21/p1-intrinsic-biases-extrinsic-harms-foundation-ai-models/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leonid Rozenblit and Frank Keil: The misunderstood limits of folk science: an illusion of explanatory depth: Expertise takes time and energy and feedbadk otherwise we suffer the: illusion of explanatory depth (IOED)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Strong opinions should be very loosely held if you are not an expert and beware of those who think they are experts on everything just because they “read it” and or did their “research”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;via Erin Kissane’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://mstdn.social/@kissane/110334250073288994&quot;&gt;toot&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;file under “things I can’t stop thinking about”
The misunderstood limits of folk science: an illusion of explanatory depth&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We argue here that people’s limited knowledge and their misleading intuitive epistemology combine to create 
an illusion of explanatory depth (IOED). Most people feel they understand the world with far greater detail, coherence,
and depth than they really do. The illusion for explanatory knowledge–knowledge that involves complex causal patterns—is separate from, and
additive with, people’s general overconfidence about their knowledge and skills. We therefore propose that knowledge of complex causal relations is
particularly susceptible to illusions of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Please read the whole thing! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3062901/&quot;&gt;The misunderstood limits of folk science: an illusion of explanatory depth
Leonid Rozenblit and Frank Keil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;September 14, 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2019/09/14/p1-true-experts-are-authors-who-can-write-it-down-and-explain-it-to-others/&quot;&gt;True experts are authors i.e. they can write down explanations and explain it to non experts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/05/12/p1-illusion-explanatory-depth/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/05/12/p1-illusion-explanatory-depth/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WSL systemd kluge no longer needed in Windows 11 because systemd is built-in</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The WSL systemd &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-making-wsl-and-windows-work-for-me#19september2021-systemctl&quot;&gt;kluge&lt;/a&gt; is no longer needed so &lt;strong&gt;un-install&lt;/strong&gt; it. Then, enable systemd by following &lt;a href=&quot;https://devblogs.microsoft.com/commandline/systemd-support-is-now-available-in-wsl/&quot;&gt;Microsoft’s instructions&lt;/a&gt;
tl;dr: add the following lines to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/etc/wsl.conf&lt;/code&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;[boot]
systemd=true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;and then &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wsl.exe --shutdown&lt;/code&gt; from powershell
and then install &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bottle imp&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arkane-systems/bottle-imp&quot;&gt;https://github.com/arkane-systems/bottle-imp&lt;/a&gt; and then done :-)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;September 19, 2021 &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-making-wsl-and-windows-work-for-me#19september2021-systemctl&quot;&gt;19september2021 systemctl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/16/p2-systemd-part-of-wsl-window11/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/16/p2-systemd-part-of-wsl-window11/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>May Wong:The Myth of Maintenance Mode:We don’t build organizations that support the culture of maintenance...I wonder if this is also why Support is chronically undervalued and underfunded.</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pwords.substack.com/p/the-myth-of-maintenance-mode&quot;&gt;The Myth of Maintenance Mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your Support team has also been cobbling together a product lifetime’s worth of workarounds to make the product keep working, and now these might break your new fix as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We don’t build organizations that support the culture of maintenance, and therefore it isn’t work that ends up being valued. I wonder if this is also why Support is chronically undervalued and underfunded.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again please read the whole thing :-) &lt;a href=&quot;https://pwords.substack.com/p/the-myth-of-maintenance-mode&quot;&gt;https://pwords.substack.com/p/the-myth-of-maintenance-mode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 9, 2018 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/01/09/p1-how-automattic-handles-2000-support-tickets-daily-communication-respect-for-team-and-customers/&quot;&gt;How does Automattic handle 2000 support requests/day? With communication and respect for customers and respect for support folks&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– sadly the following link is broken in 2023: https://blog.freshdesk.com/secret-sauce-wordpress-com/&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/16/p1-may-wong-maintenance-mode-myth-support/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/16/p1-may-wong-maintenance-mode-myth-support/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Samantha Slade: Difficult Conversations and Talking Circles: A response for those longing for healthy team dynamics</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/percolab-droplets/difficult-conversations-and-talking-circles-9fababc88e08&quot;&gt;Difficult Conversations and Talking Circles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A talking circle is NOT an action taking or decision making process, nor a feedback method. Talking circles help to go into a topic with depth, to explore what is stirring underneath, to engage in the complexity together. Think of something that is rumbling right now in your group or team. Circle practice can help to go into this rumbling in a safe way. If you find yourself being pulled into side conversations about an issue going on, it might be time to call a circle. It helps those concerned to go into the issue together, constructively. Circle helps to step away from blame culture and to really listen to one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Speak from the “I”.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Speak to the center of the circle.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Go around with a talking/listening piece&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Silence is healthy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;June 12, 2022 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/06/12/p1-megan-carpenter-stop-assuming-good-intent-i-will-give-you-grace-if-you-give-me-effort/&quot;&gt;Megan Carpenter via Tara Robertson via Nancy White: Stop Assuming Good Intent; instead: I’ll give you grace if you give me effort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/11/p1-talking-circle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/11/p1-talking-circle/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The age of average aka kinfolk, airspace, five over ones, people's choice, wind tunnel cars, same type in media, same clothing everythere, etc everywhere</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do your own thing, do your own look and style, escape the bland hegemony :-)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JUICY QUOTE (of course read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alexmurrell.co.uk/articles/the-age-of-average&quot;&gt;Alex Murrell: The age of average&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But it’s not all bad news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I believe that the age of average is the age of opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When every supermarket aisle looks like a sea of sameness, when every category abides by the same conventions, when every industry has converged on its own singular style, bold brands and courageous companies have the chance to chart a different course. To be different, distinctive and disruptive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So, this is your call to arms. Whether you’re in film or fashion, media or marketing, architecture, automotive or advertising, it doesn’t matter. Our visual culture is flatlining and the only cure is creativity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s time to cast aside conformity. It’s time to exorcise the expected. It’s time to decline the indistinguishable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For years the world has been moving in the same stylistic direction. And it’s time we reintroduced some originality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Or as the ad agency BBH says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When the world zigs. Zag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 2, 2005 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2005/04/02/how-design-really-gets-done/&quot;&gt;How design really gets done&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/10/p1-age-of-average-kinfolk-airspace-peoples-choice-five-over-ones-etc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/10/p1-age-of-average-kinfolk-airspace-peoples-choice-five-over-ones-etc/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simon Willison: ChatGPT lies. Me: so how can we trust its output to truly be helpful even if we are experts in the domain of discourse? And therefore know how to fact check it?</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simon Willison writes: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ChatGPT lies to people. This is a serious bug that has so far resisted all attempts at a fix. We need to prioritize helping people understand this, not debating the most precise terminology to use to describe it.
We accidentally invented computers that can lie to us&lt;/code&gt;. Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2023/Apr/7/chatgpt-lies/&quot;&gt;We need to tell people ChatGPT will lie to them, not debate linguistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 9, 2023 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/09/p2-are-humans-more-actualized-with-ai/&quot;&gt;Emily Bender: you are not a stochastic parrot / Judith Butler, are we more actualized with AI? from: NY Magazine you are not a parrot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/09/p3-simon-wilison-chatgpt-lies-so-how-can-we-trust-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/09/p3-simon-wilison-chatgpt-lies-so-how-can-we-trust-it/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emily Bender: you are not a stochastic parrot / Judith Butler, are we more actualized with AI? from: NY Magazine you are not a parrot</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;“On the Dangers of Stochastic Parrots” is not a write-up of original research. It’s a synthesis of LLM critiques that Bender and others have made: of the biases encoded in the models; the near impossibility of studying what’s in the training data, given the fact they can contain billions of words; the costs to the climate; the problems with building technology that freezes language in time and thus locks in the problems of the past.&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/ai-artificial-intelligence-chatbots-emily-m-bender.html&quot;&gt;Please read the whole thing: You Are Not a Parrot And a chatbot is not a human. And a linguist named Emily M. Bender is very worried what will happen when we forget this.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Judith Butler, UC Berkley: “Or that human potential — that’s the fascist idea — human potential is more fully actualized with AI than without it”. &lt;a href=&quot;https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/ai-artificial-intelligence-chatbots-emily-m-bender.html&quot;&gt;AGAIN :-), please read the whole thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 9, 2020:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/01/19/p1-canosp-firefox-support-question-tagging-project-machine-learning-university-alberta/&quot;&gt;Working with 4 University of Alberta Computer Science Students in the CANOSP program on a machine learning project to auto-tag Firefox desktop support questions based on a human trained dataset&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- in retrospect this seems like a primitive project now :-) Is this better with GPT-3 or 4?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/09/p2-are-humans-more-actualized-with-ai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/09/p2-are-humans-more-actualized-with-ai/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I have rejoined Thunderbird</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What goes around, comes around :-). As of April 3, 2023, I have re-joined Thunderbird as a support engineer!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I plan on doing some of the things I didn’t get done during my last Thunderbird stint which was 2009-2012. And am excited by the future of Thunderbird including Thunderbird on Android!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 4, 2023:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/01/04/p1-thank-you-element-matrix/&quot;&gt;Thank you Element! Leaving after being laid off after 2 years #ElementLifeboat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/09/p1-rejoined-thunderbird/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2023/04/09/p1-rejoined-thunderbird/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
