<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:51:50 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 20:51:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Got my 2nd dose of the Astra Zeneca Covid 19 vaccine today. Go science go!</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got my second dose of AZ 8.5 weeks after my first! So lucky! So privileged!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;#vaccinateThePlanet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;April 8, 2021: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/04/08/p1-first-dose-astra-zeneca-covid-19-vaccine-go-science-go/&quot;&gt;Got my first dose of the Astra Zeneca Covid 19 vaccine today. Go science go!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;April 30,2021: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/04/30/p1-three-weeks-since-astra-zeneca-vaccination-and-feel-fine/&quot;&gt;Three weeks since my first dose of the Astra Zeneca Covid 19 vaccine and I feel fine!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/06/08/p1-second-dose-astra-zeneca-covid19-vaccine-go-science-go/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/06/08/p1-second-dose-astra-zeneca-covid19-vaccine-go-science-go/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Canadian Government should implement all 94 TRC calls to action. That would be a good start to healing, anything less is unacceptable</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Canadian Government should implement all &lt;a href=&quot;http://trc.ca/assets/pdf/Calls_to_Action_English2.pdf&quot;&gt;94 TRC calls to action&lt;/a&gt;. That would be a good start to healing, anything less is unacceptable &amp;lt;– I hate the “should” word. This is a rare occasion when its use is warranted!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2021/05/30/p1-residential-school-system-genocide/&quot;&gt;@arnalLabrador:you can do these simple steps to change our country:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/06/06/p1-implement-the-94-trc-calls-to-action/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/06/06/p1-implement-the-94-trc-calls-to-action/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>@arnalLabrador:you can do these simple steps to change our country:</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ArnallLabrador/status/1399146643107295232&quot;&gt;1. Educate yourself on what the Residential School System was. 2. Educate yourself on what the TRC was and especially read the final report. 3. Have conversations with your peers and friends.  4. Have conversations with your children ( they aren’t too young)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ArnallLabrador/status/1399146644806017025&quot;&gt;5. There are children oriented resources out there to teach young children about the Residential Schools.  6. Indigenous written/ produced resources should always come first, second, or third. Our stories should always be told by our people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ArnallLabrador/status/1399146646097772544&quot;&gt;7. Educate yourself on proper etiquette for Indigenous allyship. This is essential. 8. Actively engage in anti racism. You see a post, you hear someone say something, you shut that down right away.  9. This all will be uncomfortable, you are unlearning unconscious biases.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ArnallLabrador/status/1399146647494483972&quot;&gt;10. Lastly, listen to and uplift Indigenous voices.  You may be one person, but you can enact change with a boots on the ground mentality. It all can start with you.  A lot if this is things you can do on your own.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/30/p1-residential-school-system-genocide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/30/p1-residential-school-system-genocide/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I still won't be indoor dining until over 50% of the population has 2 vaccinations even though it's allowed as of May 25</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.gov.bc.ca/releases/2021PREM0023-000578&quot;&gt;The circuit breaker lockdown that started March 30, 2021 in&lt;/a&gt; BC is over and indoor dining is allowed again as of May 25, 2021. When will that be? I’m hoping for October i.e. Canadian Thanksgiving or slightly earlier!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I still won’t be indoor dining until over 50% of the population has 2 vaccinations even though it’s allowed now?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why? aerosols, lack of filtration and ventilation in 99% of the restaurants and variants #ymmv :-)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stay healthy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/26/p1-indoor-dining-allowed-again-circuit-breaker-over/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/26/p1-indoor-dining-allowed-again-circuit-breaker-over/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Links to help me make a small reproducible example for my if_else() tidyverse R issue</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I would like to make a less than 10 line reproducible example for my &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;if_else()&lt;/code&gt; problem from my May 9, 2021 post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/09/p1-not-sure-why-r-ifelse-fails/&quot;&gt;Not sure why R’s if_else() fails! R type system misunderstanding? Misunderstanding of NA?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I bet it’s my misunderstanding and not a tidyverse or R bug!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here are the links:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt; May 24, 2021.&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/24459752/can-dplyr-package-be-used-for-conditional-mutating&quot;&gt;Stack Overflow:Can dplyr package be used for conditional mutating?&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– case_when, if_else, ifelse, na_if, see also &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/42075721/handling-na-in-if-else-in-r&quot;&gt;handling NA in if_else in r&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/50646133/dplyr-if-else-vs-base-r-ifelse&quot;&gt;dplyr if_else() vs base R ifelse()&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/25/p1-links-for-if-else-small-reproducible-example-r-tidyverse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/25/p1-links-for-if-else-small-reproducible-example-r-tidyverse/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Probably wrong prediction: We will have forgotten about outdoor dining by 2025 just like we forgot why steam radiators are so hot</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s a great idea and works in the city of Vancouver except when it’s snowing and or heavily raining i.e. it works for 365 days a year minus 100 hours or so :-) but we love our convenience and able bodied folks can’t cope with a wee bit of rain or coolness (which is weird to me since those same folks eat outside in -10 at ski resorts like Whistler)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See my tweet:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This fantastic! Probably wrong prediction: This will all be forgotten by 2025. But I think those who don&amp;#39;t have illnesses triggered by light rain &amp;amp; have warm rain gear should consider eating in light rain (under some shelter) even Post Pandemic. It&amp;#39;s fun! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/GSk2sKqv8W&quot;&gt;https://t.co/GSk2sKqv8W&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Roland Tanglao 猪肉面 (@rtanglao) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rtanglao/status/1396299282949410816?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But we’ll forget just like we forgot why steam radiators are so warm!
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2020/12/10/945136599/how-spanish-flu-pandemic-changed-home-heat-radiators&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;: “CHANG: Oh, so familiar. As it turns out, radiators that work too well  are partly a result of the 1918 flu pandemic. You see; there was once  something called the Fresh Air Movement. It called for people to be  outside more and for there to be plenty of ventilation indoors.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;See my previous posts:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/03/15/p1-how-to-vancouverite-always-carry-a-plastic-bag-for-coffee-and-doughnuts-in-the-rain/&quot;&gt;How To Vancouverite in the Rain: Always carry a plastic bag for outdoor coffee and doughnuts in the rain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/03/16/p1-how-to-vancouverite-always-carry-chopsticks-spoon-fork-knife-napkin-dining-rain/&quot;&gt;How  To Vancouverite in the Rain: Always carry chopsticks, spoon, fork,  knife wrapped in a napkin since you never know when you’ll have a  hankering for adobo, pancit, mapo tofu, kimchi stew, chana masala or  sushi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/03/19/p1-how-to-vancouverite-always-carry-raingear/&quot;&gt;How to Vancouverite in the rain: Always carry raingear because we live in a temperate rainforest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/23/p1-forgotten-about-outdoor-dining-by-2025/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/23/p1-forgotten-about-outdoor-dining-by-2025/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our son is a real artist</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From Arts Umbrella: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artsumbrella.com/stories/simon-tanglao-vasi/&quot;&gt;Learning to work as an artist today with Visual Arts Summer Intensive (VASI)&lt;/a&gt; :  “I think that being exposed to contemporary art from all sorts of  perspectives (curatorial, artistic, logistical) has deepened my  appreciation and enjoyment of it as an artist. VASI opened up a lot of  possibilities that I’m thankful for, has continued to shape my practice, and will probably continue for a long time.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/22/p1-our-son-real-artist/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/22/p1-our-son-real-artist/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On the benefits of sharing your work Composer and performer Kamala Sankaram discusses creating your own path and the diversity of opera! (I love opera!)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 18, 2021.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/people/composer-and-performer-kamala-sankaram-on-the-benefits-of-sharing-your-work/&quot;&gt;On the benefits of sharing your work Composer and performer Kamala Sankaram discusses creating your own path&lt;/a&gt;  “Most people in America have never heard an opera, so there’s 100 years of opera being made in America that’s out there to discover. We tend to think of the old Italian and German pieces, but then America had what has been called a Golden Age of Opera, especially in the last 20 years or so. There’s a lot of great work being done in New York, there’s a festival called Prototype that has new pieces every year that are pushing the boundaries of what opera can be.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Some of the composers that have come out of Prototype are David T. Little, Missy Mazzoli, Ellen Reid. There’s, of course, people who’ve been around forever, like Anthony Davis, who just won the Pulitzer last year for his opera Central Park Five.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;He has an opera from the ’80s called Malcolm X that’s just amazing. It’s going to get more productions now, but it’s really great and there’s a good recording of it out there, too. Right now, people are especially influenced by putting people on stage who haven’t been there by representing social justice issues, borrowing from popular music, jazz. There’s an opera that came out a few years ago called We Shall Not Be Moved, it’s got a lot of hip hop in it and the choreography is by Bill T. Jones.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;There are too many people to name everybody, but there’s something for everybody out there.” &amp;lt;– opera is universal i agree!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/20/p1-diverse-opera-out-there-and-universal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/20/p1-diverse-opera-out-there-and-universal/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simon Willison's github scraping is officially supported by Github who call it 'Flat Data'</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 19, 2021.&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/simonw/status/1394729289346519041&quot;&gt;Flat Data&lt;/a&gt;!  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2021/May/19/flat-data/&quot;&gt;blog post)&lt;/a&gt; Simon Willison’s git scraping is now officially supported by Github who call it “Flat Data”! yes!
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;See my previous post from October 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/16/p1-simon-willison-git-scraping-how-to-use-github-actions-to-call-an-api-every-20-minutes/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison:Git scraping: track changes over  time by scraping to a Git repository aka how to use github actions to  call an API every 20 minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/19/p1-simon-willison-github-scraping-official-supported-by-github-flat-data/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/19/p1-simon-willison-github-scraping-official-supported-by-github-flat-data/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>everest pipkin: HERE IS THE ARTICLE YOU CAN SEND TO PEOPLE WHEN THEY SAY “BUT THE ENVIRONMENTAL ISSUES WITH CRYPTOART WILL BE SOLVED SOON, RIGHT?”</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://everestpipkin.medium.com/but-the-environmental-issues-with-cryptoart-1128ef72e6a3&quot;&gt;HERE IS THE ARTICLE YOU CAN SEND TO PEOPLE WHEN THEY SAY “BUT THE  ENVIRONMENTAL ISSUES WITH CRYPTOART WILL BE SOLVED SOON, RIGHT?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Juicy Quote:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BEGIN QUOTE:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”“&lt;strong&gt;However, we must get there through collective empowerment and strong social  programs like universal basic income, universal healthcare, divestment  from warfare and policing, a regulated real estate market that does not  capitalize on housing scarcity and rent, worker unions, food programs,  environmental protections, and actual, functioning income taxes on the  wealthy.&lt;/strong&gt; An individualist fantasy of a pyramid scheme, made to  reward investors over artists and directly thieving from our shared  future just isn’t it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many would call me unrealistic and naïve for this, unwilling to make  compromises in the world we are living now because of an idealistic  vision of a tomorrow; and to them I would like to say that we literally  invented an extra-sovereign monetary system that within 10 years has  generated trillions of dollars of worth and is held up with the power  consumption of a small country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let this whole horrible chapter of history convince you that money is fake, we can do anything with it we want, and that we do not want cryptoart.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/17/p1-everest-pipkin-cryptoart-nft-environment-issues-wont-be-solved-soon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/17/p1-everest-pipkin-cryptoart-nft-environment-issues-wont-be-solved-soon/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
