<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:31:08 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 09:31:08 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr AI: AGI is more like twitter than jet engines in that it is fed by people and not predictable and not apparent from inside the software industry how others use it. But how general is it? And I agree, where do we go from here? Still skeptical but super thought provoking piece ; Robin Sloan:: AGI is here (and I feel fine)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 12, 2026 17:05 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.robinsloan.com/winter-garden/agi-is-here/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr AI: AGI is more like twitter than jet engines in that it is fed by people and not predictable and not apparent from inside the software industry how others use it. But how general is it? And I agree, where do we go from here? Still skeptical but super thought provoking piece ; Robin Sloan:: AGI is here (and I feel fine)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s not that the com­pa­nies don’t know any­thing — they know a lot—but rather that a reg­ular user can have an expe­ri­ence with these sys­tems, an idea about them, that is not avail­able to even the deepest, dankest, insider-iest insider. I contend that reg­ular users are having such expe­ri­ences &amp;amp; ideas all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think this is just how these sys­tems work, when they have so many dif­ferent people using them for so many dif­ferent rea­sons. It’s pretty weird, com­pared to other products. After all, the com­pany that man­u­fac­tures jet engines &amp;amp; sells them to five cus­tomers can rea­son­ably claim to under­stand the uses of those engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That’s all to say, for all the math &amp;amp; matériel involved in their care &amp;amp; feeding, the big models are more like Twitter than they are like jet engines, &amp;amp; this whole thing was a sur­prise anyway — from which no one has quite recovered — so I will defend vig­or­ously the right of any­body/every­body to reflect &amp;amp; opine on AI’s prop­er­ties &amp;amp; potential, &amp;amp; to declare, when it seems obvious: AGI is here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been reading a lot about the early his­tory of per­sonal com­puters, the 1970s &amp;amp; 1980s. (This book was wonderful, because its present — the pin­nacle from which it sur­veys a tumul­tuous his­tory — is … 1984.) It’s been inter­esting to dis­cover that many of the visions &amp;amp; promises of that era “rhyme” with the visions &amp;amp; promises of the present boom. It’s clear that Bay Area tech is, if not one con­tin­uous project, 1957-2026, then for sure one con­tin­uous culture. (I happen to think it’s one con­tin­uous project.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The pace is familiar, too: hot new com­pa­nies were appearing every month, fading just as fast. Yes, the dollar amounts were smaller — the com­puter was still a niche product — but the feel­ings really seem to be the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And … the visions of that era were sub­stan­tially realized ! Today, every­body really does own a per­sonal com­puter, or some­thing like one. Everybody really is con­nected to a global infor­ma­tion network, or some­thing like one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m an avid user of both my per­sonal com­puter &amp;amp; the global infor­ma­tion network, &amp;amp; I observe that we appear not to live in utopia. The and … ? of those inven­tions roars in our ears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Today, every­body really can call upon AGI, or some­thing like it: a wildly gen­eral com­puter program. I mean ! Wow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The ques­tion, always, forever: what now?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/12/p0905-agi-is-here/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/12/p0905-agi-is-here/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things that Work: Hario Tetsuya Kasuya Double Stainless All Metal Pourover Dripper with Aramse Sofi Top and holder. Best pourover coffee ever :-) !</title>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the &lt;a href=&quot;https://global.hario.com/kasuya_model/kdd.html&quot;&gt;Hario Double Stainless Dripper・KASUYA Model&lt;/a&gt;on top of your coffee cup or carafe and add your ground coffee.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place the Aramse &lt;a href=&quot;https://aramse.coffee/products/sofi&quot;&gt;Sofi&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://aramse.coffee/products/sofi-holder&quot;&gt;holder&lt;/a&gt; on top of the Tetsuya dripper and then place the top part of the Aramse Sofi brewer on top of the stand&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use your favourite pourover method. The Armase Sofi top part acts as a shower head. No need for a fancy pourover kettle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No plastic! And super coffee with no fines.
Disclaimer: I have no interest financially or otherwise in Hario or Aramse. Love them both!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/12/p0757-hario-kasuya-double-stainless-metal-pourover-dripper-aramse-sofi-highly-recommended/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/12/p0757-hario-kasuya-double-stainless-metal-pourover-dripper-aramse-sofi-highly-recommended/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: A 'Marginal Tipping Map' is needed to tell us to do the difficult but obvious :-) ie: 100% renewable energy, 100% non fossil burning transportation and industry, etc :-) ; Unpolitics: From Knowing to Doing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 12, 2026 15:41 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://unpolitics.global/contrasts&quot;&gt;ME:: A ‘Marginal Tipping Map’ is needed to tell us to do the difficult but obvious :-) ie: 100% renewable energy, 100% non fossil burning transportation and industry, etc :-) ; Unpolitics: From Knowing to Doing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing &lt;a href=&quot;https://unpolitics.global/contrasts&quot;&gt;Unpolitics: From Knowing to Doing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What’s missing is a global framework for identifying where these efforts will make the biggest difference right now. We call this the Marginal Tipping Map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Marginal Tipping Map is not yet a finished tool—it is a proposed framework, a way of thinking that enables more effective action. It is designed to help funders, governments, and institutions see where catalytic investments, policy shifts, and social momentum can unlock exponential change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This isn’t just about data—it’s about shifting strategy: from allocating cost to identifying leverage. From asking who should act, to revealing where action will move the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And it’s not hypothetical. We’ve seen it before:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Solar costs fell 89% in a decade due to scale and learning.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Norway’s EV adoption crossed 80% with clear public signals.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The U.S. Inflation Reduction Act triggered hundreds of billions in private investment.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Vietnam and Germany launched solar booms with targeted policy shifts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;These tipping points didn’t happen by accident. They were enabled. The question is how to identify and trigger the next ones—globally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/12/p0741-contrasts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/12/p0741-contrasts/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: LLMs reduce typing and the cost of using types so of course typed languages like TypeScript will be come more popular or something :-) ; Cassidy Williams:: Why AI is pushing developers toward typed languages - The GitHub Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 11, 2026 04:39 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/ai-and-ml/llms/why-ai-is-pushing-developers-toward-typed-languages/&quot;&gt;ME:: LLMs reduce typing and the cost of using types so of course typed languages like TypeScript will be come more popular or something :-) ; Cassidy Williams:: Why AI is pushing developers toward typed languages - The GitHub Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/ai-and-ml/llms/why-ai-is-pushing-developers-toward-typed-languages/&quot;&gt;Why AI is pushing developers toward typed languages - The GitHub Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But actually though, a 2025 academic study found that a whopping 94% of LLM-generated compilation errors were type-check failures. Imagine how much your projects would improve if 94% of your failures went away! Your life would be better. Your skin would clear. You’d get taller. Or at least you’d have fewer “why does this return a string now?” debugging sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What Octoverse 2025 says about the rise of typed languages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Octoverse 2025 confirmed it: TypeScript is now the most used language on GitHub, overtaking both Python and JavaScript as of August 2025. TypeScript grew by over 1 million contributors in 2025 (+66% YoY, Aug ‘25 vs. Aug ‘24) with an estimated 2.6 million developers total. This was driven, in part, by frameworks that scaffold projects in TypeScript by default (like Astro, Next.js, and Angular). But the report also found correlative evidence that TypeScript’s rise got a boost from AI-assisted development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That means AI is influencing not only how fast code is written, but which languages and tools developers use. And typed ecosystems are benefiting too, because they help AI slot new code into existing projects without breaking assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/10/p2039-why-ai-is-pushing-developers-toward-typed-languages/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/10/p2039-why-ai-is-pushing-developers-toward-typed-languages/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recipes that work:: I used smoked sardines and this was delish :-) ; Tori Avey's Mediterranean Sardine Pasta: Zesty Lemon, Capers &amp;amp; Chili</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 10, 2026 01:00 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://toriavey.com/mediterranean-sardine-lemon-pasta/&quot;&gt;Recipes that work:: I used smoked sardines and this was delish :-) ; Tori Avey’s Mediterranean Sardine Pasta: Zesty Lemon, Capers &amp;amp; Chili&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/09/p1700-mediterranean-sardine-lemon-pasta/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/09/p1700-mediterranean-sardine-lemon-pasta/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: web app search engine for 159, 801 Unicode characters as of September 9, 2025; Unicode Character Table - Full List of Unicode Symbols (◕‿◕) SYMBL</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 8, 2026 16:24 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://symbl.cc/en/unicode-table/&quot;&gt;ME:: web app search engine for 159, 801 Unicode characters as of September 9, 2025; Unicode Character Table - Full List of Unicode Symbols (◕‿◕) SYMBL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/08/p0824-unicode-table/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/08/p0824-unicode-table/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: i still want to make collages from Thunderbird support questions using Unicode icons and symbols, this along with wikipedia's list will help me figure out what's possible ;  Huge List of Unicode Character Symbols</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 8, 2026 16:19 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vertex42.com/ExcelTips/unicode-symbols.html&quot;&gt;ME:: i still want to make collages from Thunderbird support questions using Unicode icons and symbols, this along with wikipedia’s list will help me figure out what’s possible ;  Huge List of Unicode Character Symbols&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– See also &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Unicode_characters&quot;&gt;wikipedia’s list&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;This page provides a way to browse the huge list of Unicode symbols. The number listed under each symbols is the DECIMAL value. Use DEC2HEX() and HEX2DEC() in Excel to convert between hexidecimal and decimal. This is NOT a comprehensive list of ALL Unicode characters (such as the thousands of symbols used for different languages). I've mainly included math, emoji, dingbats, and other miscellanous symbols so that I could copy/paste the entire set into Excel to see what works within Excel.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/08/p0819-unicode-symbols/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/08/p0819-unicode-symbols/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: how to figure out unicode for fun icons and symbols in ruby, see also unibits gem and CLI tool and other related gems ; Jan Lelis, Yauheni Dakuka:: Idiosyncratic Ruby: Ruby has Character</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 8, 2026 16:15 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://idiosyncratic-ruby.com/66-ruby-has-character.html&quot;&gt;ME:: how to figure out unicode for fun icons and symbols in ruby, see also unibits gem and CLI tool and other related gems ; Jan Lelis, Yauheni Dakuka:: Idiosyncratic Ruby: Ruby has Character&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ruby comes with good support for Unicode-related features. Read on if you want to learn more about important Unicode fundamentals and how to use them in Ruby…&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/08/p0815-66-ruby-has-character/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/08/p0815-66-ruby-has-character/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Powerful lnav shortcuts when viewing logs: Control w for wordwrap, / to search, g for line 1, G for end of file, = to pause</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;October 4, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/04/p2208-lnav-view-colourize-multiple-log-files-including-ruby-logger-gem-logs/&quot;&gt;ME tl-dr-ing; lnav, a TUI tool to to colourize, filter and view multiple log files that works with zero configuration out of the box with standard log files like log files generated by ruby’s logger gem ; Tim Stack:: lnav v0.13.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/07/p2303-lnav-shortcuts-viewing-logs-controlw-wordwrap-slash-to-search-equal-pause-g-top-shiftG-bottom/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/07/p2303-lnav-shortcuts-viewing-logs-controlw-wordwrap-slash-to-search-equal-pause-g-top-shiftG-bottom/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It's 2026: Self Driving cars are still not proven safe and we don't need them to reduce cyclist or pedestrian deaths ; David Zipper:: Are Autonomous Vehicles Safer Than Human Drivers? We Don't Know Yet - Bloomberg</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 7, 2026 03:50 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2026-01-06/are-autonomous-vehicles-safer-than-human-drivers-we-don-t-know-yet&quot;&gt;It’s 2026: Self Driving cars are still not proven safe and we don’t need them to reduce cyclist or pedestrian deaths ; David Zipper:: Are Autonomous Vehicles Safer Than Human Drivers? We Don’t Know Yet - Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;For proof, just look outside the US, where plenty of countries have managed to bring traffic fatalities down dramatically. Most recently, the Nordic cities of Helsinki and Oslo have gone an entire year without any cyclist or pedestrian deaths at all. How did they accomplish this feat? Local leaders credited a range of infrastructural and policy changes, from slower speed limits and wider sidewalks to higher car fees and stiffer enforcement.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 6, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/06/p1829-if-self-driving-cars-worked-there-would-be-benefits-selfdriving-wont-work-before-2034-lets-deploy-more-trains-buses-first/&quot;&gt;ME:: All the benefits sound plausible but I still think self driving cars won’t work in 2034 and we’d be better improving ‘low tech’ non self driving trains and buses ; The Economist:: Self-driving cars will transform urban economies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/06/p1950-are-autonomous-vehicles-safer-than-human-drivers-we-don-t-know-yet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/01/06/p1950-are-autonomous-vehicles-safer-than-human-drivers-we-don-t-know-yet/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
