<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 10:33:21 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 10:33:21 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pluribus anti-zombie zombie 1st 2 episodes blew me away. COVID-19 awareness in a denialist world parallels per Julia Doubleday?</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See Dale and my impressions over on our Over 40 in Vancouver podcast:&lt;a href=&quot;https://over40invan.com/92-apple-tvs-pluribus-the-first-two-episodes/&quot;&gt;Episode #92 Apple TV’s Pluribus – The first two episodes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the COVID denialist parallel see Julia Doubleday’s post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegauntlet.news/p/pluribus-captures-the-isolation-of&quot;&gt;“Pluribus” captures the isolation of COVID-awareness in a COVID denialist world&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;quote-from-julia-doubledays-post&quot;&gt;QUOTE from Julia Doubleday’s post&lt;/h2&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing by Julia Doubleday: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thegauntlet.news/p/pluribus-captures-the-isolation-of&quot;&gt;“Pluribus” captures the isolation of COVID-awareness in a COVID denialist world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Let’s take a moment here. Whether or not Vince Gilligan meant to evoke the pandemic with this show, this is a show carrying a lot of psychic COVID baggage. The show begins with misused PPE, animal transmission/lab leak (pick your theory!), and the inversion of early pandemic measures.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rather than social distancing, these characters immediately begin kissing on the mouth. To me- and I’d guess, many other COVID cautious individuals, the invaded personal space and licked donuts evoke people’s continued insistence that they have the right not to isolate and mask while infected with COVID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What’s mine is yours, what’s yours is mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Rather than swab to prevent the spread of disease, they swab to further it. And while to many this may feel like a far-fetched, sci-fi premise, for those of us living with Long COVID, it does in fact feel that most people today are actively promoting the spread of COVID rather than engaging with our ongoing efforts to halt and reduce the virus’ spread.
For example, we’ve known for years that cleaning the indoor air by introducing higher ventilation standards and HEPA filtration standards would drastically reduce airborne illness. There’s a new technology called Far UVC that inactivates viral pathogens in the air. Combining these two could be a game changer- drastically reducing how much we all get sick. Yet no matter how much we bring up this idea- and no matter how often and how seriously their children get sick- people seem to prefer getting sick than breaking from The Borg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And The Borg, to be clear, is approximately where the show goes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/11/p1006-pluribus-anti-zombie-zombie-episodes-blew-covid-19-awareness-denialist-parallels-julia-doubleday/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/11/p1006-pluribus-anti-zombie-zombie-episodes-blew-covid-19-awareness-denialist-parallels-julia-doubleday/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Recipes that probably :-) work::  Gotta try this with cashews since Simon is allergic to peanuts :-) ; Genevieve Ko:: Dan Dan Noodles Recipe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 11, 2025 02:23 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/Ld85I#selection-1911.0-1911.810&quot;&gt;ME:: Recipes that probably :-) work::  Gotta try this with cashews since Simon is allergic to peanuts :-) ; Genevieve Ko:: Dan Dan Noodles Recipe&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A specialty from Sichuan, a province in the southwest of China, vendors once balanced baskets of noodles and sauce on their shoulder poles and cried out “dan dan mian!” to hawk their wares. Dan dan refers to those bamboo shoulder poles and mian means noodles, but there’s no one way to prepare them. Nowadays in the Western diaspora, the dish is associated with a few essentials, namely chile oil and sesame paste, but another is worth adding: preserved vegetables. Salty and a little sweet with the sour oomph of fermentation, pickled mustard greens give the soothing noodles an umami zing. These noodles are especially rich with sesame, but you can adjust all of the seasonings to your taste. Toasty and salty, tangy on the cliff of funk, chewy with pops of peanut, dan dan noodles are a bowl of contentment.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– see also: &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/RpRn9&quot;&gt;These Dan Dan Noodles Are the Weeknight Meal of Your Dreams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p1823-genevieve-ko-dan-dan-mian-noodles-recipe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p1823-genevieve-ko-dan-dan-mian-noodles-recipe/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I disagree with the analogue note taking folks. I don't read my old analogue notes. #Ymmv</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;And there’s no links. Digital text wins. If your notes are digital and text only (markdown, html, none of that other stuff :-)  or text + PNG and JPEG it’s simple (no crazy Obsidian or other note taking system needed) and will last forever. I want my Newton back. I guess I’ll eventually buy an iPad mini with something like the  &lt;a href=&quot;https://paperlike.com/&quot;&gt;paperlike&lt;/a&gt; screen protector that enhances the writing experience with an Apple Pencil and a Remarkable. Stylus plus printing recognition works for me., Again #Ymmv :-)  an example of the analogue note taking propaganda er marketing :-)  is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;reysu's video&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mq0XvGPSm9w\&quot;&gt;the hybrid note-taking system I wish I learned earlier&lt;/a&gt;  advocates both :-) digital and analogue no thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p1741-disagree-analogue-note-folks-read-notes-ymmv/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p1741-disagree-analogue-note-folks-read-notes-ymmv/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: LOL Ryan,respectfully I think you are wrong but what do I know :-) ; Ryan Dahl:: Humans Are Just Stochastic Parrots</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 10, 2025 17:13 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyclouds.org/humans/&quot;&gt;ME:: LOL Ryan,respectfully I think you are wrong but what do I know :-) ; Ryan Dahl:: Humans Are Just Stochastic Parrots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyclouds.org/humans/&quot;&gt;Ryan Dahl:: Humans Are Just Stochastic Parrots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This species will fabricate quotes, sources, and references – a lot of the time they just make things up that sound plausible. Their words are superficially impressive but largely lacking in substance — humans mostly produce what has been described as fluent bullshit. Humans mansplain, presenting reasoning free of evidence but with confidence in its own correctness on any topic, without regard for the audience. Like talking to a drunk person at a bar: wrong, but very confident about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yet humans really do accomplish a lot more than many thought possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Humans just spew words. It just so happens that we can decode them into something related, useful, and meaningful surprisingly often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p0913-humans-are-not-stochastic-parrots-sorry-ryan-dahl/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p0913-humans-are-not-stochastic-parrots-sorry-ryan-dahl/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Canada has lost its measles immunization status because of anti-science lies.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks anti-science people worldwide, NOT! This is 100% your fault. Go science go!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p0731-canada-lost-measles-immunization-status-anti-science-lies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/10/p0731-canada-lost-measles-immunization-status-anti-science-lies/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Polish is overrated in Podcasts :-) It's just audio on the internet. Get over yourself just post it :-) !</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry (too much) about sound quality, editing, advertising, the image etc etc I certainly haven’t since 2004 LOL. See &lt;a href=&quot;https://over40invan.com/&quot;&gt;Over 40 in Vancouver&lt;/a&gt; for an example :-) or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rolandmicroblog.com/&quot;&gt;rolandmicroblog.com&lt;/a&gt; for even more thrilling lack of polish :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/09/p2109-polish-overrated-podcasts-audio-internet-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/09/p2109-polish-overrated-podcasts-audio-internet-post/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: And so it begins go Firefox for Enterprise go :-) ! I was involved in the last Firefox Enterprise effort 2018-2020 and it didn't go anywhere; hopefully it will go further this time! ; Brian Smith:: Introducing early access for Firefox Support for Organizations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 18:25 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/en/firefox/firefox-support-for-organizations/&quot;&gt;ME:: And so it begins go Firefox for Enterprise go :-) ! I was involved in the last Firefox Enterprise effort 2018-2020 and it didn’t go anywhere; hopefully it will go further this time! ; Brian Smith:: Introducing early access for Firefox Support for Organizations&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Multiple Firefox logos forming a curved trail on a dark background. ... Increasingly, businesses, schools, and government institutions deploy Firefox at scale for security, resilience, and data sovereignty. Organizations have fine-grained administrative and orchestration control of the browser’s behavior using policies with Firefox and the Extended Support Release (ESR). Today, we’re opening early access to Firefox Support for Organizations, a new program that begins operation in January 2026.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1025-firefox-support-for-organizations/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1025-firefox-support-for-organizations/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI by an AI maximalist who seems more reasonable than most of them. Daniel Miessler:: February 2024:: Why I Created Fabric</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 18:22 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://danielmiessler.com/blog/fabric-origin-story&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI by an AI maximalist who seems more reasonable than most of them. Daniel Miessler:: February 2024:: Why I Created Fabric&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fabric is an open-source framework for augmenting humans using AI. ...The goal of the project is to provide a universally accessible layer of AI that anyone can use to enhance their life or work. &lt;/code&gt;`&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1022-fabric-origin-story/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1022-fabric-origin-story/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: clearly we know nothing about minds :-) ; Norman, Johnson, van er Linden:: 2024:: Do Minds Have Immune systems?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 18:14 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://psycnet.apa.org/fulltext/2025-55535-001.pdf&quot;&gt;ME:: clearly we know nothing about minds :-) ; Norman, Johnson, van er Linden:: 2024:: Do Minds Have Immune systems?&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;:: Do minds have immune systems? In this article, we remove several obstacles to treatingthe question in a rigorously scientific way. After giving the hypothesis that minds do have such subsystems a name—we call it mental immune systems theory—we show why it merits serious consideration. The issue hinges on our definition of an immune system, so we examine the definition that currently prevails, demonstrate its shortcomings, and offer an alternative that addresses those shortcomings. We then lay out the empirical evidence that minds really do have immune systems in the specified sense. Findings about psychological inoculation, identity-protective cognition, cognitive dissonance, psycho-logical reactance, information diffusion, and cognitive bias all point to the existence of evolved cognitive defenses—informational “immune systems” that function in much the way that bodily immune systems do. Finally, we discuss the prospects of cognitive immunology, a research program that (a) posits mental immune systems and (b) proceeds to investigate their functioning`&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1014-2025-55535-001/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1014-2025-55535-001/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: so many free LUTs to try on the S9 and in Pearla and not boring iOS Camera Apps so little time :-) l  KROLOP und GERST:: Lumix S5II LUT Package</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Nov 8, 2025 18:10 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://krolop-gerst.com/product/lumix-s5ii-lut-package/&quot;&gt;ME:: so many free LUTs to try on the S9 and in Pearla and not boring iOS Camera Apps so little time :-) l  KROLOP und GERST:: Lumix S5II LUT Package&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Mit dem Erscheinen der S5II von Panasonic ist eine neue Ära in Sachen JPG-Fotografie angebrochen. So hoffen wir zumindest. Als erste Kamera kann sie LUTs nicht nur zur Hilfsansicht nutzen, sondern auch den geladenen Look direkt ins JPG speichern. Es ist einfach irre, was sich daraus für Möglichkeiten für die eigene Fotografie ergeben. Ganz besondere Looks ohne Bearbeitung direkt aus der Kamera!... Achtung: Diese LUTs sind speziell für die Lumix S5II in Kombination mit flachem Bildstil („flat“) entwickelt. Heißt, sie sind nicht (wie auch andere Presets, Bildlooks, etc.) 1:1 auf andere Kameras bzw. Stile zu übertragen. Und natürlich passt nicht jedes LUT zur jeder fotografischen Situation. Ein gewisses Gespür entwickelt man aber sehr schnell und lädt definitiv dazu ein, sehr bewusst zu fotografieren!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1010-lumix-s5ii-lut-package/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/11/08/p1010-lumix-s5ii-lut-package/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
