<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:55:05 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 10:55:05 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: Try 20 mins of moderate cardio before important tasks, hyperactivity: strength or high intensity, impulsivity interval training: Martial Arts or Yoga; Dr. Tracey Marks:: How One Workout Can Improve Focus for the ADHD Brain</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 16, 2026 17:35 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/Bdb35NoCeUU?si=kc-GusmvSBuICa84https://youtu.be/Bdb35NoCeUU&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: Try 20 mins of moderate cardio before important tasks, hyperactivity: strength or high intensity, impulsivity interval training: Martial Arts or Yoga; Dr. Tracey Marks:: How One Workout Can Improve Focus for the ADHD Brain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Summary at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bdb35NoCeUU&amp;amp;t=488s&quot;&gt;8:08&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 squats every hour is something I might try&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/16/p0935-tracey-marks-20minscardio-focus-hyperacitivty-strength-hiit-impulsivity-martial-arts-yoga/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/16/p0935-tracey-marks-20minscardio-focus-hyperacitivty-strength-hiit-impulsivity-martial-arts-yoga/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Probably Wrong Prediction:: We'll still need software developers until we get a breakthrough which will happen before 2050 or before i die whichever comes first. Today's tools are just not up to the task of replacing software developers. Wastefully (perhaps with local models not destroying the environment) augmenting humans, yes :-) Replacing humans no :-)  Stephan Schwab:: Why We've Tried to Replace Developers Every Decade Since 1969</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 13, 2026 05:01 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.caimito.net/en/blog/2025/12/07/the-recurring-dream-of-replacing-developers.html&quot;&gt;ME:: Probably Wrong Prediction:: We’ll still need software developers until we get a breakthrough which will happen before 2050 or before i die whichever comes first. Today’s tools are just not up to the task of replacing software developers. Wastefully (perhaps with local models not destroying the environment) augmenting humans, yes :-) Replacing humans no :-)  Stephan Schwab:: Why We’ve Tried to Replace Developers Every Decade Since 1969&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/12/p2101-the-recurring-dream-of-replacing-developers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/12/p2101-the-recurring-dream-of-replacing-developers/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: too over the top and expensive for me but looks like a fun setup! TerryB:: My Complete Livestream Setup for IRL Bicycle Rides - YouTube</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 13, 2026 04:54 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v48LAcKe8Tw&quot;&gt;ME:: too over the top and expensive for me but looks like a fun setup! TerryB:: My Complete Livestream Setup for IRL Bicycle Rides - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/12/p2054-terryb-livestreaming-bicycle-setup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/12/p2054-terryb-livestreaming-bicycle-setup/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: you can learn ANY language if you have time, enthusiasm and a source of quality understandable written and audio material aka 'input'. Sure you won't be perfect but nobody cares unless you're a diplomat so have fun with it :-) ; Steve Kaufmann on YouTube:: Is German really that hard to learn? - YouTube</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 13, 2026 04:46 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=04XEaLwkjlk&quot;&gt;ME:: you can learn ANY language if you have time, enthusiasm and a source of quality understandable written and audio material aka ‘input’. Sure you won’t be perfect but nobody cares unless you’re a diplomat so have fun with it :-) ; Steve Kaufmann on YouTube:: Is German really that hard to learn? - YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/12/p2046-time-enthusiasm-quality-at-your-level-input-learn-any-language/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/12/p2046-time-enthusiasm-quality-at-your-level-input-learn-any-language/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best printing recognition with a stylus on Boox 7 GO II? Use Nebo, Good Notes or forget about it and upgrade to some other device with a better stylus?</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GoodNotes seems to be awesome on iOS but not Android according to Reddit which I don’t trust :-) ; Old Reddit threads
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/GalaxyTab/comments/11esxh7/goodnotes_is_available_on_android/&quot;&gt;Goodnotes is available on Android! &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/GoodNotes/comments/15mbxjp/goodnotes_android_full_version_is_still_a_web/&quot;&gt;GoodNotes android full version is still a web based app :(&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reddit recommendation to upgrade from some, it’s fine for others:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/Onyx_Boox/comments/1nomuvj/onyx_boox_go_7_stylus_worth_it_for_notes/&quot;&gt;Onyx Boox Go 7 + Stylus — worth it for notes?&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– might upgrade and add the screen protector?!? -&amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Bit late, but Boox has now a screen protector that is especially made for inproving the writing on the Go 7...  &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?q=how+good+is+the+nebo+stylus+support+on+boox+go+7+ii+%3F&amp;amp;client=firefox-b-d&amp;amp;hs=dIz9&amp;amp;sca_esv=896419ed210a4547&amp;amp;biw=1068&amp;amp;bih=655&amp;amp;sxsrf=ANbL-n4vieod1rj1vu2V8GR5ElT8V_0xOQ%3A1770654185651&amp;amp;ei=6QmKafa7J_2d0PEP_7CFkAg&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi21IXu6MySAxX9DjQIHX9YAYIQ4dUDCBM&amp;amp;uact=5&amp;amp;oq=how+good+is+the+nebo+stylus+support+on+boox+go+7+ii+%3F&amp;amp;gs_lp=Egxnd3Mtd2l6LXNlcnAiNWhvdyBnb29kIGlzIHRoZSBuZWJvIHN0eWx1cyBzdXBwb3J0IG9uIGJvb3ggZ28gNyBpaSA_MgUQIRigATIFECEYoAFI0EBQ4xNYgT9wAngBkAEBmAHPAaAB4g6qAQY2LjEwLjG4AQPIAQD4AQGYAgygAtAJwgIKEAAYsAMY1gQYR8ICBxAjGLACGCfCAgUQABjvBcICCBAAGIAEGKIEwgIKECEYoAEYwwQYCsICCBAhGKABGMMEwgIIEAAYogQYiQWYAwCIBgGQBgiSBwU0LjcuMaAHhU2yBwUyLjcuMbgHuwnCBwkwLjQuNi4xLjHIB0uACAA&amp;amp;sclient=gws-wiz-serp&quot;&gt;Google’s AI mode LOL&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;how good is the nebo stylus support on boox go 7 ii ?&lt;/code&gt; says (interesting YouTube videos: 4 weeks ago: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=SNuB5vNfR-s&quot;&gt;Allan Liu:: Boox Go Color 7 Gen 2 vs. Gen 1: Stylus Support with a Trade&lt;/a&gt; ; April 27, 2025: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5BS9BiqJzLQ&quot;&gt;Boox Go 7 and Go Color 7 Gen II Bring Stylus Support at Last!&lt;/a&gt; ; 7 months ago June 17, 2025  &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/vQxlGIR8LE4&quot;&gt;Chalid Raqami:: The BOOX GO 7 Is Almost Perfect — If You Don’t Care About Writing ¦ REVIEW&lt;/a&gt;; June 26, 2025::  &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/rnm092nOjSM&quot;&gt;Boox Go Color 7 Gen 2 Review - Best Value E-ink Tablet Under $300!? &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The Nebo app (and general stylus) support on the
Boox Go 7 II (or Go Color 7 Gen II) is considered decent for casual note-taking and annotating, but it is not as precise or “paper-like” as Boox’s higher-end Note series. It uses USI 2.0 technology rather than Wacom EMR, which affects the writing feel and accuracy. 
Here is the breakdown of the stylus experience based on user reports and reviews:&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;h3 id=&quot;performance-and-feel&quot;&gt;Performance and Feel&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Decent Responsiveness: The writing experience is generally responsive, but there is a slight, detectable lag between the pen tip and the screen, which can be frustrating for heavy users.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;“Tappy” Writing Feel: The screen is glass, resulting in a slippery, “tappy” feeling without much resistance. Using a screen protector can improve this feel.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Accuracy: Precision is not as high as on Wacom-based devices, which may lead to missed strokes or inaccuracies if writing very quickly or in small font.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Best Use Case: It is best suited for quick notes, highlighting, and sketching rather than long-form, heavy writing session&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/09/p0829-printing-recognition-stylus-boox-nebo-good-notes-forget-upgrade-device/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/09/p0829-printing-recognition-stylus-boox-nebo-good-notes-forget-upgrade-device/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME: tl;dr-ing: Since the days of the analog world-wide telephone system and probably long before that :-) we have had systems that nobody knows how the whole thing works;  Lorin Hochstein:: Nobody knows how the whole system works – Surfing Complexity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 9, 2026 05:27 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://surfingcomplexity.blog/2026/02/08/nobody-knows-how-the-whole-system-works/&quot;&gt;ME: tl;dr-ing: Since the days of the analog world-wide telephone system and probably long before that :-) we have had systems that nobody knows how the whole thing works;  Lorin Hochstein:: Nobody knows how the whole system works – Surfing Complexity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://surfingcomplexity.blog/2026/02/08/nobody-knows-how-the-whole-system-works/&quot;&gt;Lorin Hochstein:: Nobody knows how the whole system works – Surfing Complexity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In their own ways, Wardley, Jacob, Perens, and Bucciarelli are all correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wardley’s right that it’s dangerous to build things where we don’t understand the underlying mechanism of how they actually work. This is precisely why magic is used as an epithet in our industry. Magic refers to frameworks that deliberately obscure the underlying mechanisms in service of making it easier to build within that framework. Ruby on Rails is the canonical example of a framework that uses magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jacob is right that AI is changing the way that normal software development work gets done. It’s a new capability that has proven itself to be so useful that it clearly isn’t going away. Yes, it represents a significant shift in how we build software, it moves us further away from how the underlying stuff actually works, but the benefits exceed the risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Perens is right that the scenario that Wardley fears has, in some sense, already come to pass. Modern CPU architectures and operating systems contain significant complexity, and many software developers are blissfully unaware of how these things really work. Yes, they have mental models of how the system below them works, but those mental models are incorrect in fundamental ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Finally, Bucciarelli is right that systems like telephony are so inherently complex, have been built on top of so many different layers in so many different places, that no one person can ever actually understand how the whole thing works. This is the fundamental nature of complex technologies: our knowledge of these systems will always be partial, at best. Yes, AI will make this situation worse. But it’s a situation that we’ve been in for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p2127-since-the-world-wide-phone-system-nobody-knows-how-the-whole-system-works/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p2127-since-the-world-wide-phone-system-nobody-knows-how-the-whole-system-works/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>When will the first Winter Olympics have a Canadian of Filipino heritage as a prominent reporter? 2030? 2034? 2038? My bet: 2034</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I am patient, until then I would be happy with a Canadian of Indigenous, Indian, Pakistani, Bangladeshi or Korean or Vietnamese, etc heritage :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p1723-winter-olympics-canadian-filipino-heritage-prominent-reporter-2030-2034-2038/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p1723-winter-olympics-canadian-filipino-heritage-prominent-reporter-2030-2034-2038/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl-dr-ing; Office time is for socialization, conversation and collaboration but it's not productive solo time and that's fine; office 1 day a week (or more) for those more who have the LUXURY of a nearby office plus remote the rest is probably best and for those who don't have an office nearby how about. a 1 week onboarding with 1 more more colleagues at a nearby office or coworking space within a year of joining?; Harold Jarche:: sleepy subversion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 9, 2026 01:07 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://jarche.com/2026/01/sleepy-subversion/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl-dr-ing; Office time is for socialization, conversation and collaboration but it’s not productive solo time and that’s fine; office 1 day a week (or more) for those more who have the LUXURY of a nearby office plus remote the rest is probably best and for those who don’t have an office nearby how about. a 1 week onboarding with 1 more more colleagues at a nearby office or coworking space within a year of joining?; Harold Jarche:: sleepy subversion&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Over ten years ago I wrote that we need to flip the office. Instead of going to work, we should be going to socialize, converse, and collaborate. Productive solo time is not for the office. Knowledge workers can be productive anywhere but at the office. This is just as pertinent today. There are times when people need to be together, though with video conferencing and proper meeting management we can get a lot done with distributed work.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p1707-remote-workers-just-productive-as-remote-workers-sleepy-subversion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p1707-remote-workers-just-productive-as-remote-workers-sleepy-subversion/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: of course Art can just be words :-) Dan Sinker:: Foundational Texts: Jenny Holzer's Truisms</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 8, 2026 19:02 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://dansinker.com/posts/2026-01-31-ft-holzer/&quot;&gt;ME:: of course Art can just be words :-) Dan Sinker:: Foundational Texts: Jenny Holzer’s Truisms&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- QUOTE: “&lt;strong&gt;Art could be just words&lt;/strong&gt;. Art could be just at home slapped on a POST NO BILLS wall as it could in a gallery. And art could be angry and blunt and even funny sometimes and it could be unapologetic for being all of those things at once. It was all entirely new for me, something I would grab onto and hold dear for decades. Truisms was, for me, absolutely a bedrock-level foundational text.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p1102-2026-01-31-art-can-be-words-jenny-holzer-dan-sinker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p1102-2026-01-31-art-can-be-words-jenny-holzer-dan-sinker/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: In Vancouver (and probably all of BC), 33% whipped containers go in the mixed containers bin and are therefore not eligible to get the 10 cent deposit back ; Return-It:: Milk Container Recycling in British Columbia Frequently Asked Question</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Feb 8, 2026 18:37 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.return-it.ca/beverage/faqs/general-milk/&quot;&gt;ME:: In Vancouver (and probably all of BC), 33% whipped containers go in the mixed containers bin and are therefore not eligible to get the 10 cent deposit back ; Return-It:: Milk Container Recycling in British Columbia Frequently Asked Question&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: “Containers that are NOT included in the program are those not meant primarily as “ready-to-drink”, such as infant formula, meal replacement or dietary supplements, coffee cream and other coffee additives, &lt;strong&gt;whipping cream&lt;/strong&gt;, buttermilk, drinkable yogurt and kefir.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p1037-whipping-cream-cartons-go-in-mixed-containers-not-eligible-for-deposit-vancouver-bc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2026/02/08/p1037-whipping-cream-cartons-go-in-mixed-containers-not-eligible-for-deposit-vancouver-bc/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
