<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 18:09:32 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 18:09:32 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tad: A fast viewer for CSV and Parquet files and SQLite and DuckDb databases that supports large files.  &lt;-- Nice alternative to (in no order) dirtylittlesql.com, graphext, knime, visidata, datasette, xsv, csvkit, R tidyverse with arrow, python pandas / dask, as well as the traditional grep / uniq / cut / sed / awk / sort / uniq etc   </title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt; Sep 20, 2022 17:49 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tadviewer.com/&quot;&gt;Tad&lt;/a&gt;:  A fast viewer for &lt;strong&gt;CSV&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Parquet&lt;/strong&gt; files and &lt;strong&gt;SQLite&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;DuckDb&lt;/strong&gt; databases that supports large files. (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/antonycourtney/status/1572353401341771777&quot;&gt;this tweet&lt;/a&gt; from Antony Courtney which was in response to Simon W’s tweet: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/simonw/status/1572285367382061057&quot;&gt;If someone gives you a CSV file with 100,000 rows in it, what tools do you use to start exploring and understanding that data&lt;/a&gt;? )&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;March 2022: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/03/27/p1-firefox-sumo-317-support-questions-2021-june4-firefox89-new-look-and-feel/&quot;&gt;2021  SUMO Firefox Desktop Support Questions in a SQLite file: 317 questions  on June 4, 2021 about Firefox look and feel changes in Firefox 89 (used  DB Browser for SQLite, csvstack, csvs-to-sqlite)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;February 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/02/23/p1-sqlite-csv-json-the-eternal-golden-braid-sqlitebrowser/&quot;&gt;SQLite,  JSON, CSV :-) the eternal golden braid of formats? so many tools for  normal folks to grok them without programming e.g. sqlitebrowser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 2019: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2019/04/21/p2-howto-use-miller-mlr-to-create-csv-file-with-urls-from-ids/&quot;&gt;How  to use mlr (miller) to create an id, url CSV file from a file of ids by  concatenating ‘support.mozilla.org/questions/’ to the id&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;October 2018:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/10/20/p1-csv-to-json-mr-data-converter/&quot;&gt;Mr Data Converter converts CSV to JSON, HTML, JSON, XML, Python, ruby, etc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/20/p1-tad-fast-viewer-csv-parquet-sqlite-datasette-alternative/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/20/p1-tad-fast-viewer-csv-parquet-sqlite-datasette-alternative/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sticker Drop on the App Store for iOS 16 - lift your fav part of an image and turn it into a digital sticker</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt; Sep 19, 2022 18:07 &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/sticker-drop/id1629369500?uo=2&quot;&gt;Sticker Drop on the App Store&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Lift your favourite part out of an image and turn it into a digital sticker!&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– fun! An excuse to upgrade to iOS 16 and finally make my own iMessage stickers that I’ve been procrastinating for 5 years :-) !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May 2017: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/05/03/p1-more-sticker-apps-to-try/&quot;&gt;imoji, momento and stickerbot - more iOS sticker apps to try in addition to assembly and sticker boost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;September 2016: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2016/09/18/p1-what-instagram-and-sumo-imessage-stickers/&quot;&gt;What kind of iMessage stickers should I make from Instagram and support.mozilla.org information visualizations?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/19/p1-sticker-drop-for-ios-16/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/19/p1-sticker-drop-for-ios-16/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Russell A. Poldrack: Statistical Thinking for the 21st Century</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt; Sep 6, 2022 20:48: &lt;a href=&quot;https://statsthinking21.github.io/statsthinking21-core-site/&quot;&gt;Russell A. Poldrack: Statistical Thinking for the 21st Century&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://statsthinking21.org/&quot;&gt;(main web site with R and Python companions&lt;/a&gt;) &amp;lt;– QUOTE: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The goal of this book is to the tell the story of statistics as it is used today by researchers around the world. It’s a different story than the one told in most introductory statistics books, which focus on teaching how to use a set of tools to achieve very specific goals. This book focuses on understanding the basic ideas of statistical thinking — a systematic way of thinking about how we describe the world and use data make decisions and predictions, all in the context of the inherent uncertainty that exists in the real world. It also brings to bear current methods that have only become feasible in light of the amazing increases in computational power that have happened in the last few decades. Analyses that would have taken years in the 1950’s can now be completed in a few seconds on a standard laptop computer, and this power unleashes the ability to use computer simulation to ask questions in new and powerful ways.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://statsthinking21.github.io/statsthinking21-core-site/introduction.html#what-is-statistical-thinking&quot;&gt;section 1.1&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Statistical thinking is a way of understanding a complex world by describing it in relatively simple terms that nonetheless capture essential aspects of its structure or function, and that also provide us some idea of how uncertain we are about that knowledge. The foundations of statistical thinking come primarily from mathematics and statistics, but also from computer science, psychology, and other fields of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We can distinguish statistical thinking from other forms of thinking that are less likely to describe the world accurately. In particular, human intuition often tries to answer the same questions that we can answer using statistical thinking, but often gets the answer wrong. For example, in recent years most Americans have reported that they think that violent crime was worse compared to the previous year (Pew Research Center). However, a statistical analysis of the actual crime data shows that in fact violent crime has steadily decreased since the 1990’s. Intuition fails us because we rely upon best guesses (which psychologists refer to as heuristics) that can often get it wrong. For example, humans often judge the prevalence of some event (like violent crime) using an availability heuristic – that is, how easily can we think of an example of violent crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;August 2017: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/08/06/p1-modern-dive-really-is-a-modern-introduction-to-r/&quot;&gt;Really  enjoying: Modern Dive - An Introduction to Statistical and Data  Sciences via R -  really is a modern introduction to statistics, modern R  programming, ggplot2 and the tidyverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/18/p1-russell-a-poldrack-statistical-thinking-21st-century/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/18/p1-russell-a-poldrack-statistical-thinking-21st-century/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leah Elliott: Contra Chr*me – a webcomic – How G*ogle's browser became a threat to privacy and democracy, a 2019 re-do of Scott McCloud‘s 2008: G*ogle-commissioned Chr*me comic</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt; Sep 9, 2022 18:15  Leah Elliott: &lt;a href=&quot;https://contrachrome.com/&quot;&gt;Contra Chr*me – a webcomic – How G*ogle’s browser became a threat to privacy and democracy, a 2019 re-do of Scott McCloud‘s 2008: G*ogle-commissioned Chr*me comic &lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– a re-do in G*\ggle is e*il stylee :-) In German and French as well as English!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Previously:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;April 2005: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2005/04/30/google-jumps-the-shark-by-offering-ads-not-tied-to-keywords/&quot;&gt;G*ogle jumps the shark by offering ads not tied to keywords?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;February 2005: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2005/02/08/google-becomes-bigco-and-terminates-blogger-for-being-too-transparent-and-exposing-what-could-be-viewed-as-their-evil/&quot;&gt;G*ogle becomes Bigco and terminates blogger for being too transparent and exposing what could be viewed as their “evil”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/10/p1-leah-elliott-contra-chrome-webcomic-google-browser-threat/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/10/p1-leah-elliott-contra-chrome-webcomic-google-browser-threat/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zack Scholl: croc Fast, simple, and e2e encrypted file transfer between any two computers. &lt;- so many great CLI tools so little time. See 'Previously'</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zack’s blog post: &lt;a href=&quot;https://schollz.com/blog/croc6/&quot;&gt;croc: Fast, simple, and secure file transfer between any two computers.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code and docs: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/schollz/croc&quot;&gt;https://github.com/schollz/croc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It requires a public relay server which is $40-50 a month. See this croc github issue: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/schollz/croc/issues/453&quot;&gt;This project needs your help again #453&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are so many of these nifty command line tools! e.g. rg: grep in rust&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Previously:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/12/19/p1-thej-extract-data-html-json-xhtml-xidel/&quot;&gt;Thej: Extract Data from HTML/XML/JSON using Xidel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/05/23/p1-interactive-multiple-file-search-replace-using-fdfind-sad-instead-of-sed/&quot;&gt;Interactive  Multiple File Search and Replace using fd aka fdfind and sad instead of  sed; use sd for just stdin replacement; also check out diff-so-fancy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/04/p1-croc-fast-e2e-file-text-sharing-between-two-computers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/09/04/p1-croc-fast-e2e-file-text-sharing-between-two-computers/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I have 3 laptops and 2 Raspberry Pis: one or more of them is always online, couldn't I use them as my own CDN to serve a static website?</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As per my previous post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/08/27/p1-free-hosting-private-companies-heroku-slack-does-not-work-bring-on-the-un-black-helicopters-aka-free-government-hosting/&quot;&gt;Free  hosting from for profit companies like Heroku, Slack etc doesn’t work.  Don’t depend on it! Only viable long term solution is for the UN Black  Helicopters :-) i.e. the government needs to offer hosting&lt;/a&gt;, I don’t really trust “the Cloud” especially “free” cloud sesrvices.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have 3 laptops and 2 Raspberry Pis: one or more of them is always online, couldn’t I use them as my own CDN to serve a static website?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The whole notion of clients and servers is silly in 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Previously: June 6, 2006: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2006/06/06/my-n70-runs-raccoon-nokias-port-of-apache/&quot;&gt;My N70 runs raccoon, Nokia’s port of Apache&lt;/a&gt; with this juicy quote:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check out my N70 running the &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensource.nokia.com/projects/mobile-web-server/index.html&quot;&gt;Nokia open source port of Apache&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/project/showfiles.php?group_id=167580&quot;&gt;Raccoon&lt;/a&gt; at: 
http://roland.tanglao.guest.at.openlaboratory.net/ &amp;lt;– too bad nothing came of it,  all computers are servers and clients in 2022 it seems to me! If a Nokia phone could run a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;server&lt;/code&gt; in 2022 than my laptops and Pis can run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;servers&lt;/code&gt; in 2022!!!!!!!!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/08/28/p1-my-own-cdn-with-my-3-laptops-raspberry-pis/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/08/28/p1-my-own-cdn-with-my-3-laptops-raspberry-pis/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Free hosting from for profit companies like Heroku, Slack etc doesn't work. Don't depend on it! Only viable long term solution is for the UN Black Helicopters :-) i.e. the government needs to offer hosting</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rtanglao/status/1563327476449054721&quot;&gt;My tweet about free doesn’t last forever (but to be fair H*roku’s free lasted 15 years)!&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;i'm biased obvs so i won't comment on Sl*ck or H*roku but eventually you have to pay for free stuff. So if you can, it's better to use free open source stuff from day 1 since FOSS stuff almost always offers an export path from day 1 even if the FOSS stuff is harder at the start.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rtanglao/status/1563552664851742721&quot;&gt;My tweet about free hosting should be offered by the government&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Get off my lawn &quot;incomprehensible to oldsters like me&quot; &quot;dyno pricing model&quot; :-) I feel and am probably wrong as always :-) that governments and educational institutions should run &quot;simple&quot; :-) free hosting for open source and small hobby projects.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Probably won’t happen but I can dream can’t I?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Previously: April 2017: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/04/15/p1-mastodon-on-heroku/&quot;&gt;How to deploy mastodon on heroku - use the deploy button?!?&lt;/a&gt;  which had the following “great” :-) quotes
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;I still don’t understand Heroku’s pricing model.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tootsuite/documentation/blob/master/Running-Mastodon/Heroku-guide.md&quot;&gt;Official docs which state you can’t do reply mastodon  on free dynos&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Running on Heroku's hobby Dynos and free add-on tiers has limited testing purposes and is not recommended in production.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/08/27/p1-free-hosting-private-companies-heroku-slack-does-not-work-bring-on-the-un-black-helicopters-aka-free-government-hosting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/08/27/p1-free-hosting-private-companies-heroku-slack-does-not-work-bring-on-the-un-black-helicopters-aka-free-government-hosting/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vanbikes: Vancouver's Bicycle People &amp; the Fight for Transportation Change, 1986-2011 - Highly Recommended</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you want to learn about Vancouver bicycling activism and activism in general and how it’s a long game full of amazing folks then please buy or borrow from the library (it’s at VPL!):  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vanbikes.ca/&quot;&gt;Vanbikes&lt;/a&gt;: Vancouver’s Bicycle People &amp;amp; the Fight for Transportation Change, 1986-2011 by Colin Stein! Highly recommended! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vanbikes.ca/store&quot;&gt;Order the book at Colin’s site&lt;/a&gt; if you have the $. $25 for the PDF, $50 for the book. I have a copy (and Barb and I are on page 310 :-), see if you can spot us!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/colinmstein/status/1546197493762834437&quot;&gt;Colin has an amazing twitter thread&lt;/a&gt; that answers a lot of the questions you may have. Please check that out too!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/08/14/p1-colin-stein-vanbikes-vancouvers-bicycle-people-fight-transportation-change-1986-2011/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/08/14/p1-colin-stein-vanbikes-vancouvers-bicycle-people-fight-transportation-change-1986-2011/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cypress Challenge 2022: a few minutes slower than the last 'real' one in 2019 but happy!</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Last Sunday was the Cypress Challenge for 2022. According to the official results I was a 8 minutes slower in 2022 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startlinetiming.com/en/races/2022/cypress/view/106&quot;&gt;1 hour and 9 minutes&lt;/a&gt;) than 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.startlinetiming.com/en/races/2019/cypress/view/173&quot;&gt;1 hour and 15 seconds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But it was fun (and hot :-) !&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;$300K raised for Pancreatic Cancer research!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/people/Sjors-Liem/100008401188522/&quot;&gt;Sjors&lt;/a&gt; for riding with me!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thanks to those who sponsored me and our team &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.bccancerfoundation.com/site/TR/Events/CypressChallenge?team_id=25840&amp;amp;pg=team&amp;amp;fr_id=4125&quot;&gt;Sofia’s Camera Club&lt;/a&gt;! Pancreatic research benefits from your generous donations!!!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously-from-2021&quot;&gt;Previously from 2021&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/09/03/p1-cypress-challenge-tour-de-cure-bicycling-2021/&quot;&gt;Cypress Challenge 2021 - Tour de Cure 2021 160km ‘century ride’ formerly known as the Ride to Conquer Cancer - Bicycling as therapy and to fund cancer research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;strava-embed&quot;&gt;Strava Embed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;strava-embed-placeholder&quot; data-embed-type=&quot;activity&quot; data-embed-id=&quot;7600380573&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/08/13/p1-cypress-challenge-2022-2022-08-07-a-few-minutes-slower/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/08/13/p1-cypress-challenge-2022-2022-08-07-a-few-minutes-slower/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New tools for thought are a wee step forward from wikis and mindmapping because they are open source, easier to host and share unlike past tools like wikis</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt; Jul 26, 2022 18:32 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.synesthesia.co.uk/2022/07/27/revisiting-the-power-of-context/&quot;&gt;Revisiting ‘The Power of Context’ | Synesthesia&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;— The power is that these tools for thought are more readily available, easier to share and easier to host. Wikis have historically  been not so simple to host (compare how many blog alternatives there are and how few wiki alternatives there were) and share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;juicy---quote&quot;&gt;Juicy :-) Quote&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;These days it seems we hear of “nothing but” the power of associative thinking 
in the context of Zettelkasten or digital gardens, driven by the core principle 
of breaking ideas down into atomic concepts to support re-combination and 
serendipitous insight.

However what many who focus on those current trends ignore (or are perhaps
unaware of) is the very long history of tools that support this way of 
working (e.g. wiki, 1995, mind-mapping, 1970 ).

So what, exactly, is the new context added by digital gardens? I’m not sure I
know yet at a technical level. One clear benefit at an information level is 
that there is no shortage of discussion on how to use those tools to 
support thinking, but I would suggest much of that could be applied to any technology.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;previously-from-june-2017&quot;&gt;Previously from June 2017:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2017/06/09/p1-going-to-summarize-technical-topics/&quot;&gt;tl;dr tech stuff - Going to summarize tech stuff on my future wiki&lt;/a&gt;     &amp;lt;— 5 years later and I still haven’t setup my own wiki. Oops :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/07/31/p1-new-digital-gardens-tools-for-thought-easy-to-update-personal-wiki/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2022/07/31/p1-new-digital-gardens-tools-for-thought-easy-to-update-personal-wiki/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
