<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:50:31 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 07:50:31 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tantek post from 2018:: Post Positive things Promptly PPTP :-)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 16, 2024. 07:41 Classic &lt;a href=&quot;https://tantek.com/2018/364/t5/post-that-day-then-date-time-previous-week-month&quot;&gt;Tantek post from 2018:: Post Positive things Promptly PPTP :-)&lt;/a&gt;   &amp;lt;– I agree! &lt;a href=&quot;https://tantek.com/2018/364/t5/post-that-day-then-date-time-previous-week-month&quot;&gt;Read the whole thing from 2018&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;When posting positive things promptly*, I think it first makes sense to post positive things from that day (for reason 6**), and then from previous days (that week, or month), in pure date-time order (oldest to newest), regardless of subject (topic) or type of post (e.g. text note vs. photo).&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/16/p0741-post-that-day-then-date-time-previous-week-month/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/16/p0741-post-that-day-then-date-time-previous-week-month/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: 2030 is when folks don't realize they're browsing a fake internet using GenAI generated pages raganwald 🍓::  'How long before G⭕ogle goes back to showing you search results, but every result on the front page is generated in real-time by GenAI? How long before a large population of users think that they're browsing `the web`, but it's all fake pages written just for them at that moment?' - mastodon@bau-ha.us</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 15, 2024 07:22 &lt;a href=&quot;https://social.bau-ha.us/@raganwald/113657396478306139&quot;&gt;Me:: 2030 is when folks don’t realize they’re browsing a fake internet using GenAI generated pages raganwald 🍓::  “How long before G⭕ogle goes back to showing you search results, but every result on the front page is generated in real-time by GenAI? How long before a large population of users think that they’re browsing “the web,” but it’s all fake pages written just for them at that moment?” - mastodon@bau-ha.us&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;lt;– Sadly I think that moment has already arrived for some folks using GenAI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/15/p0722-113657396478306139-browsing-fake-genai-generated-internet-2030/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/15/p0722-113657396478306139-browsing-fake-genai-generated-internet-2030/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>microsoft/markitdown: Python tool for converting files and office documents e.g. PDF, Word, Excel, Images, Audio, speech transcription, html including Wikipedia, csv, json, json, xml to Markdown.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 14, 2024 21:17 &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/microsoft/markitdown&quot;&gt;microsoft/markitdown: Python tool for converting files and office documents e.g. PDF, Word, Excel, Images, Audio, speech transcription, html including Wikipedia, csv, json, json, xml to Markdown.&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://daringfireball.net/linked/2024/12/13/markitdown&quot;&gt;Daring Fireball via MarkItDown: Python Tool for Converting Files and Office Documents to Markdown&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– sounds great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The MarkItDown library is a utility tool for converting various files to Markdown (e.g., for indexing, text analysis, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It presently supports:  PDF (.pdf), PowerPoint (.pptx), Word (.docx), Excel (.xlsx), Images (EXIF metadata, and OCR), Audio (EXIF metadata, and speech transcription), HTML (special handling of Wikipedia, etc.), Various other text-based formats (csv, json, xml, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/14/p2117-markitdown/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/14/p2117-markitdown/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: ML should belong to governments like nuclear fission and fusion Alexander Hartley:: To Whom Does the World Belong? - Boston Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 13, 2024 09:25 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonreview.net/articles/to-whom-does-the-world-belong&quot;&gt;Me:: ML should belong to governments like nuclear fission and fusion Alexander Hartley:: To Whom Does the World Belong? - Boston Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bostonreview.net/articles/to-whom-does-the-world-belong&quot;&gt;To Whom Does the World Belong? - Boston Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We may wish to consider a still more fundamental question. If AI is as potentially capital-accumulating, dangerous, and powerful as its developers claim, should we allow private companies to hold patents on this technology at all? If the idea seems crazy, that’s only a sign of our neoliberal times. Entrepreneur Charles Jennings, himself a former tech CEO, draws a comparison between AI and nuclear fission and fusion. When Harry Truman created the Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) in 1946, he concentrated ownership and authority over nuclear power in an arm of government relatively insulated from day-to-day politics. The federal government’s role in nationalizing nuclear weapons was that of owner, not operator—it outsourced most of the work. The military possessed finished bombs, Westinghouse built and operated nuclear energy plants, but the AEC controlled the core and had all the leverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;AI pioneer Geoffrey Hinton fears what nationalization would mean in the hands of figures like D⭕nald Tr🇺mp, Vl🅰dimir P🇺tin, and Xi JInping. Here the analogy with nuclear technology presents a bleak sort of consolation. Concentrating power over atomic weapons in the hands of the executive branch has been, by any measure, terrifically dangerous. But could anyone seriously argue we would be in a safer world than the one we are in if this power were concentrated in the private branches of the military-industrial complex, and if nuclear blueprints and resources were the private possessions of large corporations?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/13/p0925-to-whom-does-the-world-belong/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/13/p0925-to-whom-does-the-world-belong/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Centralized social media are like Mainframes and Malls I agree Ted Gioia:: Are Social Media Platforms the Next Dying Malls</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 13, 2024 07:51 &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/@tedgioia/p-152031677&quot;&gt;Me:: Centralized social media are like Mainframes and Malls I agree Ted Gioia:: Are Social Media Platforms the Next Dying Malls&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– And because they are like mainframes  and malls :-) it takes a long time for them to truly die :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-point-5-from-ted--these-bunkers-were-never-real-communities-and-never-will-be-theyre-just-businessesoften-run-with-distrust-or-contempt-for-their-users&quot;&gt;Great point #5 from Ted  These bunkers were never real communities, and never will be. They’re just businesses—often run with distrust or contempt for their users.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(of course read the whole thing:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/@tedgioia/p-152031677]&quot;&gt;Ted Gioia:: Are Social Media Platforms the Next Dying Malls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the start, malls were artificial constructs designed to maximize profits for the owners—and this was insufficient to create a true community, a sense of shared purpose, or enduring loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same is true of social media. The owners of these platforms don’t even pretend otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last three years, they stopped trying to build communities, and shifted to promoting addictive scrolling and swiping. They manipulate their users with a smug attitude that can only be described as contempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just look at the terms and conditions. Imagine launching a business in your neighborhood and telling new customers this…
Screenshot of privacy disclosure on Threads
From the privacy disclosure on Threads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s not how you build a community. It’s how you exploit addicts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/13/p0751-p-152031677-ted-gioia-social-media-dying-platforms-mainframes-malls/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/13/p0751-p-152031677-ted-gioia-social-media-dying-platforms-mainframes-malls/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>$ycophants gotta $ychophant :-) or something</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 12, 2024 19:30 &lt;a href=&quot;https://devdilettante.com/@roland/113643375422686910&quot;&gt;$ycophants gotta $ychophant :-) or something&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;–nothing more needs to be said :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/12/p1930-113643375422686910-sycophants-gotta-sycophant/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/12/p1930-113643375422686910-sycophants-gotta-sycophant/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Charlie Stross: quoting Scitechdaily:  'Needle-Free: New Nano-Vaccine Effective Against All COVID-19 variants' - The Wandering Shop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 12, 2024 09:02 &lt;a href=&quot;https://wandering.shop/@cstross/113640882989709521&quot;&gt;Charlie Stross: quoting Scitechdaily:  “Needle-Free: New Nano-Vaccine Effective Against All COVID-19 variants” - The Wandering Shop&lt;/a&gt; –&amp;gt; Read while thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://scitechdaily.com/needle-free-new-nano-vaccine-effective-against-all-covid-19-variants/&quot;&gt;Scitechdaily: Needle-Free: New Nano-Vaccine Effective Against All COVID-19 variants&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(Administered as intranasal spray, stable at room temperature, broad spectrum. No word on whether/when it'll be available.)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/12/p0902-113640882989709521/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/12/p0902-113640882989709521/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: DHGDH :-) The revolt against experts has been very calculated and very R🇪publican – Kevin Drum</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 12, 2024 00:30 &lt;a href=&quot;https://jabberwocking.com/47215-2/&quot;&gt;Me:: DHGDH :-) The revolt against experts has been very calculated and very R🇪publican – Kevin Drum&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– dominant hegemony gotta dominant hegemony henceforth abbreviated as DHGDH :-) –&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;But it is wrong - it is not disdain that has driven the experts away from R🇪publicans, it is policy that people who know what they are talking about know is destructive. It is conservatives who are thin skinned, experts are used to dealing in facts.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/12/p0030-47215-revolt-against-experts-dhgdh/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/12/p0030-47215-revolt-against-experts-dhgdh/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ducky Sherwood:: oral minocycline significantly helped 89% of long COVID patients 2024-12-07 General – Pandemics in British Columbia</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 11, 2024 23:55 &lt;a href=&quot;https://covidbc.webfoot.com/2024/12/07/2024-12-07-general/&quot;&gt;Ducky Sherwood:: oral minocycline significantly helped 89% of long COVID patients 2024-12-07 General – Pandemics in British Columbia&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;⭐ ❗❗This paper from Japan (2024-12-02) reported that oral minocycline significantly helped 89% of long COVID patients in what was effectively a big case study, especially when given in the first six months. There was improvement in fatigue, post-exertional malaise, unrefreshing sleep, brain fog, disequilibrium, orthostatic intolerance, and neuropathic pain. (Minocycline is an antibiotic, but also has a number of protective effects on neurons.)&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;- Read the whole thing! Need more studies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caveats-again-quoting-ducky&quot;&gt;Caveats again quoting Ducky&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oral minocycline does frequently give unpleasant levels of nausea and/or dizziness, so it’s not an ideal medicine. Also please note that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not everyone was helped;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who had ME/CFS for longer were helped less;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This was not a randomized trial — there was no control group, so partly this might be placebo effect.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;These weren’t the sickest Long COVID patients: people had to be able to stand and walk (and, it appears, to come to a hospital) in order to participate in the study.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most of the improvement was in people who had Long COVID for less than six months, so maybe they would have recovered on their own.
However, it is encouraging news!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/11/p2355-2024-12-07-ducky-covid-general/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/11/p2355-2024-12-07-ducky-covid-general/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Generative AI is hard to use (Super subtle nuance: Code Interpreter can't make API requests; Canvas can't access uploaded files) like Excel but you only need to use a small portion of their features to benefit Simon Willison:: ChatGPT Canvas can make API requests now, but it’s complicated</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 11, 2024 07:33  &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/10/chatgpt-canvas/&quot;&gt;Me:: Generative AI is hard to use (Super subtle nuance: Code Interpreter can’t make API requests; Canvas can’t access uploaded files) like Excel but you only need to use a small portion of their features to benefit Simon Willison:: ChatGPT Canvas can make API requests now, but it’s complicated&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;lt;– The API stuff as of December 11, 2024 appears super hard to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the Whole Thing -&amp;gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/10/chatgpt-canvas/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison:: ChatGPT Canvas can make API requests now, but it’s complicated&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
This is really, really confusing

Do you find this all hopelessly confusing? I don’t blame you. I’m a professional web developer and a Python engineer of 20+ years and I can just about understand and internalize the above set of rules.

I don’t really have any suggestions for where we go from here. This stuff is hard to use. The more features and capabilities we pile onto these systems the harder it becomes to obtain true mastery of them and really understand what they can do and how best to put them into practice.

Maybe this doesn’t matter? I don’t know anyone with true mastery of Excel—to the point where they could compete in last week’s Microsoft Excel World Championship—and yet plenty of people derive enormous value from Excel despite only scratching the surface of what it can do.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/11/p0733-chatgpt-canvas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/11/p0733-chatgpt-canvas/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
