<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:12:30 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 14:12:30 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: gotta try this on my 5D Mark 1 aka Classic some day to get time lapse, focus peaking, zebras, and other goodies :-) ; a1ex:: October 2012:: &amp;lsqb;UNMAINTAINED&amp;rsqb; Canon 5D Classic Firmware  ** Beta 4 **</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 23, 2025 20:58 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.magiclantern.fm/forum/index.php?topic=1010.0&quot;&gt;ME:: gotta try this on my 5D Mark 1 aka Classic some day to get time lapse, focus peaking, zebras, and other goodies :-) ; a1ex:: October 2012:: &amp;amp;lsqb;UNMAINTAINED&amp;amp;rsqb; Canon 5D Classic Firmware  ** Beta 4 **&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/23/p1358-2012-magic-lantern-for-canon-5d-mark-i/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/23/p1358-2012-magic-lantern-for-canon-5d-mark-i/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recipes that work according to fab colleague Tarandeep :-) ; Julie The Simple Veganista:: Lemony Quinoa + Chickpea Salad - </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 23, 2025 19:23 &lt;a href=&quot;https://simple-veganista.com/quinoa-chickpea-salad/&quot;&gt;Recipes that work according to fab colleague Tarandeep :-) ; Julie The Simple Veganista:: Lemony Quinoa + Chickpea Salad - &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/23/p1223-quinoa-chickpea-salad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/23/p1223-quinoa-chickpea-salad/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: I didn't know DateTime was deprecated! Mav Tipi:: Should I Use Date, Time, or DateTime in Ruby and Rails? ¦The Startup ¦ Medium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 20, 2025 14:38 &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/swlh/should-i-use-date-time-or-datetime-in-ruby-and-rails-9372ad20ca4f&quot;&gt;ME:: I didn’t know DateTime was deprecated! Mav Tipi:: Should I Use Date, Time, or DateTime in Ruby and Rails? ¦The Startup ¦ Medium&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;–  September 2020 ruby language commit from nurse:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ruby/date/commit/58ca6e6a3ee20c72a77266e0f74920b12a06ee9d&quot;&gt;DateTime class is considered deprecated. Use Time class&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As of Ruby 3 (released December 24th, 2020, as is Ruby tradition), DateTime only exists for backwards-compatibility. The date library docs recommend you just use Time instead. (I’m pretty sure this was essentially true from 2.0 forward, but now it’s formally true.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you’re someone who googles around for answers (which you are, that’s why you’re here), keep this in mind! A lot of old articles are now misleading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This simplifies our question by a lot. The biggest difference between Date and Time is that Date is concerned with days and above; if you care at all about hours, minutes, seconds and below, or think you might care about them in the future, you have to use Time. Date can’t handle any of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On the other hand, here are some things Date can do better than Time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/20/p0738-should-i-use-date-time-or-datetime-in-ruby-and-rails-9372ad20ca4f/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/20/p0738-should-i-use-date-time-or-datetime-in-ruby-and-rails-9372ad20ca4f/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Sounds like a great optimistic yet pessimistic retro history book so I ordered the 2019 edition with a new introduction ; Reviewed By Bruce Sterling:: March 24, 2008:: The Shock of the Old by David Edgerton</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 19, 2025 23:42 &lt;a href=&quot;http://strangehorizons.com/wordpress/non-fiction/reviews/the-shock-of-the-old-by-david-edgerton/&quot;&gt;ME:: Sounds like a great optimistic yet pessimistic retro history book so I ordered the 2019 edition with a new introduction ; Reviewed By Bruce Sterling:: March 24, 2008:: The Shock of the Old by David Edgerton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing i.e. review by Bruce Sterling:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://strangehorizons.com/wordpress/non-fiction/reviews/the-shock-of-the-old-by-david-edgerton/&quot;&gt;Strange Horizons - The Shock of the Old by David Edgerton By Bruce Sterling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Having said all this—or rather, having paraphrased it—I now come to the part of the review where I lodge a mild protest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every futurist who’s any good is a historian—because the future is a kind of history that hasn’t happened yet. And, just as Dr Edgerton analyzes, futurism is old. Futurism tends to repeat the same things over and over again. World peace and universal communication, for instance: they were going to be brought to us by railroads, and then telegraphs, airplanes, then television, satellites, the Internet. These days, five minutes with the Internet is enough to tell that world peace is the last thing on its collective mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The reason for this is not that futurists are frauds or shallow; they are persistently describing an old human aspiration. Aspirations are old, but not passé. If you look into the past, obviously there’s no world peace and universal communication there. Everybody who made an effort at achieving it, H.G. Wells in painful particular, fell far short. If you want a more immediate assessment of our raw, tortuous, gloomy human condition, you can try Thomas Pynchon or J.G. Ballard (two novelists Dr Edgerton goes out of his way to praise).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I happen to much prefer Pynchon and Ballard to Wells myself. Still, trying to write Wells out of the historical picture as some kind of shallow optimist cannot work. People much prefer the Shock of the New to the Shock of the Old because people desire the living chance to make some fresh mistakes. The lesson of history is that nobody learns the lesson of history, and in the long run we are all dead. Yet the pageant of history isn’t a victimology. It’s a parade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We start as kids who know nothing. If we’re lucky, we end as tottering geezers who lack new tricks and have forgotten most of the things we should have learned. That’s us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We’re not Walter Benjamin’s Angel of History, who stares at the rubble in horror as he’s flung backward into the future on titanic winds of change. We’re not angels at all, we’re at least half-beast, so we’ve got as much right to go “Wow!” at shiny, useless crap as the next pack-rat and jackdaw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wonder is wired into us. It’s like being twenty years old, and seeing someone gorgeous, naked. Is a skeptic’s cool indifference in order there? Should we make sure to approach that prospect in a sound, old-fashioned way, like our great-grandparents?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Yeah, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/19/p1642-the-shock-of-the-old-by-david-edgerton/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/19/p1642-the-shock-of-the-old-by-david-edgerton/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Affordable housing is not a puzzle or rocket science. Allow and encourage co-housing, co-ops, 4 storey low rise apartments everywhere in the city of Vancouver and multi-dwellings strata and non strata non single family homes everywhere. The government (municipal, provincial and federal all working together) must build affordable rentals and must keep the rent low and keep building affordable rentals and keep allocating them to folks working locally, the 'market' and private developers are incapable of doing this, follow Vienna's example etc etc :-) ; Emilie K Adin::I Love These Streets. Come Walk with Me - Spacing Vancouver</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 18, 2025 23:10 &lt;a href=&quot;https://spacing.ca/vancouver/2025/03/17/i-love-these-streets-come-walk-with-me/&quot;&gt;ME:: Affordable housing is not a puzzle or rocket science. Allow and encourage co-housing, co-ops, 4 storey low rise apartments everywhere in the city of Vancouver and multi-dwellings strata and non strata non single family homes everywhere. The government (municipal, provincial and federal all working together) must build affordable rentals and must keep the rent low and keep building affordable rentals and keep allocating them to folks working locally, the “market” and private developers are incapable of doing this, follow Vienna’s example etc etc :-) ; Emilie K Adin::I Love These Streets. Come Walk with Me - Spacing Vancouver&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;While multi-family options can provide a good range of housing choices, affordability options, and some energy efficiency benefits with new construction, allowing more small-lot housing options could provide another piece of the housing puzzle.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– But what do I know, I am not an urban planner :-) I am also not a communist, a capitalist, a socialist, or a libertarian. I believe in all people in their amazing diversity not ideology. All people deserve affordable housing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/18/p1610-i-love-these-streets-come-walk-with-me/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/18/p1610-i-love-these-streets-come-walk-with-me/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: I wonder if I could use this for Firefox for Android 'support is the last QA' :-) tests ; Leland Takamine:: August 2022:: Introducing: Maestro — Painless Mobile UI Automation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 18, 2025 17:11 &lt;a href=&quot;https://maestro.dev/blog/introducing-maestro-painless-mobile-ui-automation&quot;&gt;ME:: I wonder if I could use this for Firefox for Android “support is the last QA” :-) tests ; Leland Takamine:: August 2022:: Introducing: Maestro — Painless Mobile UI Automation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you’ve written UI tests with other frameworks in the past, you can see why we’re so excited about Maestro. It reduces the time to build a functioning UI test by &amp;gt;10x, and more importantly makes updating them just as easy.
Why Maestro?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Maestro is built on learnings from its predecessors (Appium, Espresso, UIAutomator, and XCTest), but we ditched the complexity, kept the good stuff, and added some fundamental improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here are some of the reasons why we believe Maestro is the future of mobile UI testing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Built-in tolerance to flakiness. UI elements will not always be where you expect them, screen tap will not always go through, etc. Maestro embraces the instability of mobile applications and devices, and counters it under the hood.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Built-in tolerance to delays. No need to pepper your tests with sleep() calls. Maestro knows that it might take time to load the content (i.e. over the network) and automatically waits for it (but no longer than required).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Blazingly fast iteration. Tests are interpreted, so no need to compile anything. Maestro is able to continuously monitor your test files and rerun them as they change.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Declarative yet powerful syntax. Define your tests in a simple yaml file.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Simple setup. Maestro is a single binary that works anywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cross-platform. Maestro runs on iOS and Android and supports ReactNative, Flutter, WebViews, and pure Native applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/18/p1011-introducing-maestro-painless-mobile-ui-automation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/18/p1011-introducing-maestro-painless-mobile-ui-automation/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: I should do this with my toots :-) ! ; Will Richardson:: GIF: The Git Interchange Format</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 18, 2025 14:39 &lt;a href=&quot;https://willhbr.net/2025/06/16/gif-the-git-interchange-format/&quot;&gt;ME:: I should do this with my toots :-) ! ; Will Richardson:: GIF: The Git Interchange Format&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Well, the obvious solution is to encode a git repo into an image, so you can share it however you like. This is why I made GIF: The Git Interchange Format. A whole git repo—with history—can be crammed into an animated GIF. Here’s the repo for the project itself, contained within a 153px square image with four frames:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/18/p0739-gif-the-git-interchange-format/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/18/p0739-gif-the-git-interchange-format/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: yay a more intuitive language than jq (which is fab but hard to learn) for filtering JSON ; André Arko:: fx, a language for working with JSON</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 18, 2025 14:32 &lt;a href=&quot;https://andre.arko.net/2025/06/13/2025-06-13-fx/&quot;&gt;ME:: yay a more intuitive language than jq (which is fab but hard to learn) for filtering JSON ; André Arko:: fx, a language for working with JSON&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Good news, you don’t have to learn a new language to filter JSON anymore, thanks to fx. With a docs site at the excellent domain fx.wtf, and the ability to filter interactively or by providing Javascript as arguments, fx is the program I have always wished that jq was.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– via &lt;a href=&quot;https://social.jvns.ca/@b0rk/114704626786265729&quot;&gt;Julia Evans on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/18/p0732-2025-06-13-fx-filtering-language-json-more-intuitive-jq/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/18/p0732-2025-06-13-fx-filtering-language-json-more-intuitive-jq/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Recipes that work:: Jacqui Debono:: Farfalle pasta with smoked salmon &amp;amp; zucchini – The Pasta Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 18, 2025 01:47 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.the-pasta-project.com/farfalle-pasta-with-smoked-salmon-zucchini/&quot;&gt;ME:: Recipes that work:: Jacqui Debono:: Farfalle pasta with smoked salmon &amp;amp; zucchini – The Pasta Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Put a large pan of water onto boil for the pasta. When it starts to boil add some salt and bring to the boil again.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In the meantime, wash the zucchini, pat dry and cut off the ends. Cut the zucchini lengthwise in 4 parts. Cut each quarter in two and cut into cubes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Put the cream in a bowl and mix in the grated ginger, a little orange zest and some black pepper. Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Heat a little olive oil in a frying pan or skillet and add the crushed garlic cloves. As soon as the garlic begins to soften, add the zucchini and sauté for a couple of minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;As soon as the zucchini become translucent, add the smoked salmon in pieces. Remove the garlic.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cook the salmon with the zucchini for a couple of minutes then add the cream mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Turn down the heat, stir well and allow to cook for 5 minutes. Add salt and pepper to taste.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cook the pasta al dente according to the instructions on the packet. When the pasta is ready, save a cup of the cooking water, drain the pasta and add it to the sauce. Mix well. If it seems dry, add a little of the pasta cooking water.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Serve immediately with a sprinkling of orange zest, and pepper if required.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/17/p1847-farfalle-pasta-with-smoked-salmon-zucchini/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/17/p1847-farfalle-pasta-with-smoked-salmon-zucchini/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: love my radar, it's much better than a mirror since it works 140 metres away and you don't have to check, just wait for the beep. Mirrors are fine if you remember to check them :-) ;  MuddyTweed.com:: 2023:: Garmin Varia RTL515 – a review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 17, 2025 00:17 &lt;a href=&quot;https://muddytweed.com/2023/01/24/garmin-varia-rtl515-a-review/&quot;&gt;ME:: love my radar, it’s much better than a mirror since it works 140 metres away and you don’t have to check, just wait for the beep. Mirrors are fine if you remember to check them :-) ;  MuddyTweed.com:: 2023:: Garmin Varia RTL515 – a review&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Why not use a mirror, you might ask? I don’t really like the design of most mirrors, and the others are quite small and don’t give much detail. You also have to frequently look at the mirror, which is sometimes difficult if you’re riding a tough stretch of road. The Varia gives you audio warnings and shows traffic much further away – it really is system you can switch on and forget about. ... I still look around me though. When I see a car come up behind me, I keep an eye on my bike computer to see where and how fast it is approaching. Depending on where I’m riding, I wait until the icon reaches a certain point (about 25m away) and look around to show the driver that I’ve recognised them and see how they act. I can then decide on how to respond.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/16/p1717-garmin-varia-rtl515-a-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/16/p1717-garmin-varia-rtl515-a-review/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
