<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:09:09 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 17:09:09 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Belated condolences to the family of the creator of wood s lot, the best literary blog ever!!! February 2017:: Steve Dodson:: Mark Woods, RIP. : languagehat.com</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 2, 2025 16:51 &lt;a href=&quot;https://languagehat.com/mark-woods-rip/&quot;&gt;Me:: Belated condolences to the family of the creator of wood s lot, the best literary blog ever!!! February 2017:: Steve Dodson:: Mark Woods, RIP. : languagehat.com&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;I don’t know anything about Mark’s life except that he devoted a substantial part of it to producing one of the best sites on the internet, wood s lot, and updating it daily for as long as he could. As I wrote earlier: “He somehow finds the time and energy to put together a collection of images, links, and quotes that make my mind and soul feel a little better stocked.” He was a constant inspiration to me in my own efforts, and I will miss him more than I can say. I hope he and my old friend Mike are sharing thoughts, stories, and outrage somewhere on the other side.&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– Amen!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/02/p1651-mark-woods-rip/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/02/p1651-mark-woods-rip/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: 20 best overproduced npr-style shows er podcasts :-) Marnie Shure:: The 20 Best Podcasts of 2024 - The Atlantic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 2, 2025 15:07 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/culture/archive/2024/12/20-best-podcasts-2024/680853/?gift=j9r7avb6p-KY8zdjhsiSZ-Nz1ObY3CNu6HmTLdFMRBY&quot;&gt;Me:: 20 best overproduced npr-style shows er podcasts :-) Marnie Shure:: The 20 Best Podcasts of 2024 - The Atlantic&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– via &lt;a href=&quot;https://kottke.org/25/01/0045943-the-20-best-podcasts-of&quot;&gt;kottke&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Where is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.ncf.ca/ek867/wood_s_lot.html&quot;&gt;wood s lot&lt;/a&gt; of podcasts :-) ? Tired of these awesome but same old same old npr/cbc/bbc style “shows”. &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Throughout 2024, podcast creators asked us to think twice about our preconceptions: They followed stories that were supposed to be over, engaged with people who tend to get dismissed, and toyed with emerging technologies that make some people fear for humanity’s future. They explored city sewers, an historic baseball stadium, momentary fame, everyday household objects. This list represents the 20 best podcasts I heard this year, with a lean toward either new shows, or shows that have a renewed focus. Virtually all of them, even the most entertaining and quirky ones, suggested an underlying preoccupation with the power of narrative to shape our sense of reality.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/02/p1507-680853-best-podcasts-2024/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/02/p1507-680853-best-podcasts-2024/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: Dave's blogroll from scripting.com is on bluesky, go dave-feedmaster go! @scripting.com on Bluesky:: My 'little feed reader' on bluesky is ready for you to follow. @feediverse.bsky.social</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 2, 2025 07:39 &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/scripting.com/post/3lerbu7ugvc2i&quot;&gt;Me:: Dave’s blogroll from scripting.com is on bluesky, go dave-feedmaster go! @scripting.com on Bluesky:: My “little feed reader” on bluesky is ready for you to follow. @feediverse.bsky.social&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.app/profile/feediverse.bsky.social&quot;&gt;Dave’s blogroll on blue sky aka Little Feed Reader&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;My &quot;little feed reader&quot; on bluesky is ready for you to follow. @feediverse.bsky.social The selection of feeds needs more thought, but at a technical level it appears to work well.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;September 25, 2005 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2005/09/25/rss-remixing-podcast-presentation-and-links/&quot;&gt;RSS Remixing - Podcast, Presentation and Links&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/02/p0739-3lerbu7ugvc2i-little-feed-reader/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/02/p0739-3lerbu7ugvc2i-little-feed-reader/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: like everything else the language of climate change is too often defined by those in power in the global North far away from places most affected by climate change which currently are less developed countries Sanzida Alam Lisa:: The language of climate change: Can global terms capture local realities? | The Business Standard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jan 1, 2025 13:23 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tbsnews.net/thoughts/language-climate-change-can-global-terms-capture-local-realities-1032301&quot;&gt;Me:: like everything else the language of climate change is too often defined by those in power in the global North far away from places most affected by climate change which currently are less developed countries Sanzida Alam Lisa:: The language of climate change: Can global terms capture local realities? ¦ The Business Standard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tbsnews.net/thoughts/language-climate-change-can-global-terms-capture-local-realities-1032301&quot;&gt;Sanzida Alam Lisa:: The language of climate change: Can global terms capture local realities? ¦ The Business Standard&lt;/a&gt;
 via &lt;a href=&quot;https://mastodon.social/@Snoro/113753578450607249&quot;&gt;a toot from Robert Sanscartier&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The language used—technical, detached, and foreign—defines climate change, its risk to vulnerable communities, and how it should be addressed. But does it reflect the reality of Bangladesh, a country on the frontline of the climate crisis?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Bangladesh, the effects of climate change are undeniable, yet the terms imposed by global frameworks often fail to capture the essence of local struggles and experiences. Words like ‘vulnerability,’ ‘adaptation,’ ‘displacement,’ and ‘dispossession’ dominate the discourse. These terms, viewed from a Global North perspective, are disconnected from the lived experiences and realities of communities that have adapted to nature’s unpredictability for generations.
More often than not, it is those in positions of power who construct knowledge. Michel Foucault’s concept of knowledge/power in discourse analysis can be used to explain this dynamic. Foucault argued that power and knowledge are inextricably linked and mutually reinforcing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;While global reports may hail ‘alternative livelihood’ or ‘community empowerment’ as solutions, the Sundarbans’ honey collectors or Shyanmagar’s farmers may see these as distant concepts that neither acknowledge nor address their immediate struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This mismatch between global definitions and local knowledge isn’t just a matter of semantics; it shapes policies, funding priorities, and , ultimately, who gets to decide the future of countries like Bangladesh.
More often than not, it is those in positions of power who construct knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/01/p1323-language-climate-change-can-global-terms-capture-local-realities-1032301/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/01/01/p1323-language-climate-change-can-global-terms-capture-local-realities-1032301/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: HowTo disable Enhanced Visual Search off on your iPhone/iPad: Settings &gt; Apps &gt; Photos &gt; slide 'Enhanced Visual Search' to the left to disable it Jeff Johnson:: Apple Photos phones home on iOS 18 and macOS 15</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 31, 2024 07:32 &lt;a href=&quot;https://lapcatsoftware.com/articles/2024/12/3.html&quot;&gt;Me:: HowTo: Enhanced Visual Search off on your iPhone/iPad: Settings &amp;gt; Apps &amp;gt; Photos &amp;gt; slide ‘Enhanced Visual Search’ to the left to disable it Jeff Johnson:: Apple Photos phones home on iOS 18 and macOS 15&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;This morning while perusing the settings of a bunch of apps on my iPhone, I discovered a new setting for Photos that was enabled by default: Enhanced Visual Search. (I manually disabled it before taking the screenshot below.)&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– Seems like a pointless feature so I turned it off! Yet another proof that Apple is better than most but still has privacy issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;January 5, 2020 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/01/05/p1-iphone-airpod-applewatch-prove-that-total-user-experience-rules/&quot;&gt;2010s lookback: Total user experience rules! Proof is in the iPhone, AirPods and Apple Watch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/31/p0732-apple-photos-phones-home-ios18-macos15/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/31/p0732-apple-photos-phones-home-ios18-macos15/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What kinds of quality don't you care about? Me:: I don't care about pixel quality. I often don't notice teeny tiny pixel level details in software that make others go bonkers Terence Eden:: Most people don’t care about quality</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 30, 2024 16:59 &lt;a href=&quot;https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2024/12/most-people-dont-care-about-quality/&quot;&gt;What kinds of quality don’t you care about? Me:: I don’t care about pixel quality. I often don’t notice teeny tiny pixel level details in software that make others go bonkers Terence Eden:: Most people don’t care about quality&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;But, here's the thing, I don't think anyone other than a photographer would notice or care about those &quot;problems&quot;. If you're a website designer, you're always noticing &quot;jank&quot; on other sites. Your skin crawls at the poor kerning, the FOUT, the lack of keyboard navigation, improper contrast ratio, and a dozen other flaws. 99% of users just don't care. It doesn't impact them in any meaningful way.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;April 29, 2019 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2019/04/29/p1-something-you-thought-was-one-thing-is-two-things-for-me-kapampangan-tagalog/&quot;&gt;Kapampangan and Tagalog: Jenny Odell: When you think something is one thing but it’s actually two things due to your duration and quality of attention&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/30/p1659-most-people-dont-care-about-quality/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/30/p1659-most-people-dont-care-about-quality/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: file this under d⭕minant hegemony gotta d⭕minant hegemony :-) Yes, 🇦mericans are much richer when it comes to stuff than Japanese people (according to rich 🇦mericans like N⭕ah Sm🇮th LOL), easy for N⭕ah to say from his position of privilege, stuff and the ability to 'innovate' is priority 1. Doesn't health, safety and quality of life and less inequality for all matter to entitled, wealthy  🇦mericans :-) ? Evidently not ?!?!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 30, 2024 00:30 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.noahpinion.blog/p/yes-americans-are-much-richer-than&quot;&gt;Me:: file this under d⭕minant hegemony gotta d⭕minant hegemony :-) Yes, 🇦mericans are much richer when it comes to stuff than Japanese people (according to rich 🇦mericans like N⭕ah Sm🇮th LOL), easy for N⭕ah to say from his position of privilege, stuff and the ability to “innovate” is priority 1. Doesn’t health, safety and quality of life and less inequality for all matter to entitled, wealthy  🇦mericans :-) ? Evidently not ?!?!&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;- OMG! Yet another we’re no 1 post from an 🇦merican LOL. It is possible to have a far less violent country that takes care of their fellow citizens better through universal healthcare and other things and that “innovates”. Japan is just one example of country that is better on what many people value: it is safer and healthier and people have time for hobbies ie doing something other than working for 50 weeks a year like most i.e. unprivileged 🇦mericans :-) who get 2 or 3 weeks of holidays at the most and don’t have the money to buy the stuff that Mr. Smith cares so much about!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/30/p0030-yes-americans-are-much-richer-than/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/30/p0030-yes-americans-are-much-richer-than/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A: use backslash K in a regular expression (regex) to remove any text matched before it CRandER:: How to replace the last occurrence of a substring in ruby? - Stack Overflow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 29, 2024 09:34 &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/3185144/how-to-replace-the-last-occurrence-of-a-substring-in-ruby&quot;&gt;A: use backslash K to remove any text matched before it CRandER:: How to replace the last occurrence of a substring in ruby? - Stack Overflow&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Since Ruby 2.0 we can use \K which removes any text matched before it from the returned match. Combine with a greedy operator and you get this&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– For me the following ruby snippet seems to work to remove only the last .php in “.php.blah.php”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;slug&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;slug&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;sub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sr&quot;&gt;/.*\K\.[\D]+$/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;''&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/29/p0934-how-to-replace-the-last-occurrence-of-a-substring-in-ruby/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/29/p0934-how-to-replace-the-last-occurrence-of-a-substring-in-ruby/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>my ruby script that's responsible for my flurry of recent blog posts is called blog_all_open.rb.. It calls blogthis.rb to create blog posts in jekyll format with a nice slug from my all open list items in my 'blog this'  checkvist list 74286 after you type 'y' to approve it</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 28, 2024 17:18  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-checkvist/blob/main/blog_all_open.rb&quot;&gt;my ruby script that’s responsible for my flurry of recent blog posts is called blog_all_open.rb.. It calls blogthis.rb to create a blog posts in jekyll format with a nice slug from my all open list items my ‘blog this’  checkvist list 74286 after you type ‘y’ to approve it&lt;/a&gt; Check it out at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-checkvist/blob/main/blogthis.rb&quot;&gt;github: rt-checkvist/blob/main/blogthis.rb&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-checkvist/blob/main/blog_all_open.rb&quot;&gt;github: rt-checkvist/blob/main/blog_all_open.rb&lt;/a&gt;. It depends on everything being time stamped and having a link at the beginning e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Dec 26, 2024 21:43 [fun link](example.com) Moar text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so probably not generally applicable to others :-) as per usual with my hobbyist software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I re-learned that the pipe symbol, \¦,  screws things up in markdown because it triggers table formatting?!?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To do: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-checkvist/issues/4&quot;&gt;deal with all numeric slugs. Maybe ask user to input the slug manually? #4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;July 29, 2020 &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;BlogThis! A checkvist list of links to blog&lt;/a&gt; i.e. I have only been thinking about this since 2020 :-) ROFL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/28/p1718-blog_all_open/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/28/p1718-blog_all_open/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Me:: The link is everything :-) and AI summaries lose this everything-ness Dec 6, 2024 Collin Jennings:: When AI summaries replace hyperlinks, thought itself is flattened | Aeon Essays</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 26, 2024 21:43  &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/when-ai-summaries-replace-hyperlinks-thought-itself-is-flattened&quot;&gt;Me:: The link is everything :-) and AI summaries lose this everything-ness Dec 6, 2024 Collin Jennings:: When AI summaries replace hyperlinks, thought itself is flattened ¦ Aeon Essays&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://aeon.co/essays/when-ai-summaries-replace-hyperlinks-thought-itself-is-flattened&quot;&gt;Dec 6, 2024 When AI summaries replace hyperlinks, thought itself is flattened ¦ Aeon Essays&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The web made the investigative process Bush described possible by preserving trails of association. When we navigate the web via links, we are in a sense travelling through the series of connections made by someone else, not unlike reading something they wrote. This is part of what Pope’s Dunciad reveals – the shape of a medium’s form communicates its content, and the interaction between form and content is how it produces meaning. This is of course what Page and Brin recognised in implementing the PageRank algorithm. The links matter as much as the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;June 3, 2004: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2004/06/03/what-i-meant-to-say-is-blogs-are-better-because-links-are-first-class-citizens/&quot;&gt;What I meant to say is blogs are better because links are first class citizens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/26/p2143-when-ai-summaries-replace-hyperlinks-thought-itself-is-flattened/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/26/p2143-when-ai-summaries-replace-hyperlinks-thought-itself-is-flattened/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
