<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 22:12:35 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 22:12:35 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Matt Webb: There is no AFTER</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://interconnected.org/home/2020/05/06/lockdown&quot;&gt;There is no After&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– “And that’s how I think about the lockdown now. A high tide that won’t go out. It’ll come and go, a bit, but really this period is just an  extreme phase in what we’ll find is the new normal.” &amp;lt;— sadly this is probably true, &lt;a href=&quot;http://interconnected.org/home/2020/05/06/lockdown&quot;&gt;read the whole thing&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/29/p1-matt-webb-there-is-no-after/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/29/p1-matt-webb-there-is-no-after/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy Holidays, Happy New Year and Merry Christmas; my 2020-2021 holidays post</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I realized I didn’t write a Thanksgiving post back in October. This will probably be my last post of 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Looking back, I am very thankful to family, friends, supporters, funders and those who have helped out when I was in need.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;So lucky to have family, health, a roof over our heads and food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Let’s continue to wear our masks, maintain 2 metre distance, stick to our bubbles and flatten the curve and get rid of COVID together in 2021.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/21/p1-happy-holidays-thanks-friends-family-supporters-funders/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/21/p1-happy-holidays-thanks-friends-family-supporters-funders/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Completed the first 3 weeks of my new job as Support Engineer at element.io</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rtanglao/status/1340111806631538689&quot;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;: achievement unlocked: completed 1st 3 weeks at my new job   &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/element_hq&quot;&gt;@element_hq&lt;/a&gt; ! Celebrating with my fav: German wheat beer! Vielen Dank  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bmann&quot;&gt;@bmann&lt;/a&gt; für das Geschenk  &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/iLoveAllGermanWheatBeer?src=hashtag_click&quot;&gt;#iLoveAllGermanWheatBeer&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/LovingTheElementFirehoseSoFar?src=hashtag_click&quot;&gt;#LovingTheElementFirehoseSoFar&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/lucky?src=hashtag_click&quot;&gt;#lucky&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/thanks?src=hashtag_click&quot;&gt;#thanks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/20/p1-started-my-new-job-element-io-november30/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/20/p1-started-my-new-job-element-io-november30/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Funkwhale - grooveshark inspired decentralized music</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://funkwhale.audio/&quot;&gt;Funkwhale&lt;/a&gt; is a community-driven project that lets you listen and share music and audio within a decentralized, open network - Instances can be federated with the ActivityPub protocol.” Super cool, started 4 years ago roughly i.e. sometime in 2017!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the founder’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/opensource/comments/fkvah3/funkwhale_a_freeopensource_musicaudio_server_ive/&quot;&gt;Reddit AMA 9 months ago&lt;/a&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;In a nutshell, you can use Funkwhale to build your own, private Spotify&lt;/strong&gt;. Once the Funkwhale server (a.k.a. pod) &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.funkwhale.audio/installation/&quot;&gt;is deployed&lt;/a&gt;, you can upload your music on it (or import it from the server through a command-line interface), build playlists, favorites, search within your collection, etc. You can also invite other people on your pod so they  can enjoy the service.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“While you can definitely use Funkwhale to listen to music and audio created by others (this is the core use case), &lt;strong&gt;you can also use it as an alternative to SoundCloud, to publish your own work.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would love to have the time to run my own instance in the cloud!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grooveshark died in 2015. RIP I loved it!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Found via a demo last week at element.io&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/17/p1-funkwhale-decentralized-grooveshark-inspired/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/17/p1-funkwhale-decentralized-grooveshark-inspired/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meeting Recovery Syndrome - goto to a happy place for a speedy recovery (written before the pandemic)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Found&lt;/a&gt; on Dec 8, 2020. Published November 2019: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.com/worklife/article/20191111-blame-your-worthless-workdays-on-meeting-recovery-syndrome&quot;&gt;Blame your worthless workdays on ‘meeting recovery syndrome’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“While none of the counter-MRS ideas have been tested empirically yet,  Allen says one trick with promise is for employees to identify things  that quickly change their mood from negative to positive. As simple as  it sounds, finding a personal happy place, going there and then coming  straight back to work might key to expediting recovery time.” &amp;lt;— e.g. a bicycle ride, walk or trip to a cafe! This was written before COVID so it hilariously doesn’t mention Zoom or even video conferencing. Seems like ancient history! But MRS is a great acronym and still valid!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/15/p1-meeting-recovery-syndrome-written-before-covid-no-mention-of-zoom-fatigue/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/15/p1-meeting-recovery-syndrome-written-before-covid-no-mention-of-zoom-fatigue/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tom Jarrett: Designing Branch: Sustainable Interaction Design Principles</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt; Dec 12, 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.climateaction.tech/2020/10/15/designing-branch-sustainable-interaction-design-principles/&quot;&gt;Designing Branch: Sustainable Interaction Design Principles&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;— ecologically sustainable websites via Boris who got it from &lt;a href=&quot;https://floss.social/@alcinnz/105357811956073662&quot;&gt;Adrian Cochrane&lt;/a&gt;. Some quotes:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;” One of the ways we can do this is by lowering the energy demand of the  digital products and services we’re designing, making it more accessible to people with slower internet connections or on older devices. For &lt;em&gt;Branch&lt;/em&gt; we wanted to design something that still looked designed, and worked at a low bandwidth environment, but didn’t end up looking too anodyne.”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Branch&lt;/em&gt; was also designed to be ‘Demand Responsive’ to adapt to  and reflect the physical infrastructure of the internet and the energy  behind it. Utilising data from a grid intensity API and the user’s  location, &lt;em&gt;Branch&lt;/em&gt; has different interface designs that are shown dependent on the current energy demand and fossil fuels on the grid  where the user is.  “&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://branch.climateaction.tech/2020/10/15/designing-branch-sustainable-interaction-design-principles/&quot;&gt;Read the whole thing&lt;/a&gt; please :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/13/p1-branch-ecologically-sustainable-websites/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/13/p1-branch-ecologically-sustainable-websites/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Matt Webb: Is the internet of things more efficient or transformative because it contains the world? e.g. a crown in 90 minutes is more efficient&lt;-- need to ask my dentist about this </title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Matt Webb: &lt;a href=&quot;http://interconnected.org/home/2020/12/11/thingscon&quot;&gt;The hard work of imagining, ThingsCon 2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;“Even last year, making and  fitting a new crown was a 2 week job requiring a specialist lab. Now my  neighbourhood dentist can do it, and I was in and out in less than 90  minutes. So the way 3D printing has come into the world is what I would call: same but faster. Faster teeth. Faster prototyping. Faster tools for injection moulding in factories.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;But we haven’t seen the society-wide impact…So is the Internet of Things more like what we &lt;em&gt;got&lt;/em&gt; with 3D printing, or more like what we &lt;em&gt;imagined&lt;/em&gt; we’d get? Is it same-but-more-efficient, or is it transformative?…Because of the Internet of Things, this situation has inverted, it is  inside out. There is now the computer, and one of the things that it  contains is the world.-“.Answer: It’s transformative because the Internet now contains the world! Of course &lt;a href=&quot;http://interconnected.org/home/2020/12/11/thingscon&quot;&gt;read the whole thing&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/12/p1-matt-webb-a-crown-in-90-minutes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/12/p1-matt-webb-a-crown-in-90-minutes/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Elvia Wilk:The World of Yesterday Waking from the cosmopolitan daydream</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I discovered this Dec 7, 2020 and updated my &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;checkvist Blog This! Outline&lt;/a&gt; but haven’t blogged it until now :-) :
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Dec 7, 2020. Elvia Wilk: &lt;a href=&quot;https://thebaffler.com/salvos/the-world-of-yesterday-wilk&quot;&gt;The World of Yesterday Waking from the cosmopolitan daydream&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;—   “There is nothing inherently apolitical about travel; on the contrary. But we can’t defeat nationalism by traveling. If the mobile class continues trying to enact the abolition of borders of all kinds by simply crossing them ourselves, because we can, we will never realize that the last train is leaving until it’s too late. As long as borders exist, they can close. But neither can nationalism be defeated simply by staying put or exalting the romantic notion of the local for its own sake, which quickly spirals into NIMBYism. Curiously, being forced to stay in place for a while has created an opening for some to question the imperative to travel, which for a long time allowed us to ignore or neglect the true fronts of action and resistance.” &amp;lt;— it’s best to engage locally rather than get your engagement from travelling elsewhere otherwise why are you living where you are living?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/10/p1-elvia-wilk-world-yesterday-waking-cosmopolitan-daydream/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/10/p1-elvia-wilk-world-yesterday-waking-cosmopolitan-daydream/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mark Guzdial:Computing Education Research Blog:Dijkstra’s Truths about Computing Education Aren’t: The many kinds of programming</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;See my previous related posts which are basically Mark Guzdial again :-) :&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/31/p1-defund-the-cheating-police-and-improve-computer-science-education/&quot;&gt;Computing  Education Research Blog: Proposal #3 to Change CS Education to Reduce  Inequity: Call a truce on academic misconduct cases for programming  assignments and it is not necessary to have to struggle to learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2019/08/08/p1-people-are-not-dumb-programming-languages-are-hard/&quot;&gt;Computing Education Research Blog:Task-specific programming languages: People aren’t dumb. Programming is hard.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://computinged.wordpress.com/2020/12/07/dijkstras-truths-about-computing-education-are-mostly-wrong/&quot;&gt;Dijkstra’s Truths about Computing Education Aren’t The many kinds of programming&lt;/a&gt;:  &amp;lt;– “Of course, there are innate differences between people, but that fact  doesn’t have to limit who can program. Computers are the most flexible  medium that humans have ever created. To argue that only a small  percentage of people can “groove with programming” or that learning a  specific programming language “mentally mutilates” is to define  programming in a very narrow way. There are &lt;em&gt;lots&lt;/em&gt; of activities that are programming” &amp;lt;– AMEN!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/08/p1-dijkstra-wrong-about-how-teach-programming-right-about-computer-science/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/08/p1-dijkstra-wrong-about-how-teach-programming-right-about-computer-science/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Charlie Schick:@molecularist The miracle of mundane</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See my previous related post:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/04/22/p1-over40invancouver-life-during-the-pandemic-episode2/&quot;&gt;Over 40 In Vancouver: Life during the Pandemic #2 Mundanity For @sillygwailo Artichokes in Burnaby @bigheadtaco ?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charlie Schick:&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/molecularist&quot;&gt;@molecularist&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.molecularist.com/2020/12/the-miracle-of-mundane.html&quot;&gt;The miracle of  mundane&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– “There is no magic to connect to the mundane. Just be and do.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/06/p1-charlie-schick-the-miracle-of-mundane/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/12/06/p1-charlie-schick-the-miracle-of-mundane/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
