<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 11:42:42 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 11:42:42 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ben Werdmuller:: Lifelogging under fascism...Imagine a device that lifelogged and stored quantified self data using strong, key-based encryption &lt;-- ME:: I want this yes please!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 12, 2025 16:29 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://werd.io/lifelogging-under-fascism/&quot;&gt;Ben Werdmuller:: Lifelogging under fascism…Imagine a device that lifelogged and stored quantified self data using strong, key-based encryption &amp;lt;– ME:: I want this yes please!&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;:: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Imagine a device that lifelogged and stored quantified self data using strong, key-based encryption. You could access the information yourself for your own purposes, but it would remain fully encrypted and behind multi-factor login protection. If you needed to, you could release footage to predefined trusted parties: family members, a trusted member of the community, organizations like the ACLU, and as a tip to trusted newsrooms. If you didn’t get a chance to do that before being detained or otherwise incapacitated, a set number (three or five, perhaps) trusted people could agree to release your footage by taking action on their own devices together — a bit like needing multiple people to launch a nuclear missile. Every time footage was released, that action would be indelibly logged, as a guard against abuse.&lt;/code&gt; ; Read the whole thing &lt;a href=&quot;https://werd.io/lifelogging-under-fascism/&quot;&gt;Lifelogging under fascism&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0929-lifelogging-under-fascism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0929-lifelogging-under-fascism/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Ben, this sounds great, how can I help support this? Ben Werdmuller:: If I started fresh...a private-by-default, federated platform designed for groups that already know each other or are actively building trust</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 12, 2025 16:15 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://werd.io/if-i-started-fresh/&quot;&gt;ME:: Ben, this sounds great, how can I help support this? Ben Werdmuller:: If I started fresh…a private-by-default, federated platform designed for groups that already know each other or are actively building trust&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://werd.io/if-i-started-fresh/&quot;&gt;If I started fresh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By not releasing an open source project at first, the business has a chance to seed the culture of the platform. It can provide the resources, support, and vigilance needed to make sure the space is inclusive, respectful, and safe. Once the platform has matured and there are thriving, healthy communities, that’s when we can release a reference codebase — not as a symbolic gesture, but as a foundation others can build on without compromise. That moment would come once the platform has proven its core use case, the community culture is thriving, and the financial base is strong enough to support long-term governance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the meantime, because it’s all based on open social web protocols, other developers could have been building their own participating open source community platforms, dashboards, and libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0915-if-i-started-fresh/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0915-if-i-started-fresh/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ben Werdmuller:: If I ran my life, private schools would be banned &lt;-- ME::Amen!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 12, 2025 15:47 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://werd.io/if-i-ran-my-life/&quot;&gt;Ben Werdmuller:: If I ran my life, private schools would be banned &amp;lt;– ME::Amen!&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Read the whole thing:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://werd.io/if-i-ran-my-life/&quot;&gt;If I ran my life&lt;/a&gt;! &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;As for schools? One of my most controversial opinions is that private schools should be banned. Everyone, no matter how rich or how poor, should have to go through the same system. This will force the system to be better, and helps ensure that everyone has the same opportunities. (It also ensures that children meet peers from other stratas and classes.) In reality, that’s never going to happen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0847-if-i-ran-my-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0847-if-i-ran-my-life/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: LLMs are a useful tool to complement your learning and to help construct your meaning; you can use them to replace your labour and get good grades but that's not going to result in learning which is of course NOT about grades ; Soroush Sabbaghan:: AI can be responsibly integrated into classrooms by answering the ‘why’ and ‘when’</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 12, 2025 15:24 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/ai-can-be-responsibly-integrated-into-classrooms-by-answering-the-why-and-when-261496&quot;&gt;ME:: LLMs are a useful tool to complement your learning and to help construct your meaning; you can use them to replace your labour and get good grades but that’s not going to result in learning which is of course NOT about grades ; Soroush Sabbaghan:: AI can be responsibly integrated into classrooms by answering the ‘why’ and ‘when’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/ai-can-be-responsibly-integrated-into-classrooms-by-answering-the-why-and-when-261496&quot;&gt;AI can be responsibly integrated into classrooms by answering the ‘why’ and ‘when’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This reframes the “why” of using AI. From this perspective, the only justification for integrating AI into a learning process should be to support and sustain intellectual labour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;However, when the “how” of AI is used to bypass the very struggle that builds virtue (by exercising intellectual labour, including analysis, deliberation and judgment), it directly undermines the “why” of the assignment. A graduate student who generates a descriptive list of pertinent research about a topic without engaging with the sources skips the valuable process of synthesis and critical engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;For Dewey, learning happens through doing, questioning and grappling with complexity, not by acquiring information passively. Assignments that reward perfection and correctness over process and growth further incentivize the use of AI as a shortcut, reducing learning to prompting and receiving rather than engaging in the intellectual labour of constructing meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is where an “ethics of care” becomes indispensable. As philosopher Nel Noddings proposed, a care-based approach prioritizes relationships and the needs of the individual over rigid, universal rules. It moves away from a one-size-fits-all policy and toward discretionary judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Deciding the “when” requires educators to know their learner, understand the learning goal and act with compassion and wisdom. It is a relational act, not a technical one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Educators must ensure that AI supports rather than displaces the development of core capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0824-ai-can-be-responsibly-integrated-into-classrooms-by-answering-the-why-and-when-261496/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0824-ai-can-be-responsibly-integrated-into-classrooms-by-answering-the-why-and-when-261496/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GitHub - yotam/PyFlickr: Download Images using the Flickr API via the flickrapi python package </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 12, 2025 15:13 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/yotam/PyFlickr&quot;&gt;GitHub - yotam/PyFlickr: Download Images using the Flickr API via the flickrapi python package &lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– May not work since it requires the flickrapi python package which is not maintained/deprecated see previous post. &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Downloads images from Flickr with the requested tags. Requires python package flickrapi, and a Flickr API key (set this in the script).&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0813-pyflickr/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0813-pyflickr/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: looks great but sadly deprecated as of November 2024 since the maintainer/author doesn't use the flickr API any more sad face ; Sybren A. Stüvel:: Python Flickr API ¦ dr. Sybren</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 12, 2025 15:05 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://stuvel.eu/software/flickrapi/&quot;&gt;ME:: looks great but sadly deprecated as of November 2024 since the maintainer/author doesn’t use the flickr API any more sad face ; Sybren A. Stüvel:: Python Flickr API ¦ dr. Sybren&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– See this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sybrenstuvel/flickrapi/commit/21b9e721c2c4ead53e6b336b596bdd9439818627&quot;&gt;commit&lt;/a&gt;: “I have no time to maintain this repository, and haven’t used the software myself for years and years.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Flickr is one of the most popular photo hosting websites on the planet. Their extensive API gives programmers plenty of opportunity to use Flickr any way they see fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The easy to use Flickr API has several interfaces written in Python, the best one created by Beej. I’ve been the maintainer for this interface since August 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May 7, 2017: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2017/05/07/p1-cogdog-bet-flickr-api-broken-by-april-30-2018/&quot;&gt;By April 30, 2018, the flickr API will be broken — my bet with cog dog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0805-flickrapi/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/p0805-flickrapi/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Highly Recommended for all folks not just Filipinos! Carmela Sison as Chef Mela is fabulous in Lasa ng Imperyo/A Taste of Empire, an adaptation of a play by Jovanni Sy Oct 9-19, 2025 at Presentation House Theatre, North Vancouver, $30</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highly recommended&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/rapsberryshake/&quot;&gt;Carmela Sison&lt;/a&gt; as Chef Mela is fabulous -&amp;gt; Lasa ng Imperyo/&lt;a href=&quot;https://talonbooks.com/books/a-taste-of-empire&quot;&gt;A Taste of Empire&lt;/a&gt;, an adaptation of a play by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canadiantheatre.com/dict.pl?term=Sy%2C%20Jovanni&quot;&gt;Jovanni Sy,&lt;/a&gt; is playing in North Vancouver at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phtheatre.org/stec_event/lasa-ng-imperyo/&quot;&gt;Presentation House Theatre&lt;/a&gt; until October 19, 2025. It’s a history lesson from Magellan to the Spanish Empire’s influence on Filipino cuisine since the 1500s to the Spanish American war’s killing of over 10, 000 Filipinos by American soldiers (some historians say many more like over 100, 000), to the migrant workers of Mexico in Abbotsford who in an ironic twist work hard with very low wages to supply tomatoes to Filipinos (ironic because Spanish Empire Philippines was administered from Acapulco, Mexico for over 200 years, see Wikipedia: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manila_galleon&quot;&gt;Manila galleon&lt;/a&gt;) to Trump and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kawalingpinoy.com/relyenong-bangus/&quot;&gt;relyenong bangus&lt;/a&gt; cooking lesson. It’s funny sad, and gut wrenching. Only $30! The first time I’ve seen a play in Tagalog with English subtitles. &lt;strong&gt;100% relevant to everybody not just Filipinos.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;blurb-from-ph-theatre&quot;&gt;Blurb from PH Theatre&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Superstar of the culinary world, Master Chef Maximo Cortés is offering an exclusive demonstration, sharing the secrets of his trademarked Imperial Cuisine cooking techniques with you, his lucky, elite guests! Or at least, he would have, if he had shown up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Luckily, the witty and intrepid Sous-Chef Mela is here to save the day! Her task? To cook rellenong bangus, or stuffed milkfish, a dish whose intricate preparation process takes its roots from the country’s culinary traditions and colonial past. In a surprising fusion of theatre and gastronomy, this live cooking demonstration pairs the harsh truths of a global food system with shocking humour. Performed in Tagalog with English surtitles, this show guides audiences across the layered history of Philippine cultural heritage through a live cooking demonstration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This adaptation of Jovanni Sy’s &lt;em&gt;A Taste of Empire&lt;/em&gt; reimagines this acclaimed play through a fresh female perspective. As the dish is brought to life, so too are the stories embedded within its ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Food will be served. Contact 604-990-3473 if you have allergy concerns.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(originally written usig Wordland and posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://roland.wordpress.com/2025/10/12/324/&quot;&gt;roland.wordpress.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/lasa-imperyo-jovanni-sy-carmela-sison-adaptation-tagalog-presentation-house-theatre-northvan-highly-recommended/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/12/lasa-imperyo-jovanni-sy-carmela-sison-adaptation-tagalog-presentation-house-theatre-northvan-highly-recommended/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: AI stuff to code effectively requires time and $ which many minority folks simply don't have ; Dr Cat Hicks:: New research from me: AI Skill Threat &amp;amp; contest cultures on software teams</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 9, 2025 20:05 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drcathicks.com/post/new-research-from-me-ai-skill-threat-contest-cultures-on-software-teams&quot;&gt;ME:: AI stuff to code effectively requires time and $ which many minority folks simply don’t have ; Dr Cat Hicks:: New research from me: AI Skill Threat &amp;amp; contest cultures on software teams&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;And because of our deep investment in recruiting underrepresented perspectives across all of our projects, we are able to share evidence that there are critically important equity and opportunity gaps emerging across developers' experiences with AI-assisted coding. For example, 56% of Racially Minoritized developers report a negative judgment of the quality of AI outputs in coding work, compared with 28% for all developers, and report higher levels of AI Skill Threat. Women and LGBTQ+ people on software teams are less likely to report upskilling in AI-assisted coding, potentially signaling a lack of resources. It is vital to learn from these groups' insights as well as take action to ensure these gaps do not calcify into new, career-threatening barriers.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/09/p1305-new-research-from-me-ai-skill-threat-contest-cultures-on-software-teams/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/09/p1305-new-research-from-me-ai-skill-threat-contest-cultures-on-software-teams/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fuji Superia, Velvia, Kodak Ektachrome, Gold, Portra, SkyOptiimizer2, SunShadeSharp Luts from falk.wagenknecht- Google Drive</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 7, 2025 15:41 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1dcxrhHJqTxhIlgwNGNO6XL5llnVh7r84&quot;&gt;Fuji Superia, Velvia, Kodak Ektachrome, Gold, Portra, SkyOptiimizer2, SunShadeSharp Luts from falk.wagenknecht- Google Drive&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– (via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/LumixLUTs/comments/1kajiq6/big_lut_update_leave_a_like/&quot;&gt;Reddit post 5 months ago on r/LumixLUTs:&lt;/a&gt;: “Big LUT update, leave a like!” &amp;lt;– :) &amp;lt;– looks great, thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/07/p0841-falk-wegenknecht-luts-fuji-kodak-sunshadesharp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/07/p0841-falk-wegenknecht-luts-fuji-kodak-sunshadesharp/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Go Blacksky go!!! I doubt that Blacksky will be under the 'thumb of Bluesky's moderation service' forever (if this is true, I don't know enough about ATProto to know for sure who is under the thumb of who) ; Bruno Dias,:: Delusions of a Protocol ¦ Azhdarchid</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Oct 6, 2025 14:42 (UTC)&lt;a href=&quot;https://azhdarchid.com/delusions-of-a-protocol/&quot;&gt;ME:: Go Blacksky go!!! I doubt that Blacksky will be under the “thumb of Bluesky’s moderation service” forever (if this is true, I don’t know enough about ATProto to know for sure who is under the thumb of who) ; Bruno Dias,:: Delusions of a Protocol ¦ Azhdarchid&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;To my knowledge there's only one alternate stack that runs atproto as a complete service, Blacksky. But this isn't a turnkey solution that you can stand up as your own independent alternative; Blacksky at present barely has documentation. And even Blacksky users are still more or less under the thumb of Bluesky's moderation service, if they intend to reach 99% of the network as it exists today.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/06/p0742-delusions-of-a-protocol/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/10/06/p0742-delusions-of-a-protocol/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
