<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 17:51:13 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 17:51:13 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Probably wrong prediction: We will have forgotten about outdoor dining by 2025 just like we forgot why steam radiators are so hot</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s a great idea and works in the city of Vancouver except when it’s snowing and or heavily raining i.e. it works for 365 days a year minus 100 hours or so :-) but we love our convenience and able bodied folks can’t cope with a wee bit of rain or coolness (which is weird to me since those same folks eat outside in -10 at ski resorts like Whistler)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;See my tweet:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;This fantastic! Probably wrong prediction: This will all be forgotten by 2025. But I think those who don&amp;#39;t have illnesses triggered by light rain &amp;amp; have warm rain gear should consider eating in light rain (under some shelter) even Post Pandemic. It&amp;#39;s fun! &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/GSk2sKqv8W&quot;&gt;https://t.co/GSk2sKqv8W&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Roland Tanglao 猪肉面 (@rtanglao) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rtanglao/status/1396299282949410816?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 23, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But we’ll forget just like we forgot why steam radiators are so warm!
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2020/12/10/945136599/how-spanish-flu-pandemic-changed-home-heat-radiators&quot;&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;: “CHANG: Oh, so familiar. As it turns out, radiators that work too well  are partly a result of the 1918 flu pandemic. You see; there was once  something called the Fresh Air Movement. It called for people to be  outside more and for there to be plenty of ventilation indoors.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;See my previous posts:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/03/15/p1-how-to-vancouverite-always-carry-a-plastic-bag-for-coffee-and-doughnuts-in-the-rain/&quot;&gt;How To Vancouverite in the Rain: Always carry a plastic bag for outdoor coffee and doughnuts in the rain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/03/16/p1-how-to-vancouverite-always-carry-chopsticks-spoon-fork-knife-napkin-dining-rain/&quot;&gt;How  To Vancouverite in the Rain: Always carry chopsticks, spoon, fork,  knife wrapped in a napkin since you never know when you’ll have a  hankering for adobo, pancit, mapo tofu, kimchi stew, chana masala or  sushi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/03/19/p1-how-to-vancouverite-always-carry-raingear/&quot;&gt;How to Vancouverite in the rain: Always carry raingear because we live in a temperate rainforest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/23/p1-forgotten-about-outdoor-dining-by-2025/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/23/p1-forgotten-about-outdoor-dining-by-2025/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our son is a real artist</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From Arts Umbrella: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.artsumbrella.com/stories/simon-tanglao-vasi/&quot;&gt;Learning to work as an artist today with Visual Arts Summer Intensive (VASI)&lt;/a&gt; :  “I think that being exposed to contemporary art from all sorts of  perspectives (curatorial, artistic, logistical) has deepened my  appreciation and enjoyment of it as an artist. VASI opened up a lot of  possibilities that I’m thankful for, has continued to shape my practice, and will probably continue for a long time.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/22/p1-our-son-real-artist/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/22/p1-our-son-real-artist/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On the benefits of sharing your work Composer and performer Kamala Sankaram discusses creating your own path and the diversity of opera! (I love opera!)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 18, 2021.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://thecreativeindependent.com/people/composer-and-performer-kamala-sankaram-on-the-benefits-of-sharing-your-work/&quot;&gt;On the benefits of sharing your work Composer and performer Kamala Sankaram discusses creating your own path&lt;/a&gt;  “Most people in America have never heard an opera, so there’s 100 years of opera being made in America that’s out there to discover. We tend to think of the old Italian and German pieces, but then America had what has been called a Golden Age of Opera, especially in the last 20 years or so. There’s a lot of great work being done in New York, there’s a festival called Prototype that has new pieces every year that are pushing the boundaries of what opera can be.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Some of the composers that have come out of Prototype are David T. Little, Missy Mazzoli, Ellen Reid. There’s, of course, people who’ve been around forever, like Anthony Davis, who just won the Pulitzer last year for his opera Central Park Five.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;He has an opera from the ’80s called Malcolm X that’s just amazing. It’s going to get more productions now, but it’s really great and there’s a good recording of it out there, too. Right now, people are especially influenced by putting people on stage who haven’t been there by representing social justice issues, borrowing from popular music, jazz. There’s an opera that came out a few years ago called We Shall Not Be Moved, it’s got a lot of hip hop in it and the choreography is by Bill T. Jones.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;There are too many people to name everybody, but there’s something for everybody out there.” &amp;lt;– opera is universal i agree!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/20/p1-diverse-opera-out-there-and-universal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/20/p1-diverse-opera-out-there-and-universal/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simon Willison's github scraping is officially supported by Github who call it 'Flat Data'</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 19, 2021.&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/simonw/status/1394729289346519041&quot;&gt;Flat Data&lt;/a&gt;!  (&lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2021/May/19/flat-data/&quot;&gt;blog post)&lt;/a&gt; Simon Willison’s git scraping is now officially supported by Github who call it “Flat Data”! yes!
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;See my previous post from October 2020: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/16/p1-simon-willison-git-scraping-how-to-use-github-actions-to-call-an-api-every-20-minutes/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison:Git scraping: track changes over  time by scraping to a Git repository aka how to use github actions to  call an API every 20 minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/19/p1-simon-willison-github-scraping-official-supported-by-github-flat-data/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/19/p1-simon-willison-github-scraping-official-supported-by-github-flat-data/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>everest pipkin: HERE IS THE ARTICLE YOU CAN SEND TO PEOPLE WHEN THEY SAY “BUT THE ENVIRONMENTAL ISSUES WITH CRYPTOART WILL BE SOLVED SOON, RIGHT?”</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://everestpipkin.medium.com/but-the-environmental-issues-with-cryptoart-1128ef72e6a3&quot;&gt;HERE IS THE ARTICLE YOU CAN SEND TO PEOPLE WHEN THEY SAY “BUT THE  ENVIRONMENTAL ISSUES WITH CRYPTOART WILL BE SOLVED SOON, RIGHT?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Juicy Quote:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BEGIN QUOTE:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;”“&lt;strong&gt;However, we must get there through collective empowerment and strong social  programs like universal basic income, universal healthcare, divestment  from warfare and policing, a regulated real estate market that does not  capitalize on housing scarcity and rent, worker unions, food programs,  environmental protections, and actual, functioning income taxes on the  wealthy.&lt;/strong&gt; An individualist fantasy of a pyramid scheme, made to  reward investors over artists and directly thieving from our shared  future just isn’t it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many would call me unrealistic and naïve for this, unwilling to make  compromises in the world we are living now because of an idealistic  vision of a tomorrow; and to them I would like to say that we literally  invented an extra-sovereign monetary system that within 10 years has  generated trillions of dollars of worth and is held up with the power  consumption of a small country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let this whole horrible chapter of history convince you that money is fake, we can do anything with it we want, and that we do not want cryptoart.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/17/p1-everest-pipkin-cryptoart-nft-environment-issues-wont-be-solved-soon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/17/p1-everest-pipkin-cryptoart-nft-environment-issues-wont-be-solved-soon/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kim Stanley Robinson's Response to the Ministry for the Future Seminar</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is definitely worth your while to read all 9 essays linked to in yesterday’s  post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/15/p1-crooked-timber-seminar-for-the-future/&quot;&gt;Cory Doctorow: Crooked Timber’s Ministry for the Future Seminar &amp;lt;– must read essays on climate change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;But if you don’t have time at the moment, starting with &lt;a href=&quot;https://crookedtimber.org/2021/05/14/response-7/&quot;&gt;Kim Stanley Robinson’s Response to the Ministry for the Future Semina&lt;/a&gt;r and then reading the 9 linked essays also works :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/16/p1-kim-stanley-robison-response-to-seminar-for-the-future/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/16/p1-kim-stanley-robison-response-to-seminar-for-the-future/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cory Doctorow: Crooked Timber's Ministry for the Future Seminar &lt;-- must read essays on climate change</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Read the whole thing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralistic.net/2021/05/12/seminar-for-the-future/#imaginations&quot;&gt;Crooked Timber’s Ministry for the Future Seminar&lt;/a&gt;,   especially the links to the essays on climate change (see previous post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/03/20/p1-kim-stanley-robinson-ministry-for-the-future-terrible-novel-great-ideas-like-100k-for-everybody/&quot;&gt;Kim Stanley Robinson’s: The Ministry for the  Future: terrible novel but great ideas like giving $USD100K to everybody so highly recommended :-)&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;“Kim Stanley Robinson’s 2020 novel “The Ministry for the Future,” is a fierce imaginative work. Robinson doesn’t just depict a future beyond  the climate emergency and capitalism itself, he depicts the specific,  wrenching transition that takes us there.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.orbitbooks.net/orbit-excerpts/the-ministry-for-the-future/&quot;&gt;https://www.orbitbooks.net/orbit-excerpts/the-ministry-for-the-future/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;As I wrote in my review, the (variously attributed) maxim “It is  easier to imagine the end of the world than the end of capitalism,”  isn’t quite right. Imagining postcapitalism is an easy lift, but  imagining the path to that world is &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; hard.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/03/ministry-for-the-future/#ksr&quot;&gt;https://pluralistic.net/2020/12/03/ministry-for-the-future/#ksr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;Robinson didn’t leap into this project – he’s been working up to it  for literally decades, at least since the publication of the “Three  California” books, which include one of the most uplifting novels I’ve  ever read, PACIFIC EDGE:&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://memex.craphound.com/2015/01/15/pacific-edge-the-most-uplifting-novel-in-my-library/&quot;&gt;https://memex.craphound.com/2015/01/15/pacific-edge-the-most-uplifting-novel-in-my-library/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, his 2312/Aurora/New York 2140/Red Moon novels constitute a kind of rangefinding exercise, starting 300 years the future and then  walking his projection backwards to find a plausible route to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://memex.craphound.com/2017/03/18/new-york-2140-kim-stanley-robinson-dreams-vivid-about-weathering-climate-crisis/&quot;&gt;https://memex.craphound.com/2017/03/18/new-york-2140-kim-stanley-robinson-dreams-vivid-about-weathering-climate-crisis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;But all these brilliant novels really seem to be warmup exercises for the main event, The Ministry for the Future, which depicts the  intermeshed systems of economics, politics, geoengineering,  streetfighting and tragedy that might rescue us from dying in our own  waste-gases.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;It’s urgent, frightening and hopeful, raising as many questions as it answers.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;These questions are now taken up in one of Crooked Timber’s  “seminars”: a series of interdisciplinary essays about the book,  culminating in the author’s response.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://crookedtimber.org/2021/05/03/the-ministry-for-the-future-seminar/&quot;&gt;https://crookedtimber.org/2021/05/03/the-ministry-for-the-future-seminar/&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;p&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/15/p1-crooked-timber-seminar-for-the-future/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/15/p1-crooked-timber-seminar-for-the-future/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stratechery: Cloudflare Durable Objects exist on the edge where the user resides and can be easily moved anywhere</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt; May 12, 2021. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2021/cloudflare-on-the-edge/&quot;&gt;Cloudflare on the edge&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;— Durable objects exist in the user’s country and nowhere else i.e. A German user’s data resides in Germany “Durable Objects are not, in-and-of-themselves, going to kill the public clouds; what they represent, though, is an entirely new way of building infrastructure — from the edge in, as opposed to the data center out “&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zones, we don’t need no stinkin’ zones or something :-)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data should reside where it should reside and other tautologies :-)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decentralized, movable data for the win!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/13/p1-cloudflare-durable-objects-exist-where-the-user-resides-and-can-be-easily-moved-anytime/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/13/p1-cloudflare-durable-objects-exist-where-the-user-resides-and-can-be-easily-moved-anytime/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>reallifemag: The Sounds of Silence</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;May 10, 2021 &lt;a href=&quot;https://reallifemag.com/the-sounds-of-silence/&quot;&gt;The Sounds of Silence&lt;/a&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Our relationship with technology, though, is a chaotic one; in fact all interaction is by definition chaotic. Any form of play that does not center this chaos — which instead envisages human-machine interaction as a seamless unbroken circuit — will always subordinate the human to the level of object, rather than elevating an object to the level of the human. In attempting to make the world more animate, we risk de-animating ourselves&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most definitely &lt;a href=&quot;https://reallifemag.com/the-sounds-of-silence/&quot;&gt;Read The Whole Thing&lt;/a&gt; :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/10/p1-reallifemag-the-sounds-of-silence/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/10/p1-reallifemag-the-sounds-of-silence/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Not sure why R's if_else() fails! R type system misunderstanding? Misunderstanding of NA?</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following is me trying to convert my 2019 and 2020 flickr photos’ average colour to one of 657 R standard colours instead of the possible 256xx256x256 = 16777216  colours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s probably my misunderstanding and a type issue R but not sure why the following never executes the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; portion and always executes the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;else&lt;/code&gt; portion (full code is in &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;my repo over on github&lt;/a&gt;):
    &lt;div class=&quot;language-R highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;if_else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;synth_75imaveragecolour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&amp;lt;NA&amp;gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;as.hexmode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;getnumericColour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;synth_plotrixcolour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)))&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;w&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I also tried &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;is.na()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;== &quot;&quot;&lt;/code&gt; and neither of those worked&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s probably my misunderstanding of the R type system!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I think I can diagnose this further by writing a loop (!) and printing out the values and the types or by using a 2 row tibble to debug further.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/09/p1-not-sure-why-r-ifelse-fails/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2021/05/09/p1-not-sure-why-r-ifelse-fails/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
