<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 23:42:20 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 23:42:20 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Micky McCauley:: May 19, 2020:: New York Times’ Style Guide Substitutions for “The President Lied” - McSweeney’s Internet Tendency</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 16, 2025 06:18 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/new-york-times-style-guide-substitutions-for-the-president-lied&quot;&gt;Micky McCauley:: May 19, 2020:: New York Times’ Style Guide Substitutions for “The President Lied” - McSweeney’s Internet Tendency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The president, offering no evidence, insisted upon his version of the story.”
“The president extemporized with a blithe disregard for established fact.”
“Confounding experts and antagonizing the historical record, the president painted his own, rosier portrait of events.”
“The president, perhaps inadvertently, wound up smudging the line between empirical verification and his own boundless optimism.”
“The president once again found himself galloping ahead of reality’s leisurely pace.”
“The president dabbled anew in the shallow pond of misrepresentation, filling his beak with succulent morsels hidden among the reeds.”
“The president’s most recent encounter with the specter of honesty caught him wrong-footed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;June 3, 2025:: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/15/p0614-new-york-times-style-guide-substitutions-for-the-president-violated-the-constitution/&quot;&gt;Carlos Greaves:: New York Times’ Style Guide Substitutions for “The President Violated the Constitution” - McSweeney’s Internet Tendency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/15/p0618-new-york-times-style-guide-substitutions-for-the-president-lied/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/15/p0618-new-york-times-style-guide-substitutions-for-the-president-lied/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>June 3, 2025:: Carlos Greaves:: New York Times’ Style Guide Substitutions for “The President Violated the Constitution” - McSweeney’s Internet Tendency</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 16, 2025 06:14 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/new-york-times-style-guide-substitutions-for-the-president-violated-the-constitution&quot;&gt;June 3, 2025:: Carlos Greaves:: New York Times’ Style Guide Substitutions for “The President Violated the Constitution” - McSweeney’s Internet Tendency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The president remained steadfast in his novel interpretation of constitutional law.”
“Faced with the choice between clinging to the letter of the law and marching to the beat of his own legal drum, the president chose the latter.”
“The president’s solutions-focused approach to legal roadblocks necessitated thinking outside the constitutional box.”
“Perhaps unaware that he had sailed beyond the Constitution’s horizons, the president found himself drifting further and further from legal terra firma.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;November 9, 2016: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2016/11/09/p1-this-is-not-america/&quot;&gt;This is not America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/15/p0614-new-york-times-style-guide-substitutions-for-the-president-violated-the-constitution/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/15/p0614-new-york-times-style-guide-substitutions-for-the-president-violated-the-constitution/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: love the Pulsar Nextlevel metal filters (search for Pulsar – Stainless Steel Filter Discs at nextlevelbrewer DOT com! almost no fines with the following recipe. 25g coffee; close valve;add 75g water;open valve for 1 second; close valve wait 20s;open valve add 125g of water and wait until almost drained;close valve add 200g water; wait 1 minute 20 seconds;open valve ; DaddyGotCoffee:: Brew Like An Astrophysicist! Pulsar Dripper Review - YouTube</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 14, 2025 18:22 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VBqRcpoRfSA&amp;amp;t=608s&quot;&gt;ME:: love the Pulsar Nextlevel metal filters (search for Pulsar – Stainless Steel Filter Discs at nextlevelbrewer DOT com! almost no fines with the following recipe. 25g coffee; close valve;add 75g water;open valve for 1 second; close valve wait 20s;open valve add 125g of water and wait until almost drained;close valve add 200g water; wait 1 minute 20 seconds;open valve ; DaddyGotCoffee:: Brew Like An Astrophysicist! Pulsar Dripper Review - YouTube&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– Non affiliate links for Canadians to cafune: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cafune.ca/products/nextlevel-pulsar-stainless-steel-filter-discs&quot;&gt;NextLevel ¦ Pulsar Stainless Steel Filter Discs&lt;/a&gt; ; &lt;a href=&quot;https://cafune.ca/products/nextlevel-pulsar-brewer?_pos=2&amp;amp;_sid=4bc39a3ef&amp;amp;_ss=r&quot;&gt;NextLevel ¦ Pulsar Brewer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/14/p1822-nextlevel-pulsar-coffee-brewer-recipe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/14/p1822-nextlevel-pulsar-coffee-brewer-recipe/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Recipes that probably :-) work:: Irene Arita:: May 2022:: Adobong Sitaw with Chicharon:: Filipino-Mexican Culinary and Cultural Exchange – My Slice of Mexico</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 13, 2025 01:38 &lt;a href=&quot;https://mysliceofmexico.ca/2022/05/15/filipino-mexican-culinary-and-cultural-exchange/&quot;&gt;ME:: Recipes that probably :-) work:: Irene Arita:: May 2022:: Adobong Sitaw with Chicharon:: Filipino-Mexican Culinary and Cultural Exchange – My Slice of Mexico&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;— gotta try this but with 1/2 cup of chicharon not 3 cups! LOL! &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;The month of May is recognized as Asian Heritage month in Canada; this time, I am writing about the Filipino-Mexican connection, and sharing a recipe from the Philippines that could almost be Mexican.   ... Green pods of Phaseolus vulgaris, known as ejotes (in Spanish in Mexico, judías verdes, in Spain) – sitaw  (Filipino) – string/green beans (English), one of the many contributions of Mexico to the world, are the featured vegetable in this recipe.  Pork or chicken are common meat additions, but I chose fried pork rinds to continue my chicharrones theme from previous posts.  As a snack,  fried pork rinds are ubiquitous around the world, known as khaep mu in Thailand, cracklings in the US,  scratchings in the UK, etc., but in Mexico and The Philippines, they definitely came from Spain, called chicharrón in Spanish, and chicharon in Filipino/Tagalog.  Finally, red hot peppers are optional, but I included some to enhance the culinary fusion of the dish.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;June 26, 2024: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/06/26/p1014-tamales-adobo-leche-flan-spanish-mexican-dishes-filipinos-took/&quot;&gt;Tamales, adobo, leche flan – Spanish, Mexican dishes Filipinos took as their own, along with New World fruits such as tomato, avocado, and papaya ¦ South China Morning Post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;December 17, 2024: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2024/12/17/p1718-42c9c452-629f-4ab9-89b9-969e363c4769-manila-acapulco-spanish-empire-galleon-trade-mexico-phillipes/&quot;&gt;Me tl;dr-ing:: Filipino tech enabled Acapulco-Manila trade starting in the 1500s until the 1800s aka Philippines&amp;lt;-&amp;gt;Mexico Spanish empire was built with Filipino tech as well as the usual colonial oppression :-) Andrew Christian Petersen for his PhD in 2014:: Making the first global trade route : the southeast Asian foundations of the Acapulco-Manila galleon trade, 1519-1650&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/13/p0138-filipino-mexican-culinary-and-cultural-exchange/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/13/p0138-filipino-mexican-culinary-and-cultural-exchange/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: As always, Lisp and Smalltalk were there first but too early and too much $ ; Mass-produced software is too rigid; Need: A gentle slope from user to creator; Tools not avocado slicers er apps :-) ; Need: communal creation ; June 2025:: Geoffrey Litt, Josh Horowitz, Peter van Hardenberg, Todd Matthews:: ink and switch:: Malleable software: Restoring user agency in a world of locked-down apps</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 11, 2025 14:25 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inkandswitch.com/essay/malleable-software/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: As always, Lisp and Smalltalk were there first but too early and too much $ ; Mass-produced software is too rigid; Need: A gentle slope from user to creator; Tools not avocado slicers er apps :-) ; Need: communal creation ; June 2025:: Geoffrey Litt, Josh Horowitz, Peter van Hardenberg, Todd Matthews:: ink and switch:: Malleable software: Restoring user agency in a world of locked-down apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inkandswitch.com/essay/malleable-software/&quot;&gt;ink and switch:: Malleable software: Restoring user agency in a world of locked-down apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The researchers demonstrated this principle in an automation system called Buttons. To start out, users could move buttons around and change the text or color. Slightly further up the slope, users could edit variable values or use a toolkit to create simple UIs. Finally, at the top of the slope, users could create new behaviors by doing Lisp programming. The key point was that each customization could be done with the simplest technique possible, leaving full programming only as a last resort when absolutely needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/11/p1425-malleable-software/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/11/p1425-malleable-software/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: I did this to mount my Fenix FENIX HM65R-DT headlamp on my bicycle helmet using the ALG-03 V2.0 - Fenix Headlamp mount for Helmet ; Take the battery out, take the O-ring off, lift a tab and slide it out; sweetheart5978:: How to remove main headlamp from headband for FENIX HM645R-T - YouTube</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 7, 2025 17:32 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/shorts/SJ3QrXNH4qY&quot;&gt;ME:: I did this to mount my Fenix FENIX HM65R-DT headlamp on my bicycle helmet using the ALG-03 V2.0 - Fenix Headlamp mount for Helmet ; Take the battery out, take the O-ring off, lift a tab and slide it out; sweetheart5978:: How to remove main headlamp from headband for FENIX HM645R-T - YouTube&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– See Vancouver Battery’s site: &lt;a href=&quot;https://vancouverbattery.com/hm65r-dt-nebula-pink-purple-fenix-1500-lumen-rechargeable-led-headlamp/&quot;&gt;HM65R-DT (Nebula)(Pink/Purple) - Fenix 1500 Lumen Rechargeable LED Headlamp&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://vancouverbattery.com/alg-03-v2-0-fenix-headlamp-mount-for-helmet-or-hard-hat/&quot;&gt;ALG-03 V2.0 - Fenix Headlamp mount for Helmet &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/07/p1732-sj3qrxnh4qy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/07/p1732-sj3qrxnh4qy/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Charles Marohn of Strong Towns on fixing North America's broken zoning:: So let me be clear: when I say we want to “make better decisions inevitable over time,” I don’t mean inevitable like gravity. I mean inevitable like compound interest—tiny, persistent, visible pressure applied in the same direction until the math changes. It’s slow, messy, and often invisible at first.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 6, 2025 16:06 &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/profile/11031131-charles-marohn/note/c-122635942&quot;&gt;Charles Marohn of Strong Towns on fixing North America’s broken zoning:: So let me be clear: when I say we want to “make better decisions inevitable over time,” I don’t mean inevitable like gravity. I mean inevitable like compound interest—tiny, persistent, visible pressure applied in the same direction until the math changes. It’s slow, messy, and often invisible at first.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/profile/11031131-charles-marohn/note/c-122635942&quot;&gt;Charles Marohn of Strong Towns on fixing North America’s broken zoning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is why the Strong Towns approach matters even more in places like yours, where the problem isn’t preemption from above, but institutional entropy from within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what breaks the cycle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a single lever. But here are a few that I think work together:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narrative dominance&lt;/strong&gt;. Most communities have no alternative story about why the current system fails. Our job is to provide that story, clearly, repeatedly, and with examples that show what’s possible. When councilmembers start hearing the same questions from multiple directions—“Why are we blocking gentle density that aligns with our values?”—they start to feel the pressure shift.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create visible wins&lt;/strong&gt;. If the system won’t legalize ADUs by right across the board, help one homeowner do it as a pilot. Or find one that is grandfathered in and working well. Document everything. Turn the story into a column, a workshop, a visual. Sometimes the clearest path is to de-risk the unfamiliar by showing that it’s already working, quietly. The housing toolkit I shared with you is full or boringly normal people doing these things we want to ultimately seem boringly normal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strategic allyship inside the bureaucracy.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t need your entire staff to champion reform, just one or two mid-level staffers willing to help shape internal proposals, provide cost estimates, or identify the least risky way to get started. Celebrate their efforts publicly to protect them institutionally.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback loops that don’t require council&lt;/strong&gt;. Consider embedding reforms inside budget decisions, infrastructure maintenance plans, or administrative manuals. If you can’t change zoning directly, can you change how capital improvements prioritize walkable areas? Can you bake small wins into how staff scopes repairs?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pressure from organized outsiders.&lt;/strong&gt; Not state preemption, but organized citizen campaigns. If your commissioners and staff are stuck, outside groups (like a Strong Towns Local Conversation) can bring energy and legitimacy to the push. Don’t make it a demand for radical change; make it a call to implement the next smallest step.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/06/p1606-c-122635942/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/06/p1606-c-122635942/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: read load to generate feeds makes running your own BlueSky instance only affordable to people with lots of $$ ; uniphil:: Can atproto scale down? Write View for back links (i.e. not the full AppView and not the Relay) on a raspberry pi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 5, 2025 18:14 &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.bad-example.com/can-atproto-scale-down/&quot;&gt;ME:: read load to generate feeds makes running your own BlueSky instance only affordable to people with lots of $$ ; uniphil:: Can atproto scale down? Write View for back links (i.e. not the full AppView and not the Relay) on a raspberry pi&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: ` a Hard Thing that BlueSky’s AppView implementation must do is serve over 31 million users (read load) with best-in-class feedgen. Our self-host dream doesn’t involve that. … Our self-host dream does involve handling the same 31M user write load as Bluesky’s, but I think this is where the it’s expensive critique gets wires crossed: Bluesky’s read load is what’s actually expensive. I have a billion links on a happy raspberry pi.`&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/05/p1814-can-atproto-scale-down/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/05/p1814-can-atproto-scale-down/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Bad for the environment yet good for already privileged experts who have time and energy to experiment seems to be the common thread of this ever evolving ML world ; Thomas Ptacek:: My AI Skeptic Friends Are All Nuts · The Fly Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 5, 2025 18:09  &lt;a href=&quot;https://fly.io/blog/youre-all-nuts/&quot;&gt;ME:: Bad for the environment yet good for already privileged experts who have time and energy to experiment seems to be the common thread of this ever evolving ML world ; Thomas Ptacek:: My AI Skeptic Friends Are All Nuts · The Fly Blog&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– ROFL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Call any of this out if you want to watch a TED talk about how hard it is to stream The Expanse on LibreWolf. Yeah, we get it. You don’t believe in IPR. Then shut the fuck up about IPR. Reap the whirlwind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s all special pleading anyways. LLMs digest code further than you do. If you don’t believe a typeface designer can stake a moral claim on the terminals and counters of a letterform, you sure as hell can’t be possessive about a red-black tree. … When I started writing a couple days ago, I wrote a section to “level set” to the state of the art of LLM-assisted programming. A bluefish filet has a longer shelf life than an LLM take. In the time it took you to read this, everything changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kids today don’t just use agents; they use asynchronous agents. They wake up, free-associate 13 different things for their LLMs to work on, make coffee, fill out a TPS report, drive to the Mars Cheese Castle, and then check their notifications. They’ve got 13 PRs to review. Three get tossed and re-prompted. Five of them get the same feedback a junior dev gets. And five get merged&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/05/p1809-youre-all-nuts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/05/p1809-youre-all-nuts/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME: stories have their time and place, sometimes people just want to hear the facts first ; Eliot Peper:: How to Become a Better Conversationalist</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 28, 2025 21:01 &lt;a href=&quot;https://every.to/p/how-to-become-a-better-conversationalist&quot;&gt;ME: stories have their time and place, sometimes people just want to hear the facts first ; Eliot Peper:: How to Become a Better Conversationalist&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;That experience revealed another way to be interesting: package ideas in stories. Skipping straight to the punch line ruins the joke, and morals don’t stick without parables. Wrapping your idea in narrative enables others to engage with it more deeply, understand it more fully, and remember it later. So instead of diving into a direct explanation, tell a story that embodies the truth you want to communicate. Like enthusiasm, storytelling is contagious, and soon you’ll be trading insight-laden tales. ... Conversely, when you ask a question, rather than seeking an explicit answer, challenge yourself to use the question as a prompt to elicit the most interesting possible response from your interlocutor.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/28/p2101-how-to-become-a-better-conversationalist/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/28/p2101-how-to-become-a-better-conversationalist/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
