<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 21:57:41 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 21:57:41 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>No surprise in Firefox Support Questions by Operating System: Windows 10 is dominant, followed by Windows 7; Windows 8, Mac and Linux are used by a minority of Users</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s surprising but not really surprising that folks hold onto Windows 7: they like the non Metro-ness of the interface and/or their hardware is old; and or many other long tail of reasons some of which are valid :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In my bubble Windows 10 is far superior because of anti-virus and security maijly but hey I can see the reasons why others wouldn&amp;#39;t agree!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;code for the following OS graphs:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kitsune-api/blob/master/VISUALIZATIONS/12november2018-gauge-plot-ff62.r&quot;&gt;12november2018-gauge-plot-ff62.r&lt;/a&gt; (not sure why it has soooo much white space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kitsune-api/blob/master/VISUALIZATIONS/12november2018-gauge-plot-ff61.r&quot;&gt;12november2018-gauge-plot-ff61.r&lt;/a&gt; (not sure why it has soooo much white space)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ff61:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kitsune-api/raw/master/VISUALIZATIONS/5x5border-trimmed-ff61-first-3-weeks-operating-system.png&quot; alt=&quot;ff61 first 3 week operating system&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ff62:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kitsune-api/raw/master/VISUALIZATIONS/5x5border-trimmed-ff62-first-3-weeks-operating-system.png&quot; alt=&quot;ff62 first 3 week operating system&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/15/p1-no-surprise-in-ff-desktop-questions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/15/p1-no-surprise-in-ff-desktop-questions/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>John Battelle: Tech must get over itself and solve problems that really matter!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In John Battelle&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://shift.newco.co/2018/11/12/tech-must-get-over-its-superman-complex-or-were-all-screwed/&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Tech Must Get Over Its Superman Complex, Or We’re All Screwed&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; says we should solve problems that matter and I agree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Witness this nearly idea-free interview with Google CEO Sundar Pichai, also in the Times, where the meticulously media-prepped executive opines on whether his industry has a role to play in society’s ills: “Every generation is worried about the new technology, and feels like this time it’s different. Our parents worried about Elvis Presley’s influence on kids. So, I’m always asking the question, “Why would it be any different this time?” Having said that, I do realize the change that’s happening now is much faster than ever before. My son still doesn’t have a phone.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pichai’s son may not have a phone, but he is earning money mining Ethereum (really, you can’t make this shit up). I’m not sure the son of a centi-millionaire needs to earn money – but it certainly is useful to master the algorithms that will soon control nearly every aspect of human life. So – no, son, no addictive phone for you (even though my company makes them, and makes their operating systems, and makes the apps which ensure their addictive qualities).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But mining crypto currency? Absolutely!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should Harari be proven right and humanity becomes irrelevant, I’m pretty sure Pichai’s son will have a first class ticket out of whatever mess is left behind. But the rest of us? We should probably focus on making sure that kid never needs to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Absolutely &lt;a href=&quot;https://shift.newco.co/2018/11/12/tech-must-get-over-its-superman-complex-or-were-all-screwed/&quot;&gt;read the whole thing&lt;/a&gt; and Homo Deus!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/13/p1-john-batelle-tech-must-get-over-itself/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/13/p1-john-batelle-tech-must-get-over-itself/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ton points to Bryan Alexander's excellent post on how World War I actually continued until 1923</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zylstra.org/blog/2018/11/the-end-of-war-a-graphic-record/&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;The end of the war -- a Graphic Record&amp;quot;, Ton&lt;/a&gt; points to Bryan Alexander&amp;#39;s excellent post, &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bryanalexander.org/politics/when-the-guns-stopped-but-the-future-kept-happening/&quot;&gt;When the guns stopped, but the future kept happening&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;, on how World War I actually continued until 1923 in Eastern Europe. Shows how Western European-centric we are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&quot;So at the very least we can track these WWI continuations and echoes for five more horrendous years.  Indeed, Robert Gerwarth argues that we should date the war’s end as 1923.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Why, then, are our eyes drawn to 11/11/18?  I think a major reason is the long-standing* divide between eastern and western Europe.  People in the latter usually avoid paying attention to the former.  This is especially true in the United States, where “Europe” usually means “Britain and France and maybe Germany.”  The former Ottoman lands are even more neglected.  The armistice we celebrate today was only for one of WWI’s fronts.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

A great deal of the violence follows from Allied mistakes and disasters, from the stupid invasion of the Soviet Union to the failed attempts to manage Turkey.  The armistice lets us avoid all of that unpleasantness in favor of celebrating a clear victory instead.&quot;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/12/p1-world-war-i-actually-continued-until-1923-in-eastern-europe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/12/p1-world-war-i-actually-continued-until-1923-in-eastern-europe/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Remembrance Day 2018: Centum Corpora - 100 brass instruments 100 repeats of a musical phrase for 100 WWI soldiers</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://littlechambermusic.com/centum-corpora/&quot;&gt;Centum Corpora&lt;/a&gt; today which was was a very meditative and fitting way to commemorate the 100th anniversary of the WWI armistice day:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt; from their website&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&quot;The Little Chamber Music Series That Could, in association with the Homegoing Brass Band, are proud to present Centum Corpora.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

To mark the 100th anniversary of Armistice Day and the end of “the war to end all wars“, we will be placing 100 professional, student and community musicians in the Jones 45 section (enter on 41st west of Fraser) of Mountain View Cemetery, which is a Commonwealth War Graves Commission section.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Each musician will be representing a different fallen soldier from WW1, and will be standing behind their marker for the performance. Simple, beautiful chords will echo through the cemetery when 100 instruments musically repeat the name and date of death of their veteran 100 times, as the community walks amongst them for this unique composed sound installation (approx 25min). In the spirit of what soldiers in WW1 faced, this outdoor performance will proceed in any weather.&quot;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/11/p1-remembrance-day-centum-corpora/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/11/p1-remembrance-day-centum-corpora/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Remember 2006 when we used our own websites for own media like Dave's podcast with Ross Rebagliati gold medal winner</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember 2006 when we used our own websites for own media like Dave&amp;#39;s podcast: 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://daveostory.com/audio-pods-songs/olympic-outsider/coffee-talk-with-gold-medalist-ross-rebagliati-olympic-outsider-3-enhanced/&quot;&gt;Coffee talk with Gold Medalist Ross Rebagliati – Olympic Outsider #3 (enhanced)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neither do I :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bonus fun: &lt;a href=&quot;http://roland.micro.blog/2018/11/10/good-morning-dave.html&quot;&gt;A Good Morning to Mike and Dave 14 second podcast&lt;/a&gt; who inspired me to write this post. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://tippett.org/&quot;&gt;Mike&amp;#39;s site&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://daveostory.com/&quot;&gt;Dave&amp;#39;s site&lt;/a&gt;; we&amp;#39;re still here on the internet making our stuff, join us :-)!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/10/p1-remember-our-2006-era-of-scrappy-podcasts-hosted-on-our-own-sites/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/10/p1-remember-our-2006-era-of-scrappy-podcasts-hosted-on-our-own-sites/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Katharine Bailey: 'AI' leads to more jobs for humans</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Former colleague Katharine Bailey and current AI maven at Accenture continues her fabulous explanations of &amp;#39;AI&amp;#39; to newbies like myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@katherinebailey/a-i-and-the-future-of-work-e18653d1636d?fbclid=IwAR0ADV0MMw8FS6G9EwtTGL9jRnVPPTaZ4NHBIBdiWRmHYPdXAtb99AEwXC8&quot;&gt;A.I. and the Future of Work&lt;/a&gt; she writes how AI leads to more jobs for humans:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

Many companies working in the AI space today are at pains to make clear that these technologies are about augmenting human intelligence, not about machine intelligence replacing humans. This may seem like a PR platitude to avoid coming across like they’re in the business of putting people out of a job, but it’s actually more than that. The type of AI that’s being used today, i.e. Machine Learning, doesn’t just augment humans, it requires them.

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;END QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As always &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@katherinebailey/a-i-and-the-future-of-work-e18653d1636d?fbclid=IwAR0ADV0MMw8FS6G9EwtTGL9jRnVPPTaZ4NHBIBdiWRmHYPdXAtb99AEwXC8&quot;&gt;read the whole thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/08/p1-humans-required-to-train-ai-model/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/08/p1-humans-required-to-train-ai-model/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>More fun with sparklines: use ggplot and remove facet wrap labels</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More fun with &amp;quot;pseudo&amp;quot; :-) sparklines: &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/10547487/remove-facet-wrap-labels-completely&quot;&gt;use ggplot and remove facet wrap labels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would be cool to do this for 365 days a year of flickr photos per woeid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or per average colour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or per the 256 web safe colours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/07/p1-pseudo-sparklines-with-ggplot2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/07/p1-pseudo-sparklines-with-ggplot2/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating Sparklines for Blog Post with R and Plumber: REST API in R, sparklines, calling the google analytics API in R!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brettrics.com/creating-sparklines-for-blog-post-with-r-and-plumber/&quot;&gt;Creating Sparklines for Blog Post with R and Plumber&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;--- need to read and learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/06/p1-sparklines-rest-api-using-plumber-google-analytics-r/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/06/p1-sparklines-rest-api-using-plumber-google-analytics-r/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking for recommendations: OmniOutliner for Windows or as a cross platform webapp? Checkvist seems close!</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love OmniOutliner on Mac!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking for something like that for Windows!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or since it&amp;#39;s 2018 as a cross-platform web app!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The closest thing I found was &lt;a href=&quot;https://checkvist.com&quot;&gt;Checkvist&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/05/p1-omni-outliner-for-windows/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/05/p1-omni-outliner-for-windows/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>gwern.net - bitcoin is worse is better </title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Pontifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gwern.net/Bitcoin-is-Worse-is-Better&quot;&gt;gwern.net - bitcoin is worse is better&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&quot;In short, Bitcoin is a perfect example of Worse is Better (original essay). You can see the tradeoffs that Richard P. Gabriel enumerates: Bitcoin has many edge cases; it lacks many properties one would desire for a cryptocurrency; the whitepaper is badly under-specified; much of the behavior is socially determined by what the miners and clients collectively agree to accept, not by the protocol; etc.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

But it seems to work. Just like Unix, there were countless ways to destroy your data or crash the system, which didn’t exist on more &quot;proper&quot; OSs like OpenVMS, and there were countless lacking features compared to systems like ITS or the Lisp machine OSs. But like the proverbial cockroaches, Unix spread, networked, survived - and the rest did not.30 And as it survives and evolves gradually, it slowly becomes what it &quot;should&quot; have been in the first place.&quot;

**END QUOTE**

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hmmmm :-) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gwern.net/Bitcoin-is-Worse-is-Better&quot;&gt;read the whole (very long) thing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/04/gwern-net-bitcoin-is-worse-is-better/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/11/04/gwern-net-bitcoin-is-worse-is-better/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
