<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 19:06:57 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 19:06:57 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Charles Marohn of Strong Towns on fixing North America's broken zoning:: So let me be clear: when I say we want to “make better decisions inevitable over time,” I don’t mean inevitable like gravity. I mean inevitable like compound interest—tiny, persistent, visible pressure applied in the same direction until the math changes. It’s slow, messy, and often invisible at first.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 6, 2025 16:06 &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/profile/11031131-charles-marohn/note/c-122635942&quot;&gt;Charles Marohn of Strong Towns on fixing North America’s broken zoning:: So let me be clear: when I say we want to “make better decisions inevitable over time,” I don’t mean inevitable like gravity. I mean inevitable like compound interest—tiny, persistent, visible pressure applied in the same direction until the math changes. It’s slow, messy, and often invisible at first.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://substack.com/profile/11031131-charles-marohn/note/c-122635942&quot;&gt;Charles Marohn of Strong Towns on fixing North America’s broken zoning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is why the Strong Towns approach matters even more in places like yours, where the problem isn’t preemption from above, but institutional entropy from within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what breaks the cycle?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a single lever. But here are a few that I think work together:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Narrative dominance&lt;/strong&gt;. Most communities have no alternative story about why the current system fails. Our job is to provide that story, clearly, repeatedly, and with examples that show what’s possible. When councilmembers start hearing the same questions from multiple directions—“Why are we blocking gentle density that aligns with our values?”—they start to feel the pressure shift.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create visible wins&lt;/strong&gt;. If the system won’t legalize ADUs by right across the board, help one homeowner do it as a pilot. Or find one that is grandfathered in and working well. Document everything. Turn the story into a column, a workshop, a visual. Sometimes the clearest path is to de-risk the unfamiliar by showing that it’s already working, quietly. The housing toolkit I shared with you is full or boringly normal people doing these things we want to ultimately seem boringly normal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strategic allyship inside the bureaucracy.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t need your entire staff to champion reform, just one or two mid-level staffers willing to help shape internal proposals, provide cost estimates, or identify the least risky way to get started. Celebrate their efforts publicly to protect them institutionally.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feedback loops that don’t require council&lt;/strong&gt;. Consider embedding reforms inside budget decisions, infrastructure maintenance plans, or administrative manuals. If you can’t change zoning directly, can you change how capital improvements prioritize walkable areas? Can you bake small wins into how staff scopes repairs?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pressure from organized outsiders.&lt;/strong&gt; Not state preemption, but organized citizen campaigns. If your commissioners and staff are stuck, outside groups (like a Strong Towns Local Conversation) can bring energy and legitimacy to the push. Don’t make it a demand for radical change; make it a call to implement the next smallest step.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/06/p1606-c-122635942/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/06/p1606-c-122635942/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: read load to generate feeds makes running your own BlueSky instance only affordable to people with lots of $$ ; uniphil:: Can atproto scale down? Write View for back links (i.e. not the full AppView and not the Relay) on a raspberry pi</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 5, 2025 18:14 &lt;a href=&quot;https://bsky.bad-example.com/can-atproto-scale-down/&quot;&gt;ME:: read load to generate feeds makes running your own BlueSky instance only affordable to people with lots of $$ ; uniphil:: Can atproto scale down? Write View for back links (i.e. not the full AppView and not the Relay) on a raspberry pi&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: ` a Hard Thing that BlueSky’s AppView implementation must do is serve over 31 million users (read load) with best-in-class feedgen. Our self-host dream doesn’t involve that. … Our self-host dream does involve handling the same 31M user write load as Bluesky’s, but I think this is where the it’s expensive critique gets wires crossed: Bluesky’s read load is what’s actually expensive. I have a billion links on a happy raspberry pi.`&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/05/p1814-can-atproto-scale-down/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/05/p1814-can-atproto-scale-down/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Bad for the environment yet good for already privileged experts who have time and energy to experiment seems to be the common thread of this ever evolving ML world ; Thomas Ptacek:: My AI Skeptic Friends Are All Nuts · The Fly Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Jun 5, 2025 18:09  &lt;a href=&quot;https://fly.io/blog/youre-all-nuts/&quot;&gt;ME:: Bad for the environment yet good for already privileged experts who have time and energy to experiment seems to be the common thread of this ever evolving ML world ; Thomas Ptacek:: My AI Skeptic Friends Are All Nuts · The Fly Blog&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– ROFL&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Call any of this out if you want to watch a TED talk about how hard it is to stream The Expanse on LibreWolf. Yeah, we get it. You don’t believe in IPR. Then shut the fuck up about IPR. Reap the whirlwind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It’s all special pleading anyways. LLMs digest code further than you do. If you don’t believe a typeface designer can stake a moral claim on the terminals and counters of a letterform, you sure as hell can’t be possessive about a red-black tree. … When I started writing a couple days ago, I wrote a section to “level set” to the state of the art of LLM-assisted programming. A bluefish filet has a longer shelf life than an LLM take. In the time it took you to read this, everything changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Kids today don’t just use agents; they use asynchronous agents. They wake up, free-associate 13 different things for their LLMs to work on, make coffee, fill out a TPS report, drive to the Mars Cheese Castle, and then check their notifications. They’ve got 13 PRs to review. Three get tossed and re-prompted. Five of them get the same feedback a junior dev gets. And five get merged&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/05/p1809-youre-all-nuts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/06/05/p1809-youre-all-nuts/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME: stories have their time and place, sometimes people just want to hear the facts first ; Eliot Peper:: How to Become a Better Conversationalist</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 28, 2025 21:01 &lt;a href=&quot;https://every.to/p/how-to-become-a-better-conversationalist&quot;&gt;ME: stories have their time and place, sometimes people just want to hear the facts first ; Eliot Peper:: How to Become a Better Conversationalist&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;That experience revealed another way to be interesting: package ideas in stories. Skipping straight to the punch line ruins the joke, and morals don’t stick without parables. Wrapping your idea in narrative enables others to engage with it more deeply, understand it more fully, and remember it later. So instead of diving into a direct explanation, tell a story that embodies the truth you want to communicate. Like enthusiasm, storytelling is contagious, and soon you’ll be trading insight-laden tales. ... Conversely, when you ask a question, rather than seeking an explicit answer, challenge yourself to use the question as a prompt to elicit the most interesting possible response from your interlocutor.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/28/p2101-how-to-become-a-better-conversationalist/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/28/p2101-how-to-become-a-better-conversationalist/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PROBABLY WRONG PREDICTION:: ME:: By Jan 1, 2034 Tesla still won't have full self driving cars (unless they add LiDAR and/or humans in the loop :-) !) ; Ben Thompson Oct 15, 2024:: Elon Dreams and Bitter Lessons – Stratechery </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 28, 2025 14:44  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2024/elon-dreams-and-bitter-lessons/&quot;&gt;PROBABLY WRONG PREDICTION:: ME:: By Jan 1, 2034 Tesla still won’t have full self driving cars (unless they add LiDAR and/or humans in the loop :-) !) ; Ben Thompson Oct 15, 2024:: Elon Dreams and Bitter Lessons – Stratechery &lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;“Do note that Karpathy — who worked at Tesla for five years — is hardly a neutral observer, and also note that he forecasts a fully neural net approach to driving as taking ten years; that’s hardly next year, as Musk promised. That end goal, though, is Level 5, with low cost sensors and thus low cost cars, the key ingredient of realizing the dream of full autonomy and the transformation that would follow.”&lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– See also Jonathon V. Last May 28, 2025:: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebulwark.com/p/elon-musk-self-driving-fsd-tesla-tony-stark-michael-scott&quot;&gt;A Song of “Full Self-Driving”: Elon Isn’t Tony Stark. He’s Michael Scott.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/28/p1444-elon-fsd-2034-still-wont-work-for-tesla-without-lidar-bitter-lessons/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/28/p1444-elon-fsd-2034-still-wont-work-for-tesla-without-lidar-bitter-lessons/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>forget what Wil said 🙂 LOL. For the real (TM) Vancouver, eat Filipino food at Pampanga's Cuisine or Kulinarya on the Drive,  bicycle, run, or walk or electric scouter around stanley park, Special Set Meal B at New Town Bakery with Super Strong hong kong iced milk tea, get an Aquabus ferry pass and stop at all the stops including Granville Island for Pad Thai Sen :-), Saturday Farmer's Market at Trout Lake or Riley Park, Revolver Coffee for a pourover coffee, take the Seabus to Shipyards and enjoy Metro Vancouver's best public space especially Polygon Gallery and Nemesis coffee and if you have time walk up Lonsdale and have Persian food e.g. at Yaas!!!!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 26, 2025 22:26 &lt;a href=&quot;https://cosocial.ca/@roland.wordpress.com@roland.wordpress.com/114578007562262873&quot;&gt;forget what Wil said 🙂 LOL. For the real (TM) Vancouver, eat Filipino food at Pampanga’s Cuisine or Kulinarya on the Drive,  bicycle, run, or walk or electric scouter around stanley park, Special Set Meal B at New Town Bakery with Super Strong hong kong iced milk tea, get an Aquabus ferry pass and stop at all the stops including Granville Island for Pad Thai Sen :-), Saturday Farmer’s Market at Trout Lake or Riley Park, Revolver Coffee for a pourover coffee, take the Seabus to Shipyards and enjoy Metro Vancouver’s best public space especially Polygon Gallery and Nemesis coffee and if you have time walk up Lonsdale and have Persian food e.g. at Yaas!!!!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/26/p2226-forget-what-wil-arndt-wrote-real-vancouver-kulinarya-revolver-pampangas-cuisine-yaas-nemesis-polygon/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/26/p2226-forget-what-wil-arndt-wrote-real-vancouver-kulinarya-revolver-pampangas-cuisine-yaas-nemesis-polygon/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: fork this Mediawiki VS Code LSP server and add support for SUMO KB markup extensions and style guide ; bhsd-harry/vscode-extension-wikiparser: VSCode language server for MediaWiki Wikitext</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 26, 2025 21:33 &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bhsd-harry/vscode-extension-wikiparser&quot;&gt;ME:: fork this Mediawiki VS Code LSP server and add support for SUMO KB markup extensions and style guide ; bhsd-harry/vscode-extension-wikiparser: VSCode language server for MediaWiki Wikitext&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/markup-chart&quot;&gt;SUMO KB Markup extensions&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/writing-guide-knowledge-base-articles#w_style-guide-and-copy-rules&quot;&gt;style guide&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;This is a language server extension for Visual Studio Code that provides language supports for the Wikitext language.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/26/p2133-vscode-extension-wikiparser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/26/p2133-vscode-extension-wikiparser/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Supports LUTs, iOS and Android. Is it real time? Better than Pearla, we'll see :-) ; Varlens - DSLR in Phone</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 22, 2025 21:51  &lt;a href=&quot;https://varlens.com/&quot;&gt;ME:: Supports LUTs, iOS and Android. Is it real time? Better than Pearla, we’ll see :-) ; Varlens - DSLR in Phone&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– iOS and Android with LUT support. We’ll see how good it is :-) &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;It even allows you import your own LUT files (.cube) to create unique images.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/22/p2151-varlens-com/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/22/p2151-varlens-com/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Generic Cerave moisture lotion is 5 dollars cheaper at Superstore compared to Shoppers Drug Mart both of which are owned by the same company LOL</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 21, 2025 08:26 &lt;a href=&quot;https://roland.wordpress.com/2025/05/16/270/&quot;&gt;Generic Cerave moisture lotion is 5 dollars cheaper at Superstore compared to Shoppers Drug Mart both of which are owned by the same company LOL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For those who celebrate generic cerave 🙂, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.realcanadiansuperstore.ca/en/moisturizing-cream/p/21450176_EA&quot;&gt;buy it at Real Canadian Superstore Supermarket where it’s $13.49 regular price&lt;/a&gt; not at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shoppersdrugmart.ca/life-brand-moisturizing-cream/p/BB_057800231141&quot;&gt;Shoppers Drug Mart at $18.99 regular price&lt;/a&gt; (both owned by the same company)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/21/p0826-generic-cervai-ski-lotion-5-dollars-cheaper-superstore-than-shoppers-oligopolies-dont-work/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/21/p0826-generic-cervai-ski-lotion-5-dollars-cheaper-superstore-than-shoppers-oligopolies-dont-work/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Home pourovers are better than most cafe pourovers example 8888 or something :-) Brandon Dixon:: Beans to Bots: Hacking My Coffee Machine with AI</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: May 12, 2025 07:35 &lt;a href=&quot;https://applied-gai-in-security.ghost.io/beans-to-bots-hacking-my-coffee-machine-with-ai/&quot;&gt;ME:: Home pourovers are better than most cafe pourovers example 8888 or something :-) Brandon Dixon:: Beans to Bots: Hacking My Coffee Machine with AI&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;For the final application form, I wanted to embody the Fellow Aiden as an AI agent. I worked several security problems using multi-agent frameworks like Autogen and CrewAI in the past, but for this, I felt the OpenAI Assistants API was the best choice, plus despite knowing all of the features, I had not built anything with it yet. As I did with the first app, I used O1 to help me out. This time, I took a staged approach where I first formed a basic chat application that used the API and then moved to merge the Fellow library capabilities. Within three hours, I had a completed assistant capable of scraping coffee websites, forming recipes and sending them to the machine. &lt;/code&gt; &amp;lt;– includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://chatgpt.com/share/679af023-81f4-800e-954c-314836faa2fd?ref=applied-gai-in-security.ghost.io&quot;&gt;an example prompt generate an Aiden pourover coffee recipe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/12/p0735-beans-to-bots-hacking-my-coffee-machine-with-ai/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/05/12/p0735-beans-to-bots-hacking-my-coffee-machine-with-ai/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
