<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:29:02 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:29:02 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Github Actions are super powerful and yaml is super confusing</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(refer to my previous post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/16/p1-simon-willison-git-scraping-how-to-use-github-actions-to-call-an-api-every-20-minutes/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison:Git scraping: track changes over  time by scraping to a Git repository aka how to use github actions to  call an API every 20 minutes&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to read Firefox Desktop support questions every 15 minutes roughly so I can generate infographics every hour. To do this:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I modified my trusty &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kits-api3/blob/main/get-creator-answers-questions-for-arbitrary-time-period.rb&quot;&gt;get-creator-answers-questions-for-arbitrary-time-period.rb&lt;/a&gt;  (compare with api2’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kits-api2/blob/master/get-creator-answers-questions-for-arbitrary-time-period.rb&quot;&gt;get-creator-answers-questions-for-arbitrary-time-period.rb&lt;/a&gt; ) as follows:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;awesome_print&lt;/code&gt; is no longer maintained but there is a fork called &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;amazing_print&lt;/code&gt; which I switched to.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Fixed two long standing bugs that I just discovered : 1. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mozilla/kitsune/issues/3686&quot;&gt;Kitsune issue 3686&lt;/a&gt; didn’t work for both PST and PDT so I wrote &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;KludgeTimeFromBogusZtoUTC(pst_in_utc_str)&lt;/code&gt; 2. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;updated&lt;/code&gt; was wrongly using the uncorrected time!&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Created a github action, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rtanglao/rt-kits-api3/blob/main/.github/workflows/getffquestions.yml&quot;&gt;getffquestions.yml&lt;/a&gt; to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;get-creator-answers-questions-for-arbitrary-time-period.rb&lt;/code&gt; every 15 minutes and create a CSV file using Ruby 2.7&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the process I found out that like Heroku in 2007 :-), you can create servers at will with Github actions and those servers can basically run anything on Windows, Mac or Linux!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I also learned that I dislike YAML :-) Too loosey goosey! For a good time try and figure out what &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;|-&lt;/code&gt; means. This is just one of the many things that are vexing!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next thing to do: create a second github action to create infographics using R or Ruby every hour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/18/p1-github-actions-super-great-yaml-is-super-confusing/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/18/p1-github-actions-super-great-yaml-is-super-confusing/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simon Willison:Git scraping: track changes over time by scraping to a Git repository aka how to use github actions to call an API every 20 minutes</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2020/Oct/9/git-scraping/&quot;&gt;Git scraping: track changes over time by scraping to a Git repository&lt;/a&gt; aka how to use github actions to call an API every 20 minutes; the git action is a Linux cron job that calls curl to get the data and if it has changed to commit to github ; see also t&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/simonw/status/1314654153646383104&quot;&gt;his Hacker News thread for more examples&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/18/p1-github-actions-super-great-yaml-is-super-confusing/&quot;&gt;next post will be on how I used this for Firefox Support questions&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/16/p1-simon-willison-git-scraping-how-to-use-github-actions-to-call-an-api-every-20-minutes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/16/p1-simon-willison-git-scraping-how-to-use-github-actions-to-call-an-api-every-20-minutes/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>More than a few days, now starting my job search in earnest :-) aka Looking for work</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the department of famous last words :-): &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/08/18/p1-thank-you-mozilla/&quot;&gt;I’ll take a few days off and then start my next.gig.search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I needed more time off than the week that I tweeted about :-)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Here’s my &lt;strong&gt;WORK IN PROGRSS SUMMARY&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Proven ability to improve software products by analyzing user  feedback and reporting insights as well as improving support  documentation and processes. Please email me at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rolandt@gmail.com&quot;&gt;rolandt@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; if you have a software support role that combines working with folks  who use the software, gathering insights and working with engineering  and product to improve the software based on those insights. It would  also be great if I could help update the documentation so users benefit  from every support ticket and insight!&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I love software and people and have many years of experience working at the intersection of software developers and those who use the  software. I am an avid life long learner who enjoys becoming an expert  in a software product from the API level up, supporting software  products and developing them.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Some examples of products that I would love to work with include  (not in order): slack, Tableau, WordPress, github, gitlab, Thunderbird,  Squarespace, Lightroom, R Studio and many more!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re an employer or recruiter and interested in  me, please reach out on linkedIn: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rtanglao/&quot;&gt;rtanglao&lt;/a&gt;, twitter:&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rtanglao/&quot;&gt;rtanglao&lt;/a&gt;, roland AT rolandtanglao.com (goes to the same place as rolandt@gmail.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/15/p1-next-gig-more-than-a-few-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/10/15/p1-next-gig-more-than-a-few-days/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thank you Mozilla! Leaving after being laid off after 11 years #mozillalifeboat</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was one of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.mozilla.org/blog/2020/08/11/changing-world-changing-mozilla/&quot;&gt;250 people laid off last week by Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I leave with nothing but gratitude for the open web, Firefox, Thunderbird, the amazing Mozilla staff and most importantly the fab Mozilla volunteers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Really enjoyed being the Thunderbird support lead, then the Firefox Android support coordinator and finally the Firefox Support Analyst and Support Release Manager.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I learned a lot about large and small open source software projects, the folks who use them and about releasing  and reporting insights on multiple products in parallel and finally I learned a wee bit about community management from working with an amazing community of Mozilla volunteers on both Firefox  products (Firefox Desktop, Firefox for iOS, Firefox for Android, Firefox Private Network, Firefox Lite, etc etc) and Thunderbird.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onwards! #thanks #lucky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll take a few days off and then start my next.gig.search&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I can be reached on linkedIn: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rtanglao/&quot;&gt;rtanglao&lt;/a&gt;, twitter:&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rtanglao/&quot;&gt;rtanglao&lt;/a&gt;, roland AT rolandtanglao.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/08/18/p1-thank-you-mozilla/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/08/18/p1-thank-you-mozilla/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wired: Social Movements Are Pushing Google Sheets to the Breaking Point&lt;--- what if there were a decentralized version of a collaborative editing environment :-) hmmmm :-)</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://onezero.medium.com/social-movements-are-pushing-google-sheets-to-the-breaking-point-28bb86b76043&quot;&gt;Wired: Social Movements Are Pushing Google Sheets to the Breaking Point&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;— what if there were a decentralized version of a collaborative editing environment :-) hmmmm :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/08/08/p1-distributed-google-docs-sheets/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/08/08/p1-distributed-google-docs-sheets/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ton: Your Blog is your Avatar &lt;--- AMEN!</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I think it is even impossible to hide behind fancy words, or even  freeze-dried reporting, the longer you sustain a personal blog. Through  the years your blog will always reflect who you are, as your interests  move with your own life and experiences, regardless whether you chose to limit yourself to non-personal topics and interests. It is &lt;del&gt;very hard&lt;/del&gt; impossible to portray yourself as anything other than you over the  course of many years, or not have your self be revealed through your  writing during that time. “ &amp;lt;— from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zylstra.org/blog/2020/08/your-blog-is-your-avatar/&quot;&gt;Ton Zijlstra: Your Blog is Your Avatar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amen!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This particular blog dates  only from 2004 on but I’ve been blogging since 1999 (starting with Radio UserLand which is where I blogged lots of links back in 99  but that has been replaced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rtanglao/&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://pinboard.in/u:rtanglao&quot;&gt;Pinboard&lt;/a&gt; and even &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;checkvist&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have far too many interests that I’ve blogged about on many many blogs over the year but definitely eating :-) (&lt;a href=&quot;http://vaneats.com/&quot;&gt;VanEats.com&lt;/a&gt; 2000-2008) is one of them and as well as &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2004/08/02/blogs-are-about-the-people-not-about-the-technology/&quot;&gt;knowledge management&lt;/a&gt;, open source (drupal, bryght) helping folks with software and dabbling in &lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2018/08/04/p1-programmking-should-be-easier/&quot;&gt;programming in the small&lt;/a&gt; as I have since 1977 when I was 13.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/08/03/p1-your-blog-is-your-avatar/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/08/03/p1-your-blog-is-your-avatar/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Please consider donating to my team, Sofia's Camera Club, for the virtual Cypress Challenge in honour of my mother who died of Pancreatic Cancer in 2013. 100% of your donations go to pancreatic cancer; this is a zero overhead ride</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hi Friends: Please consider &lt;a href=&quot;http://donate.bccancerfoundation.com/site/TR/Events/CypressChallenge/2124870577?pg=team&amp;amp;fr_id=3723&amp;amp;team_id=23796&amp;amp;_ga=2.52942112.96561269.1595993296-1425630607.1595993296&amp;amp;fbclid=IwAR2nXXeuM2ZDJBjy13r-Egr2lkdBFTINFGBl6QrBEyTR44qPTl4TqDhTreM&quot;&gt;donating&lt;/a&gt; to my team for the Virtual Cypress  Challenge, Sofia’s Camera Club, in honour of my mother who died of  pancreatic cancer in 2013.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://donate.bccancerfoundation.com/site/TR/Events/CypressChallenge/2124870577?pg=team&amp;amp;fr_id=3723&amp;amp;team_id=23796&amp;amp;_ga=2.52942112.96561269.1595993296-1425630607.1595993296&amp;amp;fbclid=IwAR2nXXeuM2ZDJBjy13r-Egr2lkdBFTINFGBl6QrBEyTR44qPTl4TqDhTreM&quot;&gt;http://donate.bccancerfoundation.com/site/TR/Events/CypressChallenge/2124870577?pg=team&amp;amp;fr_id=3723&amp;amp;team_id=23796&amp;amp;_ga=2.52942112.96561269.1595993296-1425630607.1595993296&amp;amp;fbclid=IwAR2nXXeuM2ZDJBjy13r-Egr2lkdBFTINFGBl6QrBEyTR44qPTl4TqDhTreM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We’ll be riding up Cypress with our camera(phone)s! My Mom loved taking snapshots during her many travels.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100% of your donations go to pancreatic cancer; this is a zero overhead ride.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/08/01/p1-virtual-cypress-challenge-sofias-camera-club/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/08/01/p1-virtual-cypress-challenge-sofias-camera-club/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Computing Education Research Blog: Proposal #3 to Change CS Education to Reduce Inequity: Call a truce on academic misconduct cases for programming assignments and it is not necessary to have to struggle to learn</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://computinged.wordpress.com/2020/07/30/proposal-3-to-change-cs-education-to-reduce-inequity-call-a-truce-on-academic-misconduct-cases-on-programming-assignments/&quot;&gt;Proposal #3 to Change CS Education to Reduce Inequity: Call a truce on academic misconduct cases for programming assignments&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– “defund the cheating police” !!! aka just because you enjoyed the  process of discovery doesn’t mean that’s the best way to learn –&amp;gt;  “Learning requires challenge, but too much cognitive load reduces  learning. My guess is that we believe in the power of struggle because  it’s how many of us learned computing. We struggled to figure out  undocumented systems, to make things work, and to figure out why they  worked. We come away with a rationalization that the process of  discovery, without a teacher or guidance, is what led to our learning.  The problem is that for experts and high-ability/highly-motivated  learners, we like to learn that way. We want to figure it out for  ourselves. There is a motivational (affective) value for discovery.  However, the available evidence suggests that our belief in discovery is a mirage, a cognitive illusion, a trick we play on ourselves. We don’t  learn best by discovery.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://computinged.wordpress.com/2020/07/30/proposal-3-to-change-cs-education-to-reduce-inequity-call-a-truce-on-academic-misconduct-cases-on-programming-assignments/&quot;&gt;READ THE WHOLE THING&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/31/p1-defund-the-cheating-police-and-improve-computer-science-education/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/31/p1-defund-the-cheating-police-and-improve-computer-science-education/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BlogThis! A checkvist list of links to blog</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Been using this: &lt;a href=&quot;https://checkvist.com/p/RjpwQvvwnw89WecevQFXxe&quot;&gt;BlogThis&lt;/a&gt; which is a checkvist outline as a list of things to blog in the future. Don’t know how long this will last but quite happy with it for now. It’s cross platform and fun!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;check it out:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://checkvist.com/p/RjpwQvvwnw89WecevQFXxe&quot; scrolling=&quot;auto&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Regulate the web by yiibu: 'start challenging the assumption that the future of our online spaces can only consist of a more centralized, optimized, and sanitized version of our present'</title>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1Nmc5ZlbO3nQf8DRmUIa4lxzFR4woeaFv0OIQMF8QcDo/edit?pli=1#slide=id.g809e2812ce_0_269&quot;&gt;Regulate the web by yiibu&lt;/a&gt;: ‘start challenging the assumption that the future of our online spaces can only consist of a more centralized, optimized, and sanitized version of our present’ &amp;lt;— read the whole thing and  comment, it’s a public google slides document!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/21/p1-yiibu-regulate-the-web/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/21/p1-yiibu-regulate-the-web/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
