<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Roland Tanglao</title>
    <description>flickr.com/roland, twitter.com/rtanglao #firefox #thunderbird
</description>
    <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rolandtanglao.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 21:06:35 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 21:06:35 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Broken Achievement Society Social Scene :-) ; Doug Belshaw:: What promised to liberate us instead helps to control us</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 30, 2025 04:58 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.dougbelshaw.com/liberate-control/&quot;&gt;ME:: Broken Achievement Society Social Scene :-) ; Doug Belshaw:: What promised to liberate us instead helps to control us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.dougbelshaw.com/liberate-control/&quot;&gt;Doug Belshaw:: What promised to liberate us instead helps to control us&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Reclaim the right to be opaque, unmeasured, and unproductive.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Resist the enclosure of digital life by prioritising connection with other people over connection with brands and corporations&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Build small, shared spaces that are not immediately optimised for extraction.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/29/p2058-liberate-control/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/29/p2058-liberate-control/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: 2023 How to: read/write github gists using the gist API; Github Gist Is Here To Save The Day...Literally! - Resources / Community Tutorials - Developer Forum ¦ Roblox</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 27, 2025 18:08 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://devforum.roblox.com/t/github-gist-is-here-to-save-the-dayliterally/2412487&quot;&gt;ME:: 2023 How to: read/write github gists using the gist API; Github Gist Is Here To Save The Day…Literally! - Resources / Community Tutorials - Developer Forum ¦ Roblox&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– from 2023 so could be out of date&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/27/p1008-how-to-read-write-github-gists-using-the-api/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/27/p1008-how-to-read-write-github-gists-using-the-api/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl-dr-ing Coping with the flood of misinformation and the fact that we know less than we think we do (e.g. how do toilets work really?): rigourously maintained factual chronological timelines, critical ignoring, cognitive elaboration ; Erin Kissane:: Landslide; a ghost story</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 27, 2025 17:32 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wrecka.ge/landslide-a-ghost-story/&quot;&gt;ME:: tl-dr-ing Coping with the flood of misinformation and the fact that we know less than we think we do (e.g. how do toilets work really?): rigourously maintained factual chronological timelines, critical ignoring, cognitive elaboration ; Erin Kissane:: Landslide; a ghost story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wrecka.ge/landslide-a-ghost-story/&quot;&gt;Erin Kissane:: Landslide; a ghost story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So: Even those of us who think we know things and believe that we’re “paying attention” know far less than we think we do. We are mostly skating on a brittle scrim of knowledge over an unperceived void, blithely trusting the resources around us to fill in for our spotty brains on a just-in-time basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And let me say: Chronological timelines are about the least innovative and least sexy or funding-attracting thing imaginable, but like…go try to find them, for the things happening now! They’re hard to find and hard to make and hardest to maintain. Yet without an easily referenced record of when the many things happened, we’re extraordinarily vulnerable to doctored, adulterated, and just made up summaries of even extremely recent history. The subsequent mass misbeliefs can feel, to people who were closely tracking the realities being reinterpreted, like the results of mass hypnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think there are many other ways to densify information and make knowledge durable—and that people who work on the social internet should be thinking about how they can work toward that in their systems, in ways that also respect people’s desire to retain the orality or ephemerality of some communication. This is one of the things I’ll be digging down through in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Several of the papers I’ve been working through discuss the role of cognitive elaboration in the creation of durable knowledge. Cognitive elaboration is, very roughly, synthesizing new information with other knowledge or otherwise playing around with information as a way of knitting it into our minds in ways we can use. This is an obvious springboard for the kind of facile, thought-leader-scented solutions institutions adore (all articles are now quizzes!) but I think it’s also fruitful territory for more sophisticated thinking and experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Critical ignoring has come up several times in my explorations since my crimeing partner Liz Neeley first sent me a paper about it. I’m also very interested in trustworthy catch-up tools that perhaps use machine learning but are not chatbot summaries. A lot of my work this year has been briefings and explainers on top of timelines as a resource for people who need to just drop the rope—and then, when they’re ready, return and catch up without having to go out and wrestle the shrieking backlog themselves. I don’t think we’re all the way there yet, but we’re learning a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/27/p0932-landslide-a-ghost-story/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/27/p0932-landslide-a-ghost-story/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So much for my memory :-). Opening day for me in the 2025/26 season was Dec 21, 2025 about 3 weeks after opening day for the 2024/2025 season ; November 24, 2024: Tag Eins des 2024-25 Langlaufsaisons bei Cypress :-) #FreeTheHeelFreeTheMind #XcSkiing ¦ Nordic Ski ¦ Strava</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 23, 2025 06:55 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/12975153329&quot;&gt;So much for my memory :-). Opening day for me in the 2025/26 season was Dec 21, 2025 about 3 weeks after opening day for the 2024/2025 season ; November 24, 2024: Tag Eins des 2024-25 Langlaufsaisons bei Cypress :-) #FreeTheHeelFreeTheMind #XcSkiing ¦ Nordic Ski ¦ Strava&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/22/p2255-cypress-xc-skiing-opening-day-3-weeks-later-2025-26-season/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/22/p2255-cypress-xc-skiing-opening-day-3-weeks-later-2025-26-season/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: the bible is not anti-poor, anti-abortion, anti gay rights and anti-immigrant. Read it completely 'Christians'! ; Nicholas Kristof:: What Would Surprise Jesus About Christmas 2025? - The New York Times</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 20, 2025 15:59 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.is/OILbI#selection-949.0-953.408&quot;&gt;ME:: the bible is not anti-poor, anti-abortion, anti gay rights and anti-immigrant. Read it completely ‘Christians’! ; Nicholas Kristof:: What Would Surprise Jesus About Christmas 2025? - The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I do too. So many people who claim to follow Jesus appear to have no idea what he actually taught. When I was an evangelical, we thought it was important to know what the Bible said and act on it. But today the evangelical movement focuses largely on social agendas not promoted in the Bible while ignoring ethical injunctions the Bible makes repeatedly. Whatever one’s views of abortion today, it is simply wrong to say the Bible opposes it. The Bible never mentions a deliberate attempt to abort a fetus, and the only biblical passages that relate to the question of whether a fetus is to be treated as a living person with human rights indicate the answer is no (e.g., Exodus 21:22-25). What the Bible does stress, page after page, is the need to care for the poor, the outcast, the “other.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So too with gay rights: People regularly quote Leviticus about how it’s a sin for a man to sleep with a man (Leviticus 18:22). But they then ignore the very next chapter, which explicitly insists that immigrants to your country are to be treated just the same as citizens (Leviticus 19:33-34). Why do people focus on one verse instead of the other? They simply pick what they find useful for their own views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/20/p0759-thebible-is-not-antigay-antiimmigrant-antiabortion-antipoor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/20/p0759-thebible-is-not-antigay-antiimmigrant-antiabortion-antipoor/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: Podcasts should be 15 minutes or less, prove me wrong :-). Substack is funded by terrible people and supports terrible people on its platform (as well as great people who don't realize that they are helping those terrible people) part 88888 ; Joan Westenberg:: Comfort Food for the Thinking Class: The Great Intellectual Stagnation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 20, 2025 07:58 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.joanwestenberg.com/comfort-food-for-the-thinking-class-the-great-intellectual-stagnation/&quot;&gt;ME:: Podcasts should be 15 minutes or less, prove me wrong :-). Substack is funded by terrible people and supports terrible people on its platform (as well as great people who don’t realize that they are helping those terrible people) part 88888 ; Joan Westenberg:: Comfort Food for the Thinking Class: The Great Intellectual Stagnation&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Our intellectual underground, such as it is, consists of Substack, a platform funded by some of the most establishment venture capital imaginable, and podcasts that run for three hours and manage to say less than a single well-constructed paragraph.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;previously&quot;&gt;Previously&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;August 7, 2025 &lt;a href=&quot;https://rolandtanglao.com/2025/08/07/om-malik-wrong-about-substack-in-1939-would-you-write-for-nazi-newspaper/&quot;&gt;I don’t care what people who I otherwise respect like Om Malik and Dana Blankenhorn say about network effects blah blah blah :-) . It is wrong to be on a platform that openly allows hate speech. If the Nazi Party’s newspaper paid you $USD1000 / month in 1939 to write an op-ed monthly would you do it? No. https://om.co/2025/08/03/the-why-of-substack/ is wrong. sorry not sorry Om et al!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/19/p2358-comfort-food-for-the-thinking-class-the-great-intellectual-stagnation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/19/p2358-comfort-food-for-the-thinking-class-the-great-intellectual-stagnation/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: to import a LUT into No Fusion, tap on the multi-photo rectangular icon to import 1 or more LUTs OR Add New Preset &gt; Tick Blank &gt; Import ; LUT Import ¦ No Fusion Camera</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 18, 2025 17:48 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nofusion.app/en/lut.html&quot;&gt;ME:: to import a LUT into No Fusion, tap on the multi-photo rectangular icon to import 1 or more LUTs OR Add New Preset &amp;gt; Tick Blank &amp;gt; Import ; LUT Import ¦ No Fusion Camera&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The following quoted instructions are out of date :-) LOL I have failed to update documentation in a timely fashion in my career too so this is not a big criticism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In No Fusion, navigate to Settings -&amp;gt; Stylization -&amp;gt; Add New Preset -&amp;gt; LUT, then you can import LUTs from your photo library or files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/18/p0948-nofusion-camera-app-howto-lut/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/18/p0948-nofusion-camera-app-howto-lut/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: tl;dr-ing: pick from or edit LLM generated regexes or add your own and see relevant examples in VSCode, seems like a practical and safe use of LLMs;  Siddhartha Prasad:: LLMs ⭢ Regular Expressions, Responsibly!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 17, 2025 17:51 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.brownplt.org/2025/12/11/pick-regex.html&quot;&gt;ME:: tl;dr-ing: pick from or edit LLM generated regexes or add your own and see relevant examples in VSCode, seems like a practical and safe use of LLMs;  Siddhartha Prasad:: LLMs ⭢ Regular Expressions, Responsibly!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.brownplt.org/2025/12/11/pick-regex.html&quot;&gt;Siddhartha Prasad:: LLMs ⭢ Regular Expressions, Responsibly!&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But we can do a lot better! Our new tool, PICK:Regex, does the following. It asks you for a prompt and sends it to a GenAI system. However, it doesn’t ask for one regex; instead, it uses an LLMs ability to interpret prose in multiple ways to generate multiple (about four) candidate expressions. (The details don’t matter, but if you want to you can open the images below in a new tab to read them more easily.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In theory, that’s better than getting just one interpretation. But now you may have to read four regexes like the above, which is actually worse! Therefore, instead, PICK shows you concrete examples. Furthermore, the examples are carefully chosen to tell apart the regexes. You are then asked to upvote/downvote each example. As you do, you are actually voting on all the candidate regexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You can stop at any point (you’re always shown the regexes), but the process naturally halts when only one regex remains (this is your best candidate of the ones you’ve seen so far) or none remain (in which case it would have been dangerous to use the LLMs output!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/17/p0951-pick-regex/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/17/p0951-pick-regex/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: automation makes the bits left over humans more challenging; See also Lisanne Bainbridge's paper: Ironies of Automation from 1983; Tae Selene Sandoval Murgan:: thoughts/on-using-language-models-for-programming.md </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 16, 2025 03:20 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeberg.org/tssm/thoughts/src/branch/canon/on-using-language-models-for-programming.md&quot;&gt;ME:: automation makes the bits left over humans more challenging; See also Lisanne Bainbridge’s paper: Ironies of Automation from 1983; Tae Selene Sandoval Murgan:: thoughts/on-using-language-models-for-programming.md &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;QUOTE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read the whole thing: &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeberg.org/tssm/thoughts/src/branch/canon/on-using-language-models-for-programming.md&quot;&gt;Tae Selene Sandoval Murgan:: thoughts/on-using-language-models-for-programming.md at canon - tssm/thoughts - Codeberg.org&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;lt;– See also &lt;a href=&quot;https://ckrybus.com/static/papers/Bainbridge_1983_Automatica.pdf&quot;&gt;Lisanne Bainbridge’s classic 1983 paper in Automatic: Ironies of Automation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I wrote a version of the above as a Mastodon thread. And then I read Ironies of automation by Lisanne Bainbridge, a paper that, quoting its abstract, “discusses the ways in which automation of industrial processes may expand rather than eliminate problems with the human operator”. I got several ideas from it, but the most important is that regardless of how automation is performed, whatever levels of “intelligence” an automated system has, it’s rarely designed to collaborate with the human that formerly performed the work. On the contrary it’s designed to replace them. Which is an irony (as defined in the paper) because (among others) “by taking away the easy parts of his task, automation can make the difficult parts of the human operator’s task more difficult.” Even more, automation seldom “consider the integration of man and computer, nor how to maintain the effectiveness of the human operator by supporting his skills and motivation. There will always be a substantial human involvement with automated systems, because criteria other than efficiency are involved”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We know language models have been touted as tools that enable computers to replace humans intellectual labor. And here we have a 40 years old paper saying actually that has never worked. I don’t believe language models or any other form of artificial “intelligence” is here to stay, but if that’s the case I hope it stays as a form of human-computer collaboration. As my skills and motivation lie in writing code, I’ll keep stubbornly rejection any trend that clashes with them. And as I keep feeling pressured to use these things, I’ll try to come with more silly ways which I feel that at least they don’t erase my motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So will I eagerly apply what I just described? I surely will when copy and pasting my code on a chatbot window is cheaper in motivation terms than filling in the gaps myself. The way to smooth the process is to run a local model, or pay for a service. For now I don’t want to do any, so who knows. At least I feel a little less dumber now.`&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/15/p1920-on-using-language-models-for-programming/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/15/p1920-on-using-language-models-for-programming/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ME:: sparklines everythwere :-) Just kidding, only where they make sense ; Andros Fenollosa:: tanrax/quick-weather.el: Sparkline weather forecasts in Emacs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://rolandtanglao.com/2020/07/29/p1-blogthis-checkvist-list-links-to-blog/&quot;&gt;Discovered&lt;/a&gt;: Dec 16, 2025 03:12 (UTC) &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tanrax/quick-weather.el&quot;&gt;ME:: sparklines everythwere :-) Just kidding, only where they make sense ; Andros Fenollosa:: tanrax/quick-weather.el: Sparkline weather forecasts in Emacs&lt;/a&gt; &amp;lt;– &lt;strong&gt;QUOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Quick weather forecasts with sparklines for Emacs, using data from Open-Meteo.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/15/p1912-quick-sparklines-emacs-for-weather/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://rolandtanglao.com/2025/12/15/p1912-quick-sparklines-emacs-for-weather/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
